两天前
污染
Contamination.
*我要回圣何塞寻求内心的宁静*
*I'm going back to find some peace of mind in San Jose*
*名望和财富是磁石*
*Fame and fortune is a magnet*
*将你吸引到他乡*
*It can pull you far away from home*
*只要心怀梦想  就不会孤单*
*With a dream in your heart, you're never alone*
*梦想化作烟尘飘散*
*Dreams turn into dust and blow away*
*你却无朋作伴*
*And there you are without a friend*
*你准备行装  驱车离开*
*You'll pack your car and drive away*
*我在圣何塞有很多朋友*
*I've got lots of friends in San Jose*
*你知道去圣何塞的路吗*
*Do you know the way to San Jose*
*洛杉矶就是条高速公路*
*Oh, LA is a great big freeway*
*放下一百块美金买辆车*
*Put a hundred down and buy a car*
*一周后  也许两周  你会成为明星*
*In a week, maybe two, they’ll make you a star*
你要喝点水吗
Would you like some water?
*日复一日  时间飞逝*
*Weeks turn into years. How quck they pass*
不  我...
No. I...
*没有成为明星的人*
*And all the stars that never were*
你要喝点水吗
Would you like some water?
*如今在泊车加油*
*Are parking cars and pumping gas*
*我在圣何塞有很多朋友*
*I've got lots of friends in San Jose*
那是什么情况
What is that?
有进展了
Progress.
《双螺旋》第一季第一集
亚特兰大  疾病预防控制中心
介绍会五分钟后开始
Presentation starts in five minutes.
-我找不到那玩意了  -桌子下面找过吗
- I can't find it. - Did you look under the desk?
怎么会在桌子下面
Why would it be under the desk?
我就是在那找到了你的西博格奖章[生化奖]
That's where I found your Seaborg medal.
找个有160年历史的泵柄能有多难
How hard can it be to find a 160-year-old pump handle?
-这要看情况  -看什么情况
- Depends. - On what?
看是谁来找了
On who's doing the finding.
你在哪...
Where did you--
就在你放它的地方
Where you left it.
-你真是救星  -大家都这么说
- You're a lifesaver. - So I've been told.
1854年
In 1854,
伦敦爆发了可怕的霍乱
London experienced a terrible cholera outbreak.
当地医生将传染病归咎于
Local doctors attributed the epidemic
瘴气  或者说是糟糕的空气
to miasma, or bad air.
他们的对策是焚香驱病
Then they responded to it by burning incense
结果促进了当时香花的销量
and promoting the sale of fragrant flowers.
大家可以试想
Not, as you might imagine,
这对在疾病中死去的六百多人可没什么帮助
terribly helpful to the 600 or so who died of the disease.
但一位医生和一位牧师
But a doctor and a clergyman
将病人的分布在地图上标了出来
mapped out the victims,
这就是史上首次进行的流行疾病学研究
and this was the very first epidemiological study.
他们发现
What they found...
在布罗德街附近病例密集
was a cluster of cases around Broad Street,
而那里有个城市水泵
where there was a city water pump.
他们违抗当局  做出了一件出乎意料的事
Defying the local authorities, they did the unthinkable.
他们将泵柄拆了下来
They took off the handle,
疫情因此受到了控制
and the outbreak came to an end.
但是当初的教训仍流传至今
But the lesson lives on,
不幸的是
and so, unfortunately,
霍乱也是如此
does cholera.
一名医生的失误  会赔上一位病人的生命
When a surgeon fumbles, a patient dies.
而我们若是失误
When we drop the ball,
千万人会因此丧命
thousands die.
作为疾控中心新上任的外勤人员
As new CDC field officers,
你们将被派往全世界
you are about to embark
各种偏远角落去执行任务
on a mission to the far corners of the earth.
你们将目睹
And you will witness
他人无法想象的惨状
horrors others cannot imagine.
让霍乱都逊色的惨状
Horrors that make cholera seem tame.
你们将做出他人难以想象的牺牲
You will make sacrifices that others find unthinkable.
你们的家人朋友
And your family and your friends...
也会随你们做出牺牲
will sacrifice right along with you.
你们会走上这条路
And you will do all of this...
是因为你们坚定这是自己的理想
because you cannot fathom living any other life.
这不是儿戏  风险
This is no game. The stakes...
是确实存在的
are very real.
那里面只是苏格兰威士忌
That's just scotch in there,
顺便说一句  还是纯麦芽的哦
by the way single malt.
是真的  扔回来吧
In fact, toss it back.
祝大家好运
Good luck to you all.
昨晚深夜
Late last night,
一个军事情报站收到北极生物公司旗下
a military listening post received a distress call
一家私人研究基地的求救呼叫
from a private research base owned by Arctic Biosystems.
大医药公司
Big pharma.
才听过不少他们的事迹
Just read about them.
求救内容提及一场可能的逆转录病毒爆发
The call denoted a possible retroviral outbreak.
目前已知两人死亡
Two people dead that we know of,
还有一人受到感染
and a third person already infected.
抱歉  你是谁来着
I'm sorry, who are you again?
塞尔西奥・拜耶塞罗少校
Major Sergio Balleseros,
就职于陆军工兵部队下属的军方传染病研究所
USAMRIID by way of the Army Corps of Engineers.
我受命护送你和你的快速反应团队
I've been instructed to escort you and your rapid response team,
包括沃克博士前往基地
including Dr. Walker, up to the base
去确认是否真的有逆转录病毒的爆发
to determine whether it is in fact a retrovirus.
鉴于是军队接到的求救呼叫
Now, given that the army fielded the distress call,
我们将与疾病防治中心有同样的管辖权
we're gonna share jurisdiction with the CDC.
看上去那里根本没什么管辖权可言
It looks like there's no jurisdiction at all.
如果基地在八十三度的纬度上
If the base is above the 83rd parallel,
那就是国际区域  我们在那没有主权
it's international territory. We have no authority there.
北极生物公司准许了我们前去  暂时性的
Arctic Biosystems is granting us access,for now.
他们真是慷慨
How kind of them.
这些都没关系  但为什么选我
This is all fine, but why me?
疾病防治中心还有六个高级科学家
There are six other senior scientists at the CDC
都能负责这件行动  包括沃克博士
who can run point on this, including Dr. Walker.
呼叫求救特别要求了沃克博士前往
The distress call specifically asked for Dr. Walker.
而她认为我们最好也叫上你
She thought it best that we include you.
我... 我还是没明白
I'm... I'm still not following.
第三个感染的人是彼得
The third infected patient is Peter.
谁是彼得
Who's Peter?
我弟弟
My brother.
第一天
我们的首要目标
Our primary goal
就是确认病原体
is to identify this pathogen.
莎拉  你和我与彼得负责检查死者
Sarah. You'll be with me and Peter on the deceased
确定疾病的范围
to establish the extent of the illness.
茱莉亚负责找出疾病的主因
Julia will determine the cause of the illness.
朵琳  你负责检查彼得实验室的每一个角落
Doreen, I need you to swab every inch of Peter's lab,
检测每一只动物  查出病毒的来源
test every animal for the source of the illness.
那你呢  大兵哥  你到底是干什么的
How about you, GI Joe? What is it that you do exactly?
我是个系统工程师  我将分析基地的
I'm a systems engineer. I'll be analyzing the base
基础设施  空气  水
infrastructure, air, water,
废物处理  找到病毒可能传播的
waste treatment, looking for ways the virus might
管道或通风口
have spread through pipes or air vents.
所以你不过是个说得好听点的管道工
So, you're a glorified plumber.
你不也就是个名头响亮点的兽医吗
Only if you're a glorified veterinarian.
听着  我们完全不知道这是什么病毒
Look, we have no idea what this thing is,
所以我们要把它当作高传染性病毒对待
so we treat it like a hot agent.
生物四级安全协议  全套防护服
BSL-4 protocol, full suits,
接触每一个潜在感染源后都要进行消毒淋浴
and decontamination showers for every potential exposure.
那会消耗很多时间
That could eat up a lot of time.
小心驶得万年船
Well, better safe than sorry.
当初你不是还在
Says the man who spent the night
满是埃博拉病毒感染者的茅屋里过夜吗
in a thatched hut full of Ebola victims.
-那就是他前妻吗  -没错
- That's his ex-wife? - Yep.
-跟我想象中不一样  -她比你聪明
- Not what I expected. - She's smarter than you.
-我很怀疑  -在实验室里也比你强
- Doubtful. - Better in the lab too.
深表怀疑
Highly doubtful.
他从不提及她或者他弟弟
He never talks about her or his brother.
他不说的原因很可能是因为
That's probably because
他曾将他前妻和弟弟捉奸在床
he caught her and his brother in bed together.
不过别担心  他们都是专业人士
Don't worry, they're professionals.
他们不会让私人感情影响工作的
They'll make it work.
我为什么要担心
Why would I be worried?
因为我注意到你看他的眼神
Cause I see the way you look at him.
这真是史上最诡异的家庭重聚了
This is gonna be the most frakked-up family reunion ever.
猛禽47即将抵达北极生物公司  请回复
Raptor 47 to Artic Biosystems, come in.
我们看到你了  猛禽47  一清二楚
We read you, Raptor 47, loud and clear.
我们即将到达  可以降落了吗
We're making our final approach. We clear for landing?
丹尼尔・埃罗夫  安全负责人
Daniel Aerov, Head of Security.
抱歉我们没有铺红地毯迎接你们
Sorry we don't have the red carpet waiting,
这里很少会有访客到来
but we're not used to visitors.
我们对红地毯什么的也不感冒
We're not used to red carpets.
这位是x宏博士
This is Dr. Hiroshi Hatake,
这里的研究主管
Director of Research.
艾伦・ 法拉格特  疾病防治中心的
Alan Farragut, CDC
彼得的哥哥  一眼就能看出来
Peter's brother. Of course.
我们为彼得远道而来
We've come a long way for Peter.
什么时候能见到他
When can we see him?
他被转移到我们的隔离区域去了
He's been transferred to our isolation facility.
恐怕这不是好消息
I'm afraid the news isn't good.
他过去八小时都处在
He's been in and out of consciousness
时而昏迷时而清醒的状态
for the last eight hours.
你们这儿的其他人呢
And the rest of your people?
你们采取硬隔离还是软隔离
Are you implementing hard or soft quarantine?
都没有
Neither.
你们还没有关闭基地吗
You haven't locked down the base?
允许我解释一下
Allow me to explain.
你们已经有三名受害者感染了未知的病原体
You have three victims of an unknown pathogen.
仅此三人而已
And only three,
而且他们都在同一个实验室工作
who all worked in the same lab.
除此之外没有其他人感染
There have been no other infections.
鉴于感染没有
Since we are not seeing
在整个基地爆发  所以我们相当确定
a base-wide outbreak, we are fairly certain
感染不是通过空气传播的
it's not airborne.
"相当确定"  那还真是让人放心
Well, at least you're fairly certain.
我们的直升机怎么走了
Hey, that's our ride.
他们不能留在这里
They can't stay here.
这里气温可低至华氏零下70度
The temperature can drop to -70;
会把飞机燃料都冻成胶状
it turns jet fuel to jelly.
再说了  完全控制形势前我们不能贸然离开
Plus, we can't risk leaving before we have full containment;
-这是疾控中心规定  -这下我感觉好多了
- CDC protocol. - You just made me feel better,
-至少知道他们没走  -不用担心
- knowing they're out there. - Not to worry.
艾森豪威尔营地离这只有两百多英里
Camp Eisenhower is only 200 miles away.
他们飞回来很快的
They can be back here in no time.
大家伸出左手  我们得把射频识别标识
Please stick out your left hand. RFID marker
注射到皮层之下  这里的人都有
injected under the skin. We all have them.
你们的权限能在基地内每一处随意进出
Yours will give you unrestricted access to the base.
授予主电梯安全访问权
Main elevator security access granted.
B层
Level B.
我的老天
Sweet Mother Mary Matthew.
这里一共有多少人
How many people work here?
我们有来自35个不同国家的106位科学家
A hundred six scientists from 35 countries;
还有15名后勤人员
15 support staff.
潜在患者不少啊
That's a lot of potential patients.
我们先关注眼前的吧
Let's focus on what we know.
我要看看感染者的人事档案
I'll need to see the personnel records of the infected,
他们的工作经历和病史  还有
their professional and medical histories. I'll need to see
他们的住处以及任何其它他们常去的地方
their living quarters and any other areas they frequented.
我还要看看他们试验用的动物和研究资料
And I want access to their lab animals and research materials.
此外  找到所有与他们
And I'll need to start tracking down
有接触的人  过去...48小时内的吧
anyone they've been in contact with for the past... 48 hours.
知道了
Understood.
E层
Level E.
现在我得先去看看我弟弟
Now I want to see my brother.
F层
Level F.
我已经很久没与彼得联系过了
I haven't talked to Peter in a long time.
有多久
How long?
自从那晚之后吗
That night?
那晚我回家收拾了点东西就马上飞到拉巴斯了
I went home and packed a bag; caught the next flight to La Paz.
你做事总是那么冲动
Ah, you always did have issues with impulse control.
我很担心
I'm worried.
别担心
That's all right.
现在我们来了  我们一定尽力救治他的
We're here, we'll do what we can for him.
我担心的不是他
He's not the one I'm worried about.
危险
心电图
他的生命体征很糟糕
His vitals are all over the place.
他  可能活不过今晚了
He... probably won't make it through the night.
彼得
Peter.
我要问你几个问题
I'm going to ask you some questions.
如果你说不了话
If you can't speak,
就点头或者摇头回答
try to nod yes or no.
-你们这里有T1光纤网络吗  -没有
- Do you have a T1 link here? - No.
那就惨了  要把这些数据
That's too bad. It's gonna take forever
上传回亚特兰大那得要多久啊
to upload this data back to Atlanta.
我们没有T1是因为那个过时了
We don't have a T1 because it's obsolete.
我们用的是同步光纤网络  速度每秒10G
It's a synchronous optical network - 10 gigs a second.
这里的网速要求极高
It has to be fast,
因为我们每天只有一个小时有卫星信号
'cause we only get the satellite an hour each day.
对一个保安队长而言  你知道的医学
You seem to know a lot about medicine and technology
和科技知识真不少啊
for a head of security.
这都是x博士教我的
Dr. Hatake taught me everything I know.
你们在哪认识的
Where did you two meet?
巴罗的一家孤儿院里
An orphanage. In Barrow.
他收养了我
He adopted me.
从我记事起我就一直追随着他
I've been with him as long as I can remember.
彼得  是我  艾伦
Peter, it's me, Alan.
法拉格特博士  你知道这是什么地方吗
Dr. Farragut, do you know where you are?
你知道
Do you know
你发生了什么事吗
what happened to you?
知道
Yes.
白色房间
The white room.
彼得  彼得  看着我的眼睛
Peter. Peter. Look into my eyes.
看着我的眼睛  能做到吗
Look into my eyes. Can you do that?
看着我的...  这就对了
Look into my... That's it.
彼得  是我
Peter, it's me.
我是艾伦
It's Alan.
艾伦  看他的血
Alan, the blood.
是黑色的
It's black.
安保小队立刻来隔离室
I need a security team to quarantine now!
你撒谎
You lie!
你们都撒谎
You all lie!
所有人都撒谎
Everyone lies!
所有人
Everyone!
所有人都撒谎
Everyone lies!
彼得被分配到这间实验室工作多久了
How long had Peter been assigned to this lab?
六个月了
The last six months.
他研究的是...
Working on...?
恐怕我没有权利告诉你
I'm afraid that's over my pay grade.
你得去问x博士
You'd have to ask Dr. Hatake.
你们寻求我们的帮助  却又不愿说出
You expect us to help you, but you won't tell us
你们到底在研究什么
what you're working on?
我们每周都会检查那个
We check that weekly.
干得不错
Good for you.
瞧瞧  你还真是个大块头姑娘
Tsk, tsk, tsk, tsk, tsk. Aren't you a big girl.
还是小伙子
Or boy.
它们没有性器官
They have no sex organs.
我们研究出一种
We've designed a way to inhibit
抑制生殖器官发育信号传输的方式
the signaling pathway responsible for genitalia.
这样它们就不会胡乱繁殖
Makes control easier.
我倒不介意在前夫身上试试这项技术
Got an ex-husband I wouldn't mind trying that on.
-你们的猴子在哪  -我们没有猴子
- Where are the monkeys? - We don't have any monkeys.
开玩笑吗
You're kidding, right?
这种规模的研究会不拿猴子做试验吗
With the kind of work you're doing here?
我说没有就是没有
No monkeys means no monkeys.
这是与彼得同时发现的另外两名感染者
These are the other two victims that were found with Peter.
你准备好了吗
You ready?
是的
Yeah.
打开袋子
Open the bag.
这是怎么回事
What the hell?
这种情况不会再发生了
That won't happen again;
-我向你保证  -我能理解  莎拉
- You have my word. - No, Sarah, it's OK.
我见过不少高传染性病毒
I've been around some nasty hot agents,
但还从没见过这样的
but I've never seen anything like that.
没人见过这样的东西
No one has seen anything like this.
你还认为这是逆转录病毒吗
You still thinking retrovirus?
看上去更像是出血热病毒
Looks more like some kind of hemorrhagic fever.
出血症状符合埃博拉和马尔堡病毒  但是
Blood loss is consistent with Ebola or Marburg, but...
这种程度的人体组织溶解
this kind of tissue degradation...
这东西不仅能杀人  还能将人彻底湮灭
This thing doesn't kill; it annihilates.
那为什么彼得还活着
So how was Peter still alive?
一步一步来  朵琳在哪里
First things first: where's Doreen?
跟拜耶塞罗少校在检查彼得的实验室
With Major Balleseros, swabbing down Peter's lab.
好  尽快开始分析  莎拉
Good. Get started on the assays, Sarah.
我必须找出是什么病毒才能对付它
I need to see this thing to beat it.
-我这就去  -茱尔斯  去跟x博士谈谈
- Yeah, I'm on it. - Jules, talk to Hatake.
找出这些感染者当时在研究什么
Find out what our victims were working on.
我们得弄明白这是由什么导致的
We need to find the causation of this.
你该去陪着彼得
You should be in there with Peter.
不管他还剩下多少时间
Whatever time he's got left...
不  他不会想让我坐在那看着他死去的
No, he wouldn't want me sitting around watching him die.
你准备怎么做
What are you gonna do?
果然如我所料
Yep, just as I thought.
你在干什么
Hey, what are you doing?
这些在PRC测试后仍存活的老鼠正说明了
These live rats in the PRC test confirm conclusively
x宏是对的  这病毒不会由空气传播
that Hatake's right - it isn't airborne.
那真是太好了
That's good news.
是啊  只是我仍然找不出病原
Yep, except I'm no closer to the source,
而且对它的传播途径也没有任何头绪
and I still have no idea on the mode of transmission.
-我讨厌老鼠  -我却相反
- I hate rats. - I don't.
我父亲是个军士长
My dad was a Master Sergeant;
经常带着我们四处搬迁
moved us around a lot.
老鼠比较容易携带
Rats are easy to travel.
你在军队里经常干这个吗
You do this a lot in the service?
将下水管道和马桶大卸八块来寻找病毒
Take apart drains and toilets looking for viruses?
我第一次征战是去伊拉克
I spent my first tour in Iraq,
-搜索大规模杀伤武器  -见了不少大场面吧
- searching for WMDs. - See any action?
-我几乎不出基地  -听起来可真危险
- Rarely left the base. - Sounds dangerous.
我想你身上一定有不少被纸割伤的英勇战迹
Bet you got some pretty nasty paper cuts.
过去几年我一直在南美洲
The last few years I spent
和那些毒贩子们打交道
harassing the cartels in South America.
他们一定都被你吓坏了吧
Must have been shaking in their boots.
你真正开过枪吗
Ever actually fire a gun?
出了训练营之后就没有了
Not since boot camp.
让我看看那个
Hey, let me see that.
这是什么
What is it?
猕猴的毛发
M. Mulatta.
如果我没有猜错的话
Unless I miss my guess,
这是从恒河猴的身上来的
this is from a rhesus macaque.
这么说他们确实有猴子  那又如何
So, they have monkeys. What's the big deal?
他们隐瞒了这个事实
That they lied about it.
猴子是动物性传染的主要媒介之一
Monkeys are one of the main agents of zoonotic transfer -
它们能在动物和人类之间传播病毒
that's passing a virus from animal to human or vice versa.
这么说  他们有什么是不想让我们知道的
So, what didn't they want us to find out?
x博士
Dr. Hatake?
真让人难以置信
Unbelievable.
北极有一种隽永不变的特质
The Arctic has a timeless quality.
你说是吗
Don't you agree?
这里的交通可不太方便
Makes it a little tough on the commute, though.
没有外界的干扰
We get more accomplished
我们会取得更多成就
without the distraction of the outside world.
比如说政府监管部门的介入吗
Like interference from regulatory agencies?
我需要了解彼得过去几天的所有经历
I need to know everything about Peter's last few days,
他在忙什么  和谁一起忙
what he was working on, who he was working with--
我就觉得你会问这个
I thought you might.
-这都是什么  -彼得的研究
- What's all this? - Peter's research.
还有二十多箱
There are 20 more boxes
在他的实验室里
in his lab.
我得花好几天才能整理清楚
That's gonna take me days to sort through.
你能不能简单跟我说下他在忙什么
Can you at least tell me what he was working on?
突变原  大部分都是
Mutagens, mostly.
是用于加速基因突变的吗
For speeding up mutations.
那些研究十分危险
Those are dangerous.
绝对不是些你愿意让自己小孩轻易接触的东西
You wouldn't want to let your children play with them.
你有孩子吗
Do you have children?
不  还没有
No, I don't.
你能想到他的研究与这高传染性病毒之间
Can you think of any correlation between his research
-有任何联系吗  -不清楚
- and the infectious agent? - No.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
彼得・法拉格特博士
第一轮班  请回应  第一轮班  请回应
Shift one, report. Shift one, report.
第一轮班  请回应
Shift one, report.
艾伦  组织样本已经...
Alan, tissues samples are--
我不是有意打扰的
Uh, I didn't mean to interrupt.
没关系
No, it's OK.
224号视频日志
Entry 224.
今早晒了一会儿日光浴
Got in some UV therapy this morning.
在跑步机上跑了三英里
Ran three miles on the treadmill.
现在想分清昼夜越来越难了
It's getting harder to tell day from night,
但我想也无所谓了
but I guess that doesn't matter.
我还在和T约会
I'm still seeing T.
她...很棒
She is... terrific.
但我不禁开始怀疑自己
But I'm starting to wonder
是否真的准备好开始一段认真的恋情
whether I'm truly meant for relationships.
倒不是说我不擅长谈恋爱
And it's not that I'm bad at them.
感觉更像是  恋爱于我无益
It's more like... well, they're bad for me.
总之  能来这里我很激动  我...
More than anything, I am excited about being up here. I...
我明白了一些事情
I understand certain things now.
...我很激动  我...
...up here. I...
我明白了一些事情
I understand certain things now.
-怎么了  -看他的手
- What is it? - Look at his hand.
小时候无数个夜晚  每当父亲带着一身
We used to do that, nights when our father
醉意或怒气回家时  我们就会做这个手势
came home drunk or angry, which was most nights.
这代表什么
What does it mean?
赶紧逃命吧
Run like hell.
你最好马上去一趟隔离室
You need to come to isolation now.
彼得出事了
It's Peter.
污染
Contamination.
你怎么会在隔离室里面留了把骨锯
How do you leave him in there with a bone saw?
-我正忙着在...  -忙着遵守
- I was a little busy trying-- - Too busy to follow
-四级安全协议吗  -你俩说的都不是重点
- BSL-4 safety protocol? - You're both missing the point here.
重点是他怎么逃出去的
How did he get out?
今天早上他还处在濒死状态
This morning he was terminally ill,
现在却有力气破牢而出
now he's ripping out of restraints?
我们封锁了整层楼
We sealed off the entire floor,
解除了彼得的识别芯片权限  他无路可逃
deactivating Peter's RFID chip. He's trapped.
但我们还得把他从里面逼出来
But we still need to get him out of there.
我们会在通风道里充满氟烷气[麻醉气体]
We're gonna flood the ducts with halothane gas.
-慢着  什么  -这样会使他昏迷四小时
- Wait, what? - It'll knock him out for four hours.
等气体散去后  再把他弄出来
Once the gas clears we'll retrieve his body.
等下  彼得是我们
Look, Peter is our best chance
弄清楚病毒感染模式的唯一机会
to understand how this pathogen works.
他体内可能产生了抗体
He may have antibodies
使他能够抵抗这种病毒感染
which have allowed him to fend off the infection.
他绝不能死
We need him alive!
我很抱歉  但我必须优先考虑
I'm sorry, but I have the lives
其他120条人命
of 120 others to consider.
在捉住他之前人人都有被感染的可能
No one is safe from the virus until we've contained him.
各安保小队  请确认楼层已封锁
Security teams, confirm level lockdown.
-各安保小队...  -等麻醉气一清除
- Security teams, confirm... - Once the gas clears,
我会带领安保人员把他带回隔离室
I'll take a security team and we'll bring him back to isolation.
你要上去的话  带上我
If you're going up there, I'm going too.
不行  这太危险了
I can't allow that. It's too dangerous.
只要彼得还有可能活着
If there's any chance Peter's alive,
我就要上去找他
I need to be up there.
如你所愿
As you wish.
我们已经查了一个多小时了
Listen, we've been at this for over an hour,
可还没发现一只猴子
and still no monkeys.
既然x宏允许我们自由出入基地
If Hatake is granting us unrestricted access to the base,
何不直接当面质问他关于猴子的事呢
why don't we just confront him, tell him we found a monkey hair?
你太天真了  他怎么可能会告诉我们
Yeah, right. I doubt we'd get a straight answer.
更何况  这样更有乐趣
Besides, this is way more fun.
拒绝通过
Access denied.
转基因
拒绝通过  拒绝通过
Access denied. Access denied.
还自由出入呢  就这么点权限
So much for unrestricted access.
你有好主意吗
You got any bright ideas?
这有液氮
Liquid nitrogen.
低温能改变抗张强度
Freezing rearranges the tensile strength.
西北一区  安全
Northwest A, clear.
西北二区  安全
Section northwest B, clear.
西南二区  安全
Southwest B, we're clear.
法拉格特博士  请汇报  法拉格特博士
Dr. Farragut, we need you to check in. Dr. Farragut.
你确定我弟弟在这上面吗
Are you sure my brother's up here?
我们已经封锁了这个区域的通风管道
We sealed the vents in this sector,
那种浓度的氟烷气体应该已经把他弄晕了
and that concentration of gas should have knocked him out.
天呐
Jeez.
这里到底发生过什么
What the hell happened here?
这是什么味
What's that smell?
猴子的味道  比这更臭的只剩人类了
That is monkey. The only creatures that smell worse are humans.
这里之前至少有上百只猴子
There must have been a hundred of them.
它们都到哪儿去了
Where the hell did they all go?
不知道  但这个笼门被撬开了
I don't know, but someone busted off this cage door.
还是从里面撬开的
From the inside.
我这里发现了黑色液体
I've got something here. Uh... black mucus.
位于西南...
Uh, southwest... uh...
西南三区
Yeah, southwest C.
他一定来过这
He was definitely here.
那是什么
What was that?
彼得
Peter?
Peter!
它很机灵
He's smart.
是太机灵了
Way too smart.
你在这啊
There you are,
小家伙
handsome boy.
出来吧
Come on out.
彼得
Peter!
来吧
Come on.
-他在这  彼得在这  -请等待后援
- He's here! Peter's here! - Wait for backup!
你还好吗
Are you OK?
我有没有被划伤  皮肤上有伤口吗
Am I cut? Do you see any breaks on the skin?
-没有吧  -你要确定  人命关天
- I don't think so. - Be sure. It's important.
你没事
You're OK.
他在这  彼得在这
He's here. Peter's here.
不是他  这人...
It's not him. It's...
不是彼得
it's not Peter.
我的天
Oh, my god.
他是我的一名安保队员
He's on one of my security teams.
约瑟夫・肯尼泽  31岁
Joseph Kneizeh, 31 years old,
阿拉斯加的塔基纳人
Talkeetna, Alaska.
-被袭击后遭截肢  -没道理啊
- He was attacked and dismembered. - This doesn't make sense.
我们要问的应该是为什么
The question we should be asking is why?
彼得为什么袭击他  为什么砍了他的手
Why did Peter attack this man? Why cut off his hand?
为什么病原体反而让他变强
And why is the pathogen making him stronger?
我要封锁基地的这个区域
I want to seal off this part of the base.
非必要人员都转移到指定安全室内
All nonessential personnel, keep them in dedicated safe rooms.
任何人不得单独行动
Nobody travels unless they travel with a partner,
直到我们抓回彼得
at least until we can recapture Peter.
请注意
Attention,
行动代码830  G层  肿瘤科
code 830, level G, Oncology.
第一组培养菌里面有发现吗
Anything from the first set of cultures?
细胞破坏情况严重  大部分完全变形
Cells are heavily damaged, most totally deformed.
就像经历过末日之战一般
It's like... armageddon down there.
没发现病毒吗
But no sign of a virus?
我把现今所有的病毒结构都筛选了一遍
I screened for all current viral structures --
长丝体  多边体  圆柱体  球体
filaments, polygons, cylinders, spheres...
连二十面体都没放过
even icosahedrons.
如果不是现代病毒呢
What if it's not current?
几位麻省理工的科学家
A couple of MIT scientists discovered evidence
在格陵兰冰芯内发现了古代病毒的存在证据
of ancient viruses in the Greenland ice cores.
那些古老的病毒结构能追溯到十四万年前
They found these obsolete structures dating back 140,000 years.
我得赞扬下艾伦  他确实慧眼识才
I gotta hand it to Alan, he's got an eye for the smart ones.
我们不是你想的那样
It's not like that.
不是哪样
Not like what?
艾伦确实是位良师  但我们之间没有任何事发生
Alan is a great mentor, but there's nothing going on.
我以前也说过一样的话
I would have said the exact same thing.
不过那都是八年前的事了
Only that was eight years ago.
看看这个
Look at that.
什么  什么东西
What? What is it?
在这
Right there.
只有十五微毫
That's only 15nm.
没有这么小的病毒
There's no virus that small.
现今的病毒没有
No current virus.
-你来完成这个  -你要去哪
- I need you to finish this. - Where are you going?
去找艾伦  他必须马上看看这个
To find Alan. He needs to see this now.
我们也不知从何下手  直到茱莉亚...
We weren't even sure what we eare looking for until Julia...
沃克博士开始检查它是否存在古神经细胞结构
Dr. Walker started checking for paleoneurological structures.
看起来像是某种形式的球状衣壳
It's some form of spherical capsid,
但和任何已知的种类都不一样
but unlike anything we've ever seen before.
这不是自然产生的  至少不是本世纪的产物
It's not naturally occurring - at least not in this century.
这是放大十万倍的图像
Here it is blown up to 100,000 xPM.
这是五十万倍
Here's 500,000.
在雪中漫步的感觉如何
How was your walk in the snow?
还不错  谢谢关心
Fine, thanks.
你一定不太习惯这里的低温吧
A bit colder here than you're used to.
无所谓  我能适应
Doesn't bother me. I'm adaptable.
你也知道那些不能适应环境的人下场如何
You know what they say about those who fail to adapt.
交货会按计划进行
The delivery will be on schedule.
计划在疾控中心介入之后就不同了
The schedule changed when the CDC showed up.
这与我无关
I had nothing to do with that.
不管怎样  我们双方的雇主都不会满意
Either way, the people you and I work for aren't happy,
现在我还得收拾你的烂摊子
and now I have to clean up your mess.
那是什么鬼东西
Oh, what the hell is that?
等等  还有这个
Wait, there's more.
我的老天
My God.
我们本以为它只是在自我复制  但并不止如此
We thought it was just replicating, but there's something else.
这种突变只发生在一小部分样品上
This mutation only occurs in a fraction of the samples.
尽管很少  但在统计学来说仍然相关
It's minimal but it's statistically relevant.
这或许能解释为什么只有彼得活下来了
Which could explain why Peter is still alive and the others died.
但这会对他产生什么影响
But what's it doing to him?
我只能说  这病毒正在改变他
For lack of a better term, it's... changing him.
变成什么
Into what?
*你知道去圣何塞的路吗*
*Do you know the way to San Jose?*
*我已离开太久*
*I've been away so long*
*或许我会迷失方向*
*I may go wrong and lose my way*
*你知道去圣何塞的路吗*
*Do you know the way to San Jose?*
*我要回圣何塞*
*I'm going back to find*
寻找内心的宁静*
*Some peace of mind in San Jose*
*洛杉矶就是条高速公路*
*LA is a great big freeway*
*放下一百块美金买辆车*
*Put a hundred down and buy a car*
*一周后  也许两周  你会成为明星*
*In a week, maybe two, they'll make you a star*
*日复一日  时间飞逝*
*Weeks turn into years, how quick they pass*
*没有成为明星的人*
*And all the stars that never were*
*如今在泊车加油*
*Are parking cars and pumping gas*
*在圣何塞你会很轻松*
*You can really breathe in San Jose*
*那里有很多空间*
*They've got a lot of space*
*将会有我的容身之所*
*There'll be a place where I can stay*
*我在圣何塞出生长大*
*I was born and raised in San Jose*
*我要回圣何塞*
*I'm going back to find*
*寻找内心的宁静*
*Some peace of mind in San Jose*
*名望和财富是磁石*
*Fame and fortune is a magnet*
*将你吸引到他乡*
*It can pull you far away from home*
*只要心怀梦想  就不会孤单*
*With a dream in your heart, you're never alone*
《双螺旋》前情提要
Priviously on Helix...
昨晚深夜
Late last night,
一个军事情报站收到北极生物公司旗下
a military listening post received a distress call
一家私人研究基地的求救呼叫
from a private research base owned by Arctic Biosystems.
求救内容提及一场可能的逆转录病毒爆发
The call denoted a possible retroviral outbreak.
第三个感染的人是彼得
The third infected patient is Peter.
那就是他前妻吗
That's his ex-wife?
他从不提及她或者他弟弟
He never talks about her or his brother.
他不说的原因很可能是因为
That's probably because
他曾将他前妻和弟弟捉奸在床
he caught her and his brother in bed together.
我们相当确定感染并不通过空气传播
We are fairly certain it's not airborne.
彼得  你知道自己发生了什么事吗
Peter, Do you know what happened to you?
这东西不仅能杀人  还能将人彻底湮灭
This thing doesn't kill; it annihilates.
他是怎么逃出去的
How did he get out?
今早他还处在濒死状态
This morning he was terminally ill,
现在却有力气破牢而出
now he's ripping out of restraints?
我们双方的雇主都不会满意的
The people you and I work for aren't happy,
现在我还得收拾你的烂摊子
and now I have to clean up your mess.
第二天
-我们被他感染了吗  -我们会死吗
- Did he infect us? - Are we going to die?
我不清楚发生了什么
I'm not sure what happened.
突然间  彼得...法拉格特博士跳到了我身上
Suddenly, Peter...Dr. Farragut...was on top of me.
他将我压倒在地
He held me down,
把嘴压到我的嘴上  就像野兽一般
put his mouth over mine, like some kind of animal.
我从未受过如此的侵犯
I've never felt so violated.
-我快窒息了  -我不能呼吸
- I was choking. - I couldn't bloody breathe.
就像他要闷死我一样
Like he was trying to smother me.
其他人怎样了
What about the others?
什么其他人
What others?
当时还有三个人在这里  袭击过后
There were three more in here with us. After the attack...
他们跑了
they ran.
去哪了
Where?
我不知道
I don't know.
告诉我他们的名字
I need their names.
请注意  行动代码425  R层
Attention, Code 425 Level-R.
有疑似感染者逃离了隔离区
We have a containment issue.
听说了  我已经向x博士申请安保小队
I heard. I've asked Hatake for a security team.
我们会组织一次搜索
We're mounting a search.
这地方太大了
This place is huge.
如果我们连简单的隔离制度都保证不了
If we can't maintain a simple isolation protocol--
这种情况下可没有简单的事
There's nothing simple about this.
我们还是先关注眼前的问题吧
All right, let's concentrate on what we do know.
我们知道病毒不会通过空气传播
We know the virus is not airborne.
受害者们怎么说
What are the victims saying?
他们说彼得对他们进行了某种口对口的接触
They're saying that Peter engaged in some kind of oral contact.
就像接吻或者啃咬吗
What, like a kiss or a bite?
更像是一种攻击
More like an assault.
那这病毒的R0系数就变成6了
The R-naught of the virus is now six.
再乘以逃脱的人数
Multiply that times our escapees--
我们可能会有十八个新病例
That's 18 new cases we can look forward to.
我们还不确定彼得是否会再次袭击
We're not even sure Peter's done yet.
茱尔斯  我需要你立刻在老鼠身上进行模拟
Jules, I need you to get started on the rats right away.
我们得明确感染率
We need to find out the rate of infection.
莎拉  你能在朵琳回来前负责隔离室吗
Sarah, can you handle the isolation unit until Doreen checks in?
没问题
Yeah, absolutely.
如果谁有任何急性病毒综合征的迹象
If you see any signs of acute viral syndrome--
发热  流汗  皮疹  咽喉痛  恶心
Fever, sweats, rash, sore throat, nausea,
呕吐  肌痛  关节痛  淋巴结肿大
vomiting, myalgia, arthralgia, lymphadenopathy...
只要有任何这些症状
Any of that.
你马上穿上隔离服去找我
You get back into a Racal suit and you find me immediately.
法拉格特博士
Dr. Farragut.
三个失踪的博士
Our three missing doctors,
特蕾西  雷弗和德克勒克
Tracey, Raver, and Deklerk.
他们逃离日光浴室后便不知所踪
No one has seen them since they fled the sunroom.
这真是意料之中的事
Why does that not surprise me?
那你能告诉我
Can you tell me, then,
在过去八小时中有人试图离开基地吗
if anyone's tried to leave the base in the last eight hours?
没有
No.
那我们只能用最原始的方法了
Well, then we'll have to do this the old-fashioned way.
我和拜耶塞罗少校会挨层挨屋的去找
Major Balleseros and myself will go floor to floor, room by room.
如果他们像你弟弟一样拒绝合作呢
And if they refuse to cooperate? Like your brother?
别忘了我们还没找到他
Let's not forget he's still out there.
我只能尽量说服他们
I'll have to persuade them.
希望你可以  不过以防万一
I hope you can. But just in case,
安保人员会随身携带电棍和束带
our security teams will carry stun batons and restraints.
你要用武力来制服他们吗
You're going to try to win them over with force?
我只关心这个基地的安全
The safety of this base is my only concern.
好吧
All right,
我也不同意用武力解决问题
I don't agree with restraining people any more than you do,
但我们还是先找到他们
but let's just find them first,
看看能否说服他们以大局为重
see if we can convince them to do what's best for the whole base.
我可以帮你应付那些逃离的病人
You're gonna need my help with those escaped patients.
实验室里更需要你
Not as much as I need you in the lab.
感染率远不如隔离重要  你知道的
Rate of infection is secondary to containment. You know that.
过去两年我一直在追踪感染患者
I've been tracking infected patients for the past two years.
我知道怎么跟他们交流
I know how to talk to them.
-这和你的资历无关  -那和什么有关
- This is not about your qualifications. - Then what is it about?
-这里资源有限  -那都是胡扯
- Our lack of resources up here. - That's bullshit.
你有多久没踏出亚特兰大了
When was the last time you even left Atlanta?
该死的  茱尔斯  我们不能同时掌权
Damn it, Jules, we cannot both be in charge.
这一次你必须得听我指挥
You'll have to follow my lead on this.
《双螺旋》第一季第二集
隔离室
我们得在这儿呆多久
How long do we have to be in here?
最多几周
A couple of weeks at most.
几周  那我的研究怎么办
A couple of weeks? What about my research?
万一我没被感染呢  我跟他们共处一室
What if I'm not infected? I'm in the same room with them.
-呼吸同样的空气  -闭嘴  布赖斯
- We're breathing the same air-- - Shut up, Bryce.
大家都冷静一点  我知道你们压力很大
Everybody, please calm down. I know this is very stressful.
你能懂什么  你才多大
You don't know anything. How old are you?
我今年二十六岁
I'm twenty-six.
你看起来只有十五岁
You look like you're 15.
我在麻省理工大学
I have two Master's and
专攻病毒学和生物遗传学
a PhD from MIT specializing
获得两个硕士学位  一个博士学位
in virology and biogenetics.
是十几年来疾控中心雇用的最年轻的博士
I was the youngest doctor hired by the CDC in over a decade,
法拉格特博士让我负责隔离室
and Dr. Farragut put me in charge of isolation
是因为我能胜任
because I'm qualified.
我会尽量满足你们的需求
Now, I will do my best to address your needs,
但是我要声明一件事
but I want to make one thing perfectly clear
一切要按规矩走
we will have order here.
我们从特蕾西博士的房间开始
We'll start with Dr. Tracey's room.
我会先砸开门进去
I'll breach the door and enter first.
没听到我的指令不要进去
Don't follow until you hear the all-clear.
那是什么
What's that?
电击棍  专门对付北极熊用的
Stun baton. Use 'em on polar bears.
不致命  但冲击力极强
Non-lethal, but they pack a wallop.
这只有碰见熊时才会派上用场吧
Ought to come in handy if we run into any bears.
如果遇上彼得・法拉格特
If we run into Peter Farragut,
你会庆幸我们带了这家伙
you'll be glad we have these.
他把一个人的脑袋拧了下来
He tore off a man's head.
你觉得仅仅靠电击就能制服他吗
You think a shock is gonna stop him?
-莫非你有更好的主意  -是的
- You got a better idea? - Yeah, I do.
不用砸门  不用电棍  我们敲门
No breaching, no batons. We knock on the door.
如果特蕾西博士在屋内  我们好好谈谈
If Dr. Tracey's home, we have a conversation.
要是她没心情交谈呢
And if she's in no mood to converse?
我可不想自己的双手被人砍下来
I've grown kind of fond of my hands.
特蕾西博士
Dr. Tracey?
Dr. Tracey,
我是疾控中心的艾伦・法拉格特
it's Alan Farragut with the CDC.
这是日光浴室的东西  她来过这里
These are from the sunroom. She was here.
但是她不想呆着这儿
But she didn't want to be.
她曾试图逃出去
She was trying to get out.
那她到底去哪了
Then where the hell did she go?
你是谁
Who are you?
朵琳・博伊尔
D-Doreen Boyle.
我怎么知道这是不是真名
How do I know that's your real name?
我  我的驾照上就是这名字
I-It's on my driver's license.
上面还有我的真实体重  但我可不会告诉你
I got my real weight on there too, but I'm not telling you that.
谁派你来的
Who sent you here?
我为疾控中心工作
I work for the CDC.
我专门研究传染病
I study infectious diseases.
也许你能帮我
Maybe you can help me--
不准靠近我们  听到没
Don't you come near us! You hear me?
我们  你在和谁说话
Us? Who are you talking to?
你把我脑子都弄糊涂了
You're messing with my head.
我不会伤害你的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
-你需要医生  -我就是博士[医生]
- You need a doctor. - I am a doctor.
所以我正是来带你去隔离...
That's why I'm here-- to take you to isolation--
不不不  不去那儿
No, no, no! Not there.
他们会对我做可怕的事
They do terrible things to you.
不  我不能告诉你
No, I can't tell you.
他们会把我弄去白色房间的  像威特博士一样
They'll take me to the White Room, like Dr. Hvit.
我要离开这基地
I want off this base!
你给我弄架直升机来  你答应吗
You get me on the helicopter. You promise me?
没问题  让你坐副驾驶座都行
I'll even get you to sit shotgun.
-来吧  我和你一起去  -为什么
- Come on, I'll go with you-- - Why...
你为什么要骗我们
...why would you lie to us?
这里根本没有直升机
There is no helicopter here.
现在是没有  但我可以打电话安排
No, not now, but I can make a call.
你真是个卑鄙无耻的骗子
You are a dirty, filthy liar.
现在我们该怎么处置你呢
Now, what are we gonna do with you?
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事
Yeah.
我好像听到了什么声音
I thought I heard something.
我总忍不住去想彼得可能就在上面
I keep thinking about Peter up there.
那只是基地运作的动静而已
It's just the base settling.
你抵达之后有睡过觉吗
Have you slept since you arrived?
睡了一两个小时吧
Uh, an hour or two.
我没事  真的
I'm fine, really.
在北极  睡眠非常重要
Sleep in the Arctic is critical.
不然你会思维混乱的
The mind can play tricks.
我会考虑你的建议
I'll take that under advisement.
等等  刚刚是怎么回事
Wait. What just happened?
-你看到了吗  -是的
- Did you see that? - Yes.
那间实验室里发生了什么
What was going on in that lab?
我说过了
I told you.
彼得之前在研究突变原
Peter was researching mutagens.
我想咱们都心知肚明  那不是突变原
I think we both know that was no mutagen.
他到底在研究什么
What was he really working on?
你得让我们出去  这是绑架
You've got to let us out of here. This is kidnapping.
我要见律师
I demand to talk to a lawyer!
这是公共卫生危机
This is a public health crisis.
疾控中心有完全管辖权
The CDC has full jurisdiction.
那你们又做了什么呢
Oh! A hell of a lot of good that's done!
我们自己研究治疗方案都比你们强
We could do a better job of finding a cure ourselves.
消停一会儿吧  布赖斯
Give it a rest, Bryce.
你才要消停一会儿
You give it a rest!
你又不是和那边的
You're not the one who shared a bathroom
美国第一位健康带菌者
一生中至少将伤寒传染给50个人以上
"伤寒玛莉"共用卫生间的人
with Typhoid Mary over there.
我很抱歉  别乱动
I'm sorry. Try to keep still.
不然怎样
Or what?
我会病死吗
I'll get sick and die?
一定很严重  你又把防护服穿上了
Must be bad - you put the suit back on.
我们只是不确定究竟面对的是什么
We don't know exactly what we're dealing with.
说不定一切都会没事的
Everything could be fine.
因为不知情  所以一定不会是好事
Not knowing is why things can't be fine.
因为不知情  那两位也会与我敌对
Not knowing is why those two over there are gonna turn on me.
都是迟早的事
It's just a matter of time.
我不会让你有事的
I'm not gonna let anything happen to you.
我保证
I promise.
这可不是你能轻易做的保证
That's a promise you don't want to make.
你们这里有硫酸吗啡吗
Do you have morphine sulfate here?
他急需吗啡  我在哪能找到
He needs morphine now. Where do I get it?
G层  药品仓库
Level G, drug stockroom.
起来
Get up!
他是谁
Who is it?
从日光浴室逃走的人之一
One of the runners from the sunroom.
他藏在了楼梯井里
He was hiding in the stairwell.
他是气溶胶部门的德克勒克博士
That's Dr. DeKlerk from the aerosol division.
你们没必要对他这么粗鲁
You didn't have to be so rough with him.
谁叫你们不听从指示
Maybe if you people followed directions.
谁叫你们不告诉我们到底是怎么回事
Maybe if you told us what the hell was going on.
怎么了  他被感染了吗
What's wrong with him? Is he infected?
我们不知道  他叫什么
Uh, we don't know. What's his name?
-我说过了  德克勒克  -他的名字呢
- I told you. DeKlerk. - His first name!
-好像是亨里克吧  -亨里克  有我们在
- Uh, Henrik, I think. - Henrik, we're with you.
有我们在  我们会照顾你的  他还有呼吸
We're with you. We'll take care of you. He's still breathing.
把他送去医务室
Get him to sickbay.
没什么好看的  都回去吧
Show's over. Everyone go back to your rooms.
我们为什么还不能撤离
Not until you tell us why
你不告诉我们是不会回去的
we haven't been evacuated.
让他离我远点
Keep him away from me.
你还没回答我的问题
You didn't answer my question.
我们正在竭尽所能
We're doing the best we can.
放屁  你们可是疾控中心来的人
That's bullshit. You're from the CDC.
要把我们弄出去不是轻而易举的事吗
You could get us out of here if you really wanted to.
你说的对  没错
You know what? You're right. You're right.
我们是可以把你们全部撤离
We could evacuate you all,
把你们空运到最近的医院去
airlift you out to the nearest hospital,
但是你们知道接下来会发生什么吗
and you know what would happen then?
首先是那些照顾你们的医生和护士
It would start with the doctors and the nurses -
受到感染
the ones caring for you.
他们回到家中
They'd go home to their families,
吻着孩子道晚安  然后将病毒传染给他们
kiss their kids goodnight, and pass on the virus.
第二天在学校里
And the next day at school,
这些孩子又会传染别人
some of those kids would infect others,
两周之后  这病毒
and in two weeks' time, this virus
就会肆虐于人民大众
is in the general population;
四周之后
in four weeks,
地球上每座主要城市都会遭殃
every major city on this planet.
所以  不行
So, no,
我们不能将你们撤离
we're not evacuating you.
但我们也没有放弃你们
But we're not abandoning you.
我们会和你们在一起
We will stay with you
直到弄清楚发生了什么
as long as it takes to figure this out.
现在  请各位
Now, please,
回到自己的房间
just go back to your rooms.
说的好
Nice speech.
1995年刚果基奎特爆发了埃博拉病毒
自从95年基奎特后
I haven't heard that since...
我就没听过你这么说了
Kikwit, '95?
1996年南非约翰内斯堡也爆发了埃博拉病毒
那是96年在约堡  你怎么在这里
It was Joburg, '96. What are you doing here?
彼得的实验室里发生了一些怪事
There was something strange going on in Peter's lab.
我正在排查监控录像
I've been combing surveillance tape--
我让你去研究感染率
I asked you to work on rate of infection.
但这个看起来更重要
This seemed more important.
我已经说的很清楚了
I thought I made this clear--
到底怎么了  艾伦
What's going on, Alan?
虽说你一直很固执  但至少你以前还讲道理
You were always stubborn, but at least you made sense.
-我们已经谈过了  -是关于彼得的吗
- We talked about this-- - Is this about Peter?
-真荒唐  -你在惩罚我吗
- That's absurd. - Are you punishing me?
相信我  我惩罚自己够多的了
Because believe me, I've punished myself
连你那份也算上了
enough for both of us.
现在不是合适的时间和地点谈这个...
This is not the time, it's not the place--
我们从没有合适的时间地点来解决问题
It was never the time or the place!
这就是我们当初争执的起源
That was the problem to begin with.
茱尔斯
Jules.
你来这里是
You're here for...
-什么  -你来这里是有原因的
- What? - You're here for a reason!
是的  我是
Um... yeah, I'm, uh,
我是疾控中心的人
I'm with the CDC.
-我们是来帮助你的  -不  不是你
- We're here to help you. - No! Not you.
是沃克
Walker.
我找到了这个
Got something here.
过去三个月的注射记录
Injection logs for the last three months.
这是与监控录像匹配的当日记录
Here's the date that matches the surveillance tape.
2月19日  他给第14组
February 19th. Lot 14.
注射了0.2毫升的纳尔维克-A
He injected 0.2cc's of NARVIK-A.
给第15组注射了0.2毫升的纳尔维克-B
Lot 15, 0.2ccs of NARVIK-B.
那是什么
What is that?
我常鼓励手下挑战自我
I encourage my staff to push the envelope,
尝试新的未试验过的配方
to try new and untested formulas.
纳尔维克-A
彼得也被注射了这个吗
Was Peter experimenting with this?
据我所知没有
Not that I was aware of.
纳尔维克-B
还有谁和他一起在这个实验室工作
Who else worked in this lab with him?
你昨天已经见过了
You met both of them yesterday -
停尸袋里那两位
in body bags.
我们得重做这实验
We need to replicate the test -
彼得的实验  然后自己分析结果
Peter's research. We can examine the results ourselves.
给更多的老鼠注射
Inject more rats?
然后看结果怎样
And see what happens.
我早该知道的
I should've known.
他们绝不会用它来做好事
They were never gonna use it for something good.
到处移动基因位置
Move a few genes here and there,
再激活复制周期
activate the replication cycle.
大功告成  一个完美的武器诞生了
Bingo, you got yourself the perfect weapon.
这不是我的错  对吗
It wasn't my fault, right?
我怎么知道这事会向坏处发展呢
How was I supposed to know it was gonna go sideways?
你不可能创造出一种病毒
You can't make a virus
还妄想它会听你摆布
and expect it to follow instructions, right?
别装了  你谁也骗不了
Don't play dumb! You're not fooling anyone.
你很清楚你一直以来都干了些什么
You knew what you were doing this whole time.
我才不会为这事背黑锅  听见了吗
I am not taking the fall for this alone, you hear me?!
天啊  对不起
Oh, God! I'm sorry.
我是怎么了
What's wrong with me?
莎拉
Sarah!
你还好吧
Are you all right?
不好
Not really.
他...碰你了吗  有任何接触吗
Did he... touch you? Make any kind of contact?
他有任何分泌物溅到你身上吗
Did he get any secretions on you?
没有  我没事  他没攻击我
No, I'm... I'm ok. He didn't attack me.
这里有很多空药瓶和注射管
A lot of empty vials and syringes over here.
硫酸吗啡
Morphine sulfate.
他很痛苦
He's in pain.
-这是好现象  -什么
- This is good. - Excuse me?
如果他还有清醒的头脑来自治
If he has the presence of mind to self-medicate,
那也许我们还能在他感染更多人之前
then maybe we can talk him into coming back to isolation
劝说他回到隔离室
before he infects anyone else.
我不知道  他
I don't know. He...
他那个眼神
he had this look in his eyes...
不太  不太像是人类
It wasn't... it wasn't quite human.
他还做了什么
What else did he do?
你是说除了像蜘蛛侠一样爬上笼子吗
You mean aside from climbing this cage like Spiderman?
他说了些东西
He said something.
他说  "你来这里是有原因的"
He said, "You're here for a reason."
-不过不是说我  他是指沃克  -茱尔斯
- Only not me, he said Walker. - Jules?
看样子他给我们留下了一条线索
I think he left us a trail to follow.
我去召集一个安保队伍
I'll get a security team.
我和你一起去
I'm going with you.
这次不行  博士
Not this time, Doc.
事情已经失去控制
Things have been getting out of hand,
你知道我们可不能失去你
and you know we can't afford to lose you.
不过倒是可以这样
But I'll tell you what, though.
你来当我的助手如何
How about you be my wingman?
出自电影《虎胆龙威》
我总算知道冷冻快餐被加热是什么感觉了
Now I know what a TV dinner feels like.
我想你那时候还没记事吧
I didn't think you were old enough to remember that one.
《虎胆龙威》  当然记得  三年级时看的
Die Hard? Sure. Saw it on third grade.
在上边看到什么了吗
You see anything up there yet?
没有  我们怎么知道他还在不在这
Nada. How do we even know he's still up here?
我了解彼得  他还在上边
I know Peter, he's still up there.
你如何肯定
What makes you so sure.
小时候为了躲避喝醉了酒
He used to hide in the attic when we were kids,
或者一身怒气的父亲  他经常躲到阁楼上
when our dad was drinking or angry, which was a lot.
小声点  别把他吓跑了
Keep the chatter down. We don't want to scare him away.
说真的  我觉得被吓的可不是他
No offence, but I don't think he's the one who's scared.
你能往上看吗  我什么都看不到
Will you look up? I can't see anything.
我这也是
Join the club.
那是什么
What was that?
什么是什么
What was what?
把你的头抬高二十度左右
Tilt your head up about 20 degrees.
向左看
Now look left.
这里黑得很  看到了吗
It's dark up here. Get it?
检查正后方  确认他没跟在你后边
Check your six. Make sure he's not behind you.
拜耶塞罗
Balleseros.
-他还好吗  -我不确定
- Is he all right? - I'm not sure.
他受感染了吗
Is he infected?
他还有呼吸  身上也没有那些黑玩意
Well, he's still breathing, none of that black shit on him.
脉搏很稳定
His pulse is steady.
上面发生了什么
What happened up there?
我怎么知道  之前我还是一个人
Hell if I know. One minute I was alone,
转眼间就和你兄弟面对面了
the next minute, I'm getting a face full of your brother.
估计我用电棍把我俩都给电晕了
I guess I must have nailed us both with that bug zapper.
那电棍含有60万伏电压
That stun baton packs 600KV.
他应该已经毫无知觉了
It should have knocked him out cold.
看起来很多常理
Seems like a lot of things
已经不能应用到彼得身上了
that should be happening with Peter aren't.
基地一号
Base One.
好的  我们马上去
Ok, we're on our way.
楼上的升降机警报刚刚响了
Elevator alarm just went off upstairs.
有人想要离开基地
Someone's trying to leave the base.
纳尔维克-A组实验对象大量死亡
NARVIK-A subjects are decimated.
接近百分之百的死亡率
Close to a 100% mortality rate.
-纳尔维克-B呢  -百分之百出现病症
- And NARVIK-B? - Morbidity at 100%,
可死亡率为零
mortality at zero.
受了感染但是还活着
They're infected but still alive.
我已经很久没在实验室干过活了
It's been a long time since I did real lab work.
你一定已经忘了它能有多无聊吧
Guess you forget how tedious it can be.
不是  我很怀念
No, I miss it.
那些力求精准
The precision,
全心投入  与不畏牺牲的精神
commitment, sacrifice,
一切都是为了发现新事物的喜悦
all leading to the joy of discovery.
我母亲以前也经常对我这么说
My mother used to say something just like that.
她也是个科学家吗
She was also a scientist?
细胞生物学家
Cellular biologist, yeah.
她在我很小的时候就去世了
She died when I was very young.
我很遗憾
I am sorry.
你父亲呢
What about your father?
天呐
Oh, my god.
你能让他歇会吗
Can't you make him stop?
吗啡不管用  如果我给他更大剂量
Morphine isn't working. If I give him any more,
可能会致死
I might kill him.
是吗  那听起来也不错
Yeah, maybe that's not such a bad idea.
有点同情心好吗
Nice.
要是换你躺在那儿
I suppose you'd feel the same way
看你还能不能说出这种话
if it was you lying there?
我替海文感到难过  但这于事无补
Look, I feel sorry for Haven, but those are the breaks.
能别吵了吗  我们要有耐心
Everybody, please. We just need to be patient.
你说得倒轻巧
That's easy for you to say;
你穿着防护服呢
you're back inside that suit.
这只是我们研究出治疗方法
This is just a precaution
之前的一种防护措施
until we figure out a treatment.
你根本就没在想治疗方法
You're not figuring out a treatment.
说实话  我觉得你对这种病毒
In fact, I don't think you know a damn thing
压根屁都不懂
about this virus at all.
别吵了  我们都是博士  不是吗
Stop it! Stop. We're all doctors here, right?
与其争吵  不如我们群策群力
Instead of bickering, let's put our heads together.
没错  让她放我们出去
Yeah, let's get her to let us out of here.
你知道我不能这么做
You know I can't do that.
你可能会传染给别人或具有攻击性
There's a chance that you could infect others or become violent--
如果这里的人变得有攻击性呢
And what if someone gets violent inside this box,
那我们又该怎么办
What are we supposed to do then?
把门打开
Open the door.
至少让我们回自己的实验室
At least let us go back to our labs.
不行
No.
随你做什么  反正我是不会放你们走的
Do what you want, but I'm not letting you out of here.
那就叫愿意放走我们的人来
Then you're gonna call someone who will.
一号基地
Base One.
-好的  我们得回去  -为什么
- OK. We have to go back. - Why?
有几个被隔离的人要求被释放
A couple of detainees are demanding to be let loose.
他们挟持了乔丹博士
They're holding Dr. Jordan.
你去吧  我去检查外面
Go. I'll check outside,
确保周边安全
secure the perimeter.
各安保小队  请确认楼层已封锁
Security teams, confirm level lockdown.
立即释放乔丹博士
Release Dr. Jordan at once.
然后我们再谈
Then we can talk.
放我们出去  我们就放了她
Let us out and she comes with us.
我保证不伤害她
No harm done.
如果你让我们回实验室
If you let us back to our labs,
我们可以帮忙研究病毒
we can help with the virus.
布赖斯是血液学家  我是生化学家
Bryce is a hematologist; I'm a biochemist.
隔离是为了你们自身的安全
You are in isolation for your own safety.
更像是被关在笼子里的老鼠
More like rats in a box.
我们不会坐以待毙的
We're not gonna die in here.
我们正在研究抗病毒疗法
We are working on an antiviral therapy.
只要动物试验一开始
As soon as we run animal trials--
那可能会花上好几周
Animal trials could take weeks!
我们可等不了那么久  你应该明白
We're not going to be around that long, and you know it.
法拉格特博士
Dr. Farragut.
放了乔丹博士
I need you to let Dr. Jordan go.
想都别想  别过来
Uh-uh! Don't come any closer!
听着  我们正竭尽全力
Look, we're working as hard as we can
解决问题  不达目的不罢休
to figure this thing out, and we won't stop until we do.
我们才不会信你的鬼话
We both know that's a crock of shit.
先让他说完  布赖斯
Hear him out, Bryce.
听我说  我和你们一样在里面
Listen, I'm in here with you;
而不是在外面
not out there.
我们会解决的
We will work this out.
好吗  把注射器给我
All right? Just give me the syringe
放开乔丹博士
and let Dr. Jordan go.
我们凭什么相信你
Why should we trust you?
法拉格特博士
Dr. Farragut.
现在我们没区别了
Now we're in this together.
艾伦  刚才你所做的一切
Alan, what you did back there...
谢谢你
Thank you.
我只是在尽我的职责
I was just doing my job.
你不是也坚守岗位  没放他们出去吗
And so were you by not letting them leave.
-严师出高徒  -是吗  哪个老师
- I had a good teacher. - Yeah? Do I know him?
反正也没什么危险
There's no risk anyway,
它不通过空气传播
what with the lack of airborne transmission.
茱尔斯  什么事
Jules, what is it?
我要给你看点东西
I need to show you something.
纳尔维克-A的试验对象死状恐怖
The NARVIK-A subjects died horribly -
机能障碍  失血性休克
lesions, hemorrhagic shock,
内脏溶解
liquification of internal organs.
但纳尔维克-B的试验对象活了下来
But the NARVIK-B subjects didn't die.
它们高度亢奋  极具攻击性
They became highly aggressive, agitated.
听起来像是狂犬病毒属
Sounds like a lyssavirus.
会不会是狂犬病毒的变体
Maybe some form of rabies?
狂犬病毒不会强制传染
Rabies doesn't include a compulsion to spread the contagion.
我从没见过哪种病原体
I've never seen a pathogen with such
有这样高度突显的行为模式
focused behavioral patterns.
B实验对象的表现与带菌者一模一样
The B samples are acting just like vectors.
还是服用了兴奋剂的带菌者
Vectors on steroids.
我认为B病毒改写了感染者的大脑
I think the B virus rewires the brain
使他们变成了完美的传染机器
to create a perfect contagion machine.
就像彼得一样
Like Peter.
法拉格特博士  x博士想跟您谈谈
Dr. Farragut, Dr. Hatake would like a word with you.
我也正想和他谈谈
And I'd like a word with him.
回到隔离区  查看一下感染患者
Get down to isolation. Check on the infected patients.
如果你所发现属实
If what you've discovered is true,
我们要面对的就不只是病毒
we're not just dealing with a single virus anymore.
要出去遛弯吗
Going for a spin?
今晚可真是够冷的  希望你穿够了衣服
It's a brisk night. I hope you brought your woolies.
这事跟你没关系
This doesn't have anything to do with you.
尽管如此  我还是得请求你回到基地
Still, I'm gonna have to ask you to return back to the base.
要是你知道他们在这干些什么
If you had any idea what they were doing here,
你也会立马逃离这里的
you'd be getting the hell out yourself.
转基因实验  病毒库...
The transgenic experiments, the virus vaults...
不受限研究  这些听起来都不错
Unregulated research sounds great
可做起来完全不是这么一回事
until you're actually doing it.
他们在猴子身上做的实验简直丧心病狂
What they did to those monkeys was... was an abomination.
回基地吧  把这些一五一十跟我说说
Come back inside. I want to hear about this.
我不会回去的
I'm not going back.
回来再说吧  你在外面会冻僵的
Just come back inside. You're gonna freeze out here.
人们有权知道这里发生了什么
People have to know what's going on up here.
我们得告诉媒体  告诉所有人
We have to tell the newspapers. Hell, we have to tell everyone.
你没事吧
You OK?
我很好
Yeah, I'm fine.
你不需要马上投入工作的
You don't have to go back in there right now.
我一个人就行
I can handle it.
我没事  谢谢
I'm good, thanks.
来帮个忙吧  这位是特蕾西博士
A little help? Meet Dr. Tracey.
她已经到晚期了
She's in the advanced stages,
但我给了她一针镇定剂
but I got her tranked up on monkey juice.
费了好大的劲
Took me a long damn time
才把她弄上来
to haul her ass up here.
而且我还知道了这里一些见不得人的事情
And there's some other monkey business
我想法拉格特博士会感兴趣的
I think Dr. Farragut would like to hear about.
隔离区
你们不会打算把她也关这吧
You're not bringing her in here, are you?
她会被直接送进重症监护室
She's going straight into the ICU chamber.
你们不会有任何接触的
You won't have any contact.
现在才这么做晚了点吧
A little late for that, isn't it?
他在抽搐  我需要一套急救设备
He's seizing! I need a crash cart!
我这就去
Got it!
现在动手
Do it now.
快跑  咱们得赶紧离开这里
Come on, let's get out of here!
抱歉  亲爱的
Sorry, love.
在疾控中心来之前情况并没如此严重
This virus was less of a danger before the CDC arrived.
我的人才是受害者
My people were the ones attacked in there.
正是被你的人袭击的
Yours were doing the attacking.
我以为你能控制这里的状况
I thought you had that situation under control.
看来是我高估你了
I was mistaken.
我也以为你会对我毫无隐瞒
And I thought we had the full picture,
更别提说好的全面授权了
not to mention complete access.
或许你能向我解释为什么这里的病人
Maybe you can tell me how it is that patients here
总是会离奇不见
just go missing,
或者为什么我的队员
or how a member of my team
会被一只本不该存在的
is attacked by an infected monkey
受感染的猴子袭击
she was told didn't exist in the first place.
或者你是否愿意告诉我
Or maybe you'd like to tell me why
我弟弟为什么会在他自己的实验室
my brother was tinkering with maybe the worst contagion
研究一种前所未有的危险传染病毒
this world has seen in his own damn lab?
这事你该去问你弟弟
You should ask your brother.
我绝不会鼓励下属如此鲁莽
I would never encourage something so reckless.
当下要紧的是
First things first:
我们要如何隔离受感染的患者
how do we contain the infected patients?
除非你对我开诚布公  不然没有任何办法
We don't, not without complete transparency.
我要是拒绝呢
And if I refuse?
我们是来帮忙的  你想靠自己解决问题
We came here to help. You no longer want that help?
行  但是看起来除了我们你也别无所靠了
That's fine. But it seems to me we're the last chance you have.
所以  如果我们能互相帮助
So, maybe we give each other what we want
或者说各取所需
what we need...
或许我们还能活着离开这里
and just maybe we all get out of here alive.
-抱歉  -为什么  又不是你的错
- I'm sorry. - For what? It's not your fault.
我没保护好你
I should've been there.
别气馁  我们会找到他们的
Ah, don't beat yourself up. We'll get them back.
我不是因为彼得才拒绝你参加搜寻
I didn't keep you off the search because of Peter.
我是不想再...
I didn't want to...
我已经失去过你一次了
I lost you once.
我很感激你对我的照顾  真的
I appreciate that, I do.
但我不再是你的责任了
But I'm not your responsibility anymore.
你不能一直这样保护我
You can't keep trying to protect me.
我没法控制自己不这么做
I don't know that I can stop.
茱莉亚
Julia.
彼得
Peter.
不要
No. No!
求求你  彼得  不要
Please! Peter! Please!
《双螺旋》前情提要
Previously on Helix...
彼得为什么袭击他
Why did Peter attack this man?
为什么病原体会让他变强
And why is the pathogen - making him stronger?
通过验尸
Pending necropsy,
我们也许找到了病源
I believe we may have found the source of the contagion.
这种突变只发生在一小部分样品上
This mutation only occurs in a fraction of the samples.
尽管很少  但在统计学来说仍然相关
It's minimal, but it's statistically relevant.
-这会对他产生什么影响  -把门打开
- But what's it doing to him? - Open the door.
-不行  -快跑
- No. - Come on! Now!
人们有权知道这里发生了什么
People have to know what's going on up here!
彼得
Peter.
第三天
没事了
It's all right.
艾伦
Alan?
没事了  放轻松
It's all right. Relax.
怎么回事
What happened?
你告诉我啊  我发现你晕倒在这里
You tell me. I found you here passed out.
-你还记得什么  -我在...
- What do you remember? - Uh, I was, uh...
我在...
I... I was, uh...
洗澡  消毒程序
taking a shower-decontamination procedures
然后...
and... and...
我...
I, uh...
I...
-茱尔斯  -我一阵头晕  就不记...
- Jules. - I just felt lightheaded. I don't remem...
不记得接着发生什么事了
I don't remember what happened next.
也许是
I guess I, um...
我没意识到自己有多疲惫
I didn't realize how exhausted I am.
我们的确压力很大
Well, we've... all been pushing really hard.
你得去睡几小时
You need to get a few hours' sleep.
这时候我需要你全神贯注
I need you 100% for this one.
-好主意  -我送你回房
- OK, good idea. - I'll walk you back to your quarters.
彼得还逃窜在外  独自一人不安全
With Peter roaming around out there, it's not safe to go alone.
我出去等你
I'll give you a moment.
有人吗
Hello?
这里有人吗
Anybody in here?
救...  我
Help... me.
《双螺旋》
第一季第三集
如果发现皮损  流感样症状或排出黑色黏液
Please report to me immediately if you see any skin lesions,
请立刻向我报告
flu-like symptoms, or black mucus discharge.
我们不用注射抗病毒剂吗  比如
Should we not be taking antivirals? Like...
-奥司他韦  -那是H1N1流感用的
- Oseltamivir? - That's for H1N1 influenza.
我们已经排除这个作为感染原因的可能性了
We've ruled that out as a cause of infection.
-那到底是什么  -没事的
- What is it then? - It's all right.
吃错药比不吃药更糟糕
Taking the wrong meds can do more harm than no meds at all.
我们已经在加紧研究治疗方法了
We're working 'round the clock on a treatment,
一旦研发出来
and when we find it,
就会狠狠击退病毒
we'll attack the virus aggressively.
我明白他们很害怕
Now, they are scared; I get that.
但有时真想冲他们吼一嗓子
But sometimes I just want to yell at 'em, you know?
他们的敌人又不是我们
We're not the enemy here.
安保队还在不断搜寻
Security teams are doing constant sweeps.
还是不见三个出逃的人或彼得・法拉格特的踪影
Still no sign of our three escapees or Peter Farragut.
G层发生了另一起袭击事件
And another attack has been reported on Level G-
两人可能受到感染
two more possibly infected.
已经将他们转移到隔离室了
They're being moved to isolation.
楼层封锁已经32小时了
We've been in lockdown for 32 hours.
大伙都慌了
People are panicking.
如果不做出些改变  也许基地会失控
If something doesn't change, we risk losing control of the base.
茱莉亚・沃克在哪
Where is Julia Walker?
不清楚  你要跟她谈话吗
I... I'm not sure. Do you want to speak to her?
不用了
That won't be necessary.
法拉格特博士
Dr. Farragut.
-你干什么  -把我哥哥隔离起来
- What are you doing? - Getting my brother into containment.
为什么不通知我们
Why didn't you inform us?
我以为你派来跟着我的人会告诉你呢
Because I presumed the man you had following me would tip you off.
给他做肝功能化验  全血计数差异比较
I want a full workup lFT, CBC with differential,
凝血因子  病毒检查
coags, viral screen,
以及所有能做的抗原-抗体化验
and all available - antigen-antibody assays.
我的安保人员都招架不住他  你怎么做到的
My security teams couldn't wrangle him. How did you manage it?
是他主动来找的我
He turned himself in.
彼得情况怎么样
What is Peter's status?
暂时稳定了
Stable for now.
我问的是镇静情况
I meant the status of his sedation.
-我们可不想再出一次安全事故了  -不太可能
- We don't want - another security incident. - That's unlikely.
就跟砍下一个人的手  使用他的识别芯片
As unlikely as cutting off a man's hand
一样不可能吗
to access his RFID chip?
彼得投降了  没有反抗  没有挣扎
Peter gave himself up; no fight, no struggle.
如果他要逃跑  何必如此大费周章
Why would he do that - if he were planning to escape?
我们上次隔离他时也是这么想的
That's what we thought - the last time we put him in isolation.
看样子吗啡对他有用
He appears to be controllable on morphine.
我给他接上止痛泵了
I've hooked him up to a pain pump.
他不会威胁到任何人
He shouldn't - be a danger to anyone.
-我不愿意冒这个风险  -我也是
- I'm not willing - to take that chance. - Neither am I.
有更安全的地方隔离他吗
Is there somewhere more secure we can hold him?
这层楼是北极生物公司的第一期工程
This floor was phase one of Arctic Biosystems.
公司日益壮大  这栋建筑也逐日扩张
As the company grew, so did the facility.
R层包括早期实验室  宿舍
Level R contains our early labs and living quarters,
还有维持整个基地的设备
along with maintenance for the entire base.
二氧化碳净化器
The Co2 oxygen scrubbers,
保暖系统  装备储蓄库
the heating systems, equipment storage,
很多实验室已经转移到了上层
though most of the lab works has moved upstairs.
这里只进行一些敏感和危险的研究
Now we use this level for sensitive and hazardous research.
这里的实验室应该能满足你的安全需求
One of the empty labs should provide the security you're looking for.
这间屋子里的通风系统
The ventilation system in this room
是独立于整个设施的
is separate from the rest of the facility.
混凝土墙壁  三英尺宽
The walls are concrete, three feet thick,
而门则是双倍加厚的钢板
and the door is double-plated steel.
没什么能够来去自如
Nothing is getting in or out.
什么样的实验需要用到核反应堆
What kind of research were you conducting with nuclear reactors?
我在森迪亚实验室呆过一阵子
I spent time at Sandia Labs.
美国核武器实验室
墙上这些烧痕看起来很相似
The burn patterns on these walls are virtually identical.
受控聚变
Controlled fusion,
已经被遗弃的计划
a project we abandoned.
上一次辐射检查是什么时候
When was the last radiation screen down here?
我们每半年检查一次
We test every six months,
而这实验室至少已经空了五年
and the lab has been empty - for about five years.
也就是说很安全了
So it's safe?
相当的  足够给彼得用作隔离室的了
Perfectly. More than qualified to be an isolation unit for Peter.
以及其他所有人
For everyone else as well.
这层有很多空房间  地方很大
There are empty rooms on this level, plenty of space,
而这个加固实验室可以用来分隔带菌者
and this secure lab allows us - to separate vectors
-与那些被感染者  -带菌者
- from those who are just infected. - Vectors?
就是我们用来称呼彼得那种
It's what we're calling the infected who are...
使用武力来进行病毒传播的感染者
physically attacking others to spread the disease, like Peter.
我想这里可以实现全面隔离
I think we can achieve full containment down here.
你是什么意思
Well, what are you saying?
我的意思是把R层变成隔离楼层
I'm saying we turn Level R into an isolation floor.
打起精神  茱尔斯
Get it together, Jules.
你  没有  生病
You don't... get... sick.
十八位病患已进行隔离  包括彼得
All right, we have 18 sick in isolation, including Peter.
还有三名逃跑两名潜在患者  一共23名
With three on the loose and two presumed infected, that's 23.
只是目前已知的
That we know of.
我想把他们都转移到R层
I want to move them all down to Level R.
我需要医疗设备
I'll need medical equipment.
将一间实验室改成分诊部
Turn one of the labs into a triage unit.
我需要足够四十人用的食物水和寝具
I'll need food, water, bedding, for 40 patients.
感染规模肯定会在完全隔离前扩大
This thing will get bigger before we achieve full containment.
我想这些我们能安排
I think we can accommodate that.
救我  救我
Help me. Help me.
-站那别动  -抱歉我跑了  他们逼我的
- Stay where you are. - I'm sorry I ran. They made me do it.
-我们能帮你  -他们逼我的
- We can help. - They made me!
-不要再走了  -相信我  他们逼我
- You need to stop. - Believe me. They made me...
拿个担架过来  然后去找查普林医生
Bring a gurney and find Dr. Chaplin.
不  没时间了  她陷入休克了
No! There's no time. She's going into shock.
给我找把手术刀和用来包扎伤口的东西
Find me a scalpel and something to pack into the wound.
保持清醒  你会没事的  快点
Stay with me now. You'll be ok. Hurry up!
好  我摸到子弹了
All right, I feel the bullet.
按住这条血管  按住这条血管
Here, pinch off this vein. Pinch off this vein!
好的  用点力  就是这  我拿到了
Yes. More pressure. Right there. I have it, I have it.
好的
Good.
你会没事的
You're gonna be fine now.
她情况足够稳定  可以进行转移了
She should be stable enough to move.
把她转移到聚变实验室去
We take her down to the fusion lab.
多亏了你的敏捷思维
Thanks to your quick thinking.
我的敏捷思维本该是不需要的
My quick thinking shouldn't have been necessary in the first place.
好了  来吧
All right. Come on. Come on!
她没有武器并且在向我们呼救
She was unarmed and asking for our help.
我只是想保护x博士
I was only trying to protect Dr. Hatake.
她不是在威胁他  她是被吓坏了
She wasn't threatening him. She was scared.
当时事态紧急
The situation was escalating.
事态一点都不紧急  直到你小题大做
It didn't escalate until you panicked
差点谋杀一位受感染的病人
and almost murdered an infected patient!
这基地的规则是我定的
I set the rules on this base.
这里没有国家  没有法律
There are no countries here, no laws.
苏勒玛尼博士生死由我负责  不是丹尼尔
Dr. Sulemani's life is my responsibility, not Daniel's.
作为这件案子中经验最丰富的学者
As senior scientist on this case,
每位病人的生命都是我的一份责任
every patient's life is my responsibility.
告诉你的那些安保队员这将是最后一次
You tell your security people that this is the last time
在我的病人身上使用致命武力
lethal force is to be used on one of my patients!
-我无法保证  -你管好他们
- I can't guarantee that. - You tell them!
不然我就带走我的小组
Or I'll pull my team,
然后等六个月之后回来做尸检
and we can do this again in six months' time as a postmortem!
你对我做了什么  彼得
What did you do to me, Peter?
你做了什么
What did you do?
痛
...Pain...
我们封锁楼梯间
We seal off the stairwells,
用电梯来当气阀
use the elevator for an airlock,
只要控制住楼层入口
and once we control access to the floor,
我们就有了一个隔离室
we should have a viable isolation unit.
健康的留在楼上  受感染的去楼下
So, healthy people come upstairs, sick people go down.
没准有用
It might work.
但如果有些人还未显现出症状
But if people aren't showing symptoms yet,
怎么能知道他们是否被感染
how do we know who's infected?
我们需要一个测试  还得是立马可行的测试
We'll need a test, something that we can administer quickly.
最快的是做快速反应测试
A rapid-response test would be the fastest.
但首先我们得找出病毒纯样
But first we need to synthesize a pure sample of the virus.
两种病毒都要
Both viruses.
彼得实验室里找到的实验病毒有什么发现
What about those vials you found in Peter's lab?
从现有的数据库来看
Neither NARVIK-A nor B
纳尔维克-A和B都不是病原体
show up as a pathogen in any existing database.
纳尔维克-B就是让实验鼠群
NARVIK-B is the strain that created the vectors
变成带菌者的那个菌株  是吗
in the rat population, right?
基于那个变体  设计出测试需要多久
How long to synthesize a test based on that variant?
做出可行的测试至少要八个小时
Eight hours at least for something functional.
好  给你四小时  和乔丹合作
Well, you have four. Work with Jordan.
那只受感染的猴子身上还有什么信息吗
Tell me more about this infected monkey.
我觉得猴子体内的病毒是关键
I think the virus inside the monkey is the key.
我正在对它的全部基因组进行排序
I'm sequencing the full genome now.
如果我们能证明传染病是从猴子传染到人的
If we can prove that the infection passed from monkey to human...
那我们对原始菌株的了解就更近了一步
it gets us one step closer to the original strain.
这样我们才有机会找到疫苗
And the best shot we have at a vaccine.
好  开始工作吧
All right, get started on it.
我和她一起去  现在我们要加倍小心
I'll go with her; can't be too careful right now.
谢了  但我能保护好自己
Thanks, but I can take care of myself.
朵琳  让他跟你一起
Doreen, take him with you.
大家听好
All right, everybody,
通信系统在6小时42分钟以后将会连通
the com link window goes live in six hours and 42 minutes.
如果我们到时能把相关数据传到亚特兰大
If we have this data to upload to Atlanta,
或许就能战胜这次危机
we might just get on top of this thing.
去干活吧
Let's get to work.
20包盐水  改成30包
And 20 bags - make that 30 bags - of saline drip.
基地的医生已经检查过苏勒玛尼博士了
Our base doctor's seen Dr. Sulemani.
她会撑过去的
She's gonna make it.
好  让他持续给她注射异丙酚[麻醉药物]
Well, have him keep her on a propofol infusion.
苏勒玛尼的事件我并没有小题大做
I didn't panic with Sulemani.
她感染了致命病毒  企图攻击x博士
She was infected with a lethal virus and coming at Dr. Hatake.
我权衡轻重之后才开了枪
I assessed the options and I pulled the trigger.
感染了就得挨枪子
We shoot everyone who's infected?
是这样吗
Is that it?
-来消除威胁  -是的  如果有这个必要
- Eliminate the threat? - If necessary.
那些潜在的感染者呢  也要杀了他们吗
And those who might be infected? Do we kill them too?
你没开枪的原因
The only reason you didn't fire that shot
是因为你手里没枪
is because the gun wasn't in your hands.
维修组  请速到B层生活区
Maintenace team to living quarters, level B.
又是假阳性结果
Another false positive.
我也是  我已经试验了所有非典型酶
Me too. I've gone through all of the atypical enzymes.
你从非典型着手的吗
You started with atypicals?
它们的催化率太低
Their catalyzation rate is too low.
我看过一项研究
I read a study that linked the
用非典型酶找出了某些病毒抗体
use of atypical enzymes to certain viral antibodies.
你得广泛试验  缩小范围
You have to start wide and narrow down.
所以我才让你用EC-1酶
That's why I assigned you EC-1 enzymes...
这种酶能用任何东西催化  这对我们毫无帮助
EC-1 catalyzes with everything, which tells us nothing,
而且我们没有时间把数千种酶一个个试验
and we don't have time to go through a thousand different enzymes.
如果我们要在三小时内做成试验的话
If we're gonna come up with a test in less than 3 hours,
我们得做出创新
we need to do some crea...
-莎拉  -干嘛
- Sarah. - What?
你的手怎么了
What's wrong with your hand?
你还好吧
Are you OK?
你感到什么症状了吗
Are you feeling any symptoms?
我整整三天没合眼
I've been up for three days straight.
大概只是太累了
I'm probably just exhausted.
彼得的血清用完了
We're out of Peter's blood serum.
-我去再抽点血样  -我去吧
- I should go get some more samples... - I'll do it.
如果发现病毒确实源于猴子
If you find the virus did come from the monkeys,
这有利于找出解药吗
will that help you figure out a cure?
找出病毒的“解药”只是一个相对的说法
"Curing" a virus is a relative term.
我们得想出治疗方案  让感染者情况好转
We need a treatment to help the infected folks get better,
研制出疫苗预防感染
and a vaccine to prevent anyone else from getting infected.
还有漫漫长路要走  猴子只是第一步
That sick monkey is just the first step down a long road...
见鬼  感染的猴子去哪儿了
Where the hell is my monkey?
这是什么味道
What's that smell?
福尔马林
Formaldehyde.
带走猴子的人将这里彻底清扫了个遍
Whoever did this wanted to kill any living organism left behind.
他们不想让我对猴子抽样分析
They didn't want me analyzing the samples from that monkey.
真的很臭
It reeks.
再臭也臭不过x宏那个浑蛋
Reeks all right. Reeks of Hatake.
你要干什么
What are you gonna do?
-去办公室质问他吗  -没错
- Walk into his office and demand answers? - Why not?
你明知他会怎么回答你
Because you know how that conversation's gonna go.
他会说这是生物安全规定
He's gonna say it was biosafety protocol,
或是日常维护程序
or scheduled maintenance.
我曾认识一个上校  他就像x博士一样固执己见
I knew this full-bird colonel, just like Hatake. Real stickler.
要解决事情  你得有点创意
You had to find creative ways to get things done.
你有什么好建议
What'd you have in mind?
如果我能找到另一只猴子做样本呢
What if I could get you another monkey sample?
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
三天前  我们都在适应各自的新生活  现在呢
Three days ago, we were moving on with our lives, and now this?
看着你  往事如潮水般涌来
Seeing you, it all comes flooding back -
我和艾伦之间的不愉快
how unhappy I was with Alan;
我甚至认不出
how I couldn't even recognize...
和他在一起的时候我是谁
who I was with him anymore.
但我不会承认
But instead of acknowledging it,
我什么都不会说  我只是
I didn't say anything; I just...
默默地承受着这所有的一切
swallowed it, all of it,
直到这一切把我淹没  令我窒息
until it filled me up, and I was drowning in it.
然后你又出现了
And then you.
我以为我能承受得住
I thought I could handle this.
从来没见过这样的东西
Never seen anything like this.
你看它们的脸
Look at their faces!
没错  太他妈恐怖了
I know. It's pretty damn scary.
不  不是恐怖  是恐惧
No, not scary; scared.
这些猴子们为了逃命不顾一切
These monkeys were running for their lives.
它们在逃离什么
Running from what?
说真的  你是怎么找到这个地方的
How'd you find this place, anyway?
我在这检查基地周围冰层的稳固性
I was just checking the stability of the icepack around the base.
放屁
Horseshit.
你他妈的到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
告诉你了  我是陆军工程师
I'm just an army engineer, like I said.
你要想和我一起干活  行
You want to work together? I got no problem with that.
但你必须要跟我说实话
But you have got to start telling me the truth.
-我说的是实话  -骗谁呢
- I am! - Ha.
陆军部队里有一些人
There are people in the army,
包括我在内
myself included, who are wondering
都怀疑疾病的爆发是否真是一场意外
if this outbreak was an accident.
你觉得这是x宏一手策划的吗
You think Hatake did this on purpose?
他为什么要那么做
Why would he do that?
不如你帮我一起找出真相
Why don't you come help me find out?
隔离措施建好之前让人24小时看守这里
I want 24-hour guards on this door until we get full containment.
基地一号  请讲
Base One, go ahead.
他们在这一层发现了一名逃跑感染者
They found one of the escapees on this level.
你为什么这么开心
What are you so happy about?
没什么  我刚研究出了测试方法
Nothing. I just cracked the test.
你弄明白了吗  是哪种酶催化
You figured it out? Which enzyme catalyzed?
哪种都不是
None of them.
你离开之后  我想起了另一项研究
After you left, I remembered another study.
那项研究运用了人体本身的机能
It utilizes the body's natural way
来检查入侵的病原体
of detecting foreign pathogens.
白细胞  明白了  快说重点
White blood cells. Yes. Get to the point.
那项研究用维多利亚多管发光水母的基因
So it modified the white blood cells with genes
来改变白细胞的结构
from a crystal jellyfish, Aequorea victoria,
从而形成一个快速反应测试
to create a rapid-response test.
水母基因会产生一种绿色荧光蛋白
The jellyfish genes produce a fluorescent green protein.
你重复试验了吗
You replicated this?
我从三个警卫人员身上取了对照样本  测试都没变色
I swabbed three security techs for control samples - all clear.
然后我在已知感染者身上重做了那个测试
Then I ran the test on known infectees
彼得  特蕾西博士和德克勒克博士
Peter, Dr. Tracey, and Dr. DeKlerk.
结果全部呈现绿色  证明受到了感染
All green - positive for infection.
再做一次给我看  以你自己为对照样本
Show me again. Use yourself as a control.
为什么要这样做
Why does that matter?
听着  如果你想看看这个测试的效果
Look, if you want to see it in action,
我可以直接在你身上试验
I can take a swab from you right now.
行  拿我来测
OK. Test me.
我不明白为什么要在这浪费时间
I don't know why we're wasting our time with this.
我们得尽快告诉艾伦
We need to tell Alan.
开门  杜尚  我知道你在里面
Come on, Duchamp! I know you're in there!
-别靠近我  -把它放下  把它放下
- Don't come any closer. - Put it down. Put it down.
让我们来帮助你
We're going to help you.
就像帮助苏勒玛尼博士那样帮我吗
Oh, just like you took care of Dr. Sulemani, huh?
发生在苏勒玛尼博士身上的
What happened to Dr. Sulema--
-你要把我们都杀了  -是个错误
- You want us all to die! - ...was a terrible mistake,
我们不想伤害到你
all right? We don't want to hurt you,
-但是你必须去隔离  -我坚决不去
- but you have to come to isolation. - I'm not going there!
我没有被感染
I'm not even infected!
至少在你把我和他们关在一起之前没有
Or at least I wasn't until you threw me in with the rest of them!
-让我帮助你吧  -给我解药
- Let me help you. - I want the cure!
-我们没有解药啊  -放屁
- We don't have a cure. - Bullshit!
索迪拉就在这里面
The SODRA's in there.
你不让我们拿到它  我不会让你这么做的
You're keeping it from us, and I'm not gonna let you!
把他和苏勒玛尼一起关到聚变实验室
Put him in the fusion lab with Sulemani.
我是疾控中心的艾伦・法拉格特
This is Alan Farragut of the CDC.
里面的人都还好吗
Everybody all right in there?
谢天谢地你来了  他们差点就闯进来了
Thank God you're here. They almost got in.
-你叫什么名字  -菲力浦・杜尚
- What's your name? - Philippe Duchamp.
为什么他说你有解药
What was he saying about you having a cure?
他在胡说  根本没有解药
This is ridiculous. There is no cure.
加入增长因子  细胞就能增长到足够的数量
Adding growth factor so the cells will build a critical mass
用来进行基因组测序
for the genome sequencing.
然后把它放到培养器中
And we stick it in the incubator
剩下的就是等待了
and wait.
就是继续做我这一小时在做的事就对了
So, do the same thing I've been doing for the last hour.
这正常吗
Is that supposed to happen?
这就是你说的培养病毒吗
So, when you said you're growning the virus?
不应该长成那样的
It wasn't supposed to grow like that.
你是指像活的一样吗
You mean like it was alive?
病毒不是活着的有机体
Viruses aren't living organisms.
它们不存在能量和碳代谢
They lack any form of energy or carbon metabolism.
那它为什么会突然急速增长
Why did it hulk out?
那就是我们要寻找的答案
That's what we're gonna find out.
也许艾伦会知道为什么它对增长因子
Maybe Alan'll know why it reacted so violently
-反应如此剧烈  -等等
- to the growth factor. - Wait.
-不要  -不要干什么
- Don't. - Don't what?
不要告诉任何人  如果x宏知道了
Don't tell anyone. If Hatake gets wind of this,
就会像清理猴子室那样把这里清的一干二净
it'll be the monkey room all over again.
我还是不信任你  不过你说得对
I still don't trust you, but when you're right, you're right.
布赖斯博士说杜尚在研发一种解药
Dr. Bryce said Duchamp was working on a... a cure,
-叫索迪拉  -抱歉 无可奉告
- Something called SODRA. - I can't discuss that.
这是机密研究
The research is proprietary.
不  别再藏着掖着了
No! No more secrets!
你答应我不再隐瞒任何事情的
You promised me transparency.
当接到卫星信号时
When the satellite comes online,
我会和我的董事会谈谈
I'll speak with my board of directors.
你必须把该让我知道的事都告诉我
You will tell me everything I need to know,
否则  当接收到卫星信号时
or when that satellite comes online,
我会告诉所有主流新闻机构
I'll tell every major news organization on earth
这个基地到底发生了什么
what's happening in this base.
你觉得美国军队可怕吗
You think you're afraid of the US military?
当你想在《纽约邮报》面前保守秘密时再说吧
Wait till you have to keep your secrets from the New York Post.
索迪拉是一种有惊人治愈率的
SODRA is an antiviral treatment
抗病毒治疗剂
with an astonishing cure rate -
治愈率几乎100%
nearly 100%.
你说的治疗
When you say cure,
是说它能将病毒完全铲除
you mean total viral elimination?
-而对宿主细胞没有任何伤害吗  -是的
- With no harm to host cells? - Yes.
你测试过多少种病毒了
How many viruses have you tested against?
范围有多广
How wide a range?
所有病毒种类
All of them.
甲流  肝炎  艾滋病吗
H1N1? Hepatitis? HIV?
该死的  天花也是一种病毒
Hell, smallpox is a virus.
全世界只有两个地方有天花样本
There are only two places on earth that have smallpox:
疾控中心和俄罗斯载体研究院
the CDC, and Vector Institute in Russia.
实际上  是三个地方有
Actually, there are three.
你为了研发一种万能解药
You have been growing lethal viruses
一直在培育致命病毒吗
for the purpose of developing a cure-all.
索迪拉的确有效
SODRA works.
在所有的动物试验中  病毒都被杀死了
In all animal test cases, the viruses were killed.
唯一的问题就是死亡率
The only problem is the mortality rate.
共有多少试验样本死亡
How many subjects were killed?
超过百分之七十五
Over 75%.
所以索迪拉不能投入使用
Which is why SODRA is not an option.
R层的隔离措施已经建造完毕
Level R has been sealed.
我们把他们带下去  逐个排查
We'll take everyone downstairs, go person to person.
感染者留在下面  其他人回来
Anyone who's infected stays below; everyone else comes back up.
已经准备好进行一百四十个测试的器材了
A hundred and forty tests ready to go.
你们俩干得不错
You two did good work.
被叫到名字的人
If I call your name,
受感染测试样本
生物危险品
请上前来  从乔丹博士那
please step over here, take a face shield
拿一个面罩  然后站到这边
from Dr. Jordan, and then come stand over here.
阿尔瓦雷斯博士
Doctors... Alvarez...
米哈洛维奇博士
Mihalovich...
哈桑博士
Hassan.
安保人员特里
Security Tech Terry.
李孙博士
Dr. Sun-Lee.
安保人员格鲁宁
Security Tech Gruning.
被我叫到的人
Those of you whose names I have called,
请跟我走
you'll follow me.
其他人跟乔丹博士和沃克博士留在这里
The rest of you will stay with Dr. Jordan and Dr. Walker.
等等  为什么他们能回到楼上
Wait! Why are they getting to go back upstairs?
因为测试结果显示他们没感染病毒
Because they tested negative for the virus.
大家请随意选择空余床位安顿下来
Please find any empty cot. Make yourselves at home.
沃克博士和乔丹博士
Dr. Walker and Dr. Jordan will be
会向你们收集医疗信息
coming around to collect your medical information.
大家去吧
Go ahead.
-这是最后一组  -有多少人
- That's the last group. - How many?
四十三个感染者
Forty-three infected.
这几乎是基地人数的三分之一了
That's almost a third of the base.
我想把布赖斯博士和苏勒玛尼博士也带下来
I want to bring Drs. Bryce and Sulemani down here.
难道不该把他们继续锁在聚变实验室吗
Shouldn't they stay locked up in the fusion lab?
他们已经试图逃脱一次了
They already tried to escape once.
这层很牢固  他们逃不掉的
This floor is secure. There's no way out.
失陪了
Excuse me.
把这层隔离起来是个好主意
Isolating this level was a good idea.
人们慢慢适应了这里
People are settling in.
是啊  但是他们都很恐慌
Yeah, but they're scared.
我觉得很多人都相信他们没病
I think a lot of them believed they weren't sick.
其实有些人是知道的  他们只是不愿相信
Part of them knew. They just didn't want to believe it.
我又检查了彼得的生命体征  他快不行了
I took Peter's vitals again. He's all over the place...
只要一有卫星信号
I'm sending his lab work to
我会马上把他的实验内容传给疾控中心
the CDC as soon as the satellite window opens.
让更多人一起参与
Get some more heads in the game
加速找到安全的疗法和疫苗
when finding a safe treatment and a vaccine.
对他来说  那可能已经晚了
That may be too late for him.
开门
Open the door.
把他们转移到隔离区
Let's get these people into the isolation beds.
样本整理好了吗
Almost done with the samples?
我正要拿到楼上去
I was just about to bring them upstairs.
怎么了
What's wrong?
没事  只是不小心滑了一下
No, I'm fine. I just slipped.
-莎拉  你被感染了吗  -什么
- Are you infected, Sarah? - What?
你曾在药品库遇上彼得  他袭击你了吗
You were in the drug stockroom with Peter. Did he attack you?
没有  我说过了  他跑了
No. I told you. He ran off.
没错  但那只是你的一面之词
That's right, you told us.
-你认为我会在这种事上撒谎吗  -你的症状
- You think I would lie about something like that? - Your symptoms.
今天早上你还想掩藏手抖的事实
You tried to hide your hand tremor this morning,
而且你不肯把自己
and you wouldn't use yourself
作为快速反应测试的对照样本
as a control sample for the rapid-response test...
你要我做这个测试吗
You want me to take the test?
-行  -我不是在指责你
- Fine. - I'm not judging.
我能理解...
I can understand...
如果我真的被感染了  我绝不会隐瞒
I would never risk spreading an infectious disease.
那样太没有职业道德了
That's completely unethical.
你帮我当成什么样的医生了
What kind of a doctor do you think I am?
我没被感染
It's clear.
满意了
Happy?
-我很抱歉  我只是...  -艾伦在哪
- I'm sorry. I just thought... - Where's Alan?
在巡查分诊室  有事吗
Checking the triage room. Why?
我们有麻烦了
We have a problem.
苏勒玛尼博士逃离了聚变实验室
Dr. Sulemani broke out of the fusion lab.
-她还杀死了布赖斯博士  -什么
- She killed Dr. Bryce. - What?
苏勒玛尼博士也在这一层吗
Dr. Sulemani is on this level?
她正在大开杀戒
She's killing people!
停下来  保持冷静
Stop! Remain calm!
停下来
Stop!
请大家保持冷静
Please, stay calm!
保持冷静
Calm down!
-别紧张  先退后  -退后
- Relax, get back! - Back!
大家都保持冷静
Everyone remain calm!
-莎拉  -艾伦
- Sarah! - Alan!
发生了什么事  茱莉亚在哪
What's going on? Where's Julia?
退后
Get back!
茱莉亚
Julia!
退后  赶紧退后
Get back! Back, now!
离开走道  快离开走道
Out of the hallway! Get out of the hallway!
快离开走道
Get out of the hallway!
-我们得赶紧坐电梯回到楼上  -我不行
- We need to get in the elevator. Get upstairs... - I can't.
我们重新休整  治好伤者...
We'll regroup, get medical supplies for the injured...
-我得留在下面  -这里太危险了
- I have to stay down here. - It's too dangerous.
-我们得尽快离开  -艾伦  我不行
- We have to go. - Alan, I can't.
发生什么了
What happened?
沃克博士在哪里
Where is Dr. Walker?
她留在了楼下
She's staying down there.
你怎么能放心把她留在那里
How could you risk leaving her?
法拉格特博士
Dr. Farragut.
艾伦
Alan!
她被传染了  她感染了病毒
She's infected. She has the virus.
我们得封锁R层
We need to seal off Level R.
这是唯一能阻止继续传染的方式
It's the only way to stop the contagion.
就这么丢下他们吗  没有任何的水和食物
Leave them down there? With no food or water?
那里面有足够一星期的供给
There's a week's worth of supplies.
他说得对
He's right.
我们...
We've...
我已经失去了对局面的控制
I have lost control of this situation.
我们必须将那一层完全封锁
We need to seal it off.
沃克博士还在那里  你怎么能说出这种话
How can you say that with Dr. Walker still down there?
这只是支援来前的暂时之计
It's only until help arrives.
一旦卫星通讯可以使用
When the satellite com link goes operative again,
我就会呼叫军队寻求支援
I'm calling in the army for backup.
两百七十四人
Two hundred and seventy-four.
三名基奎特护士  死于埃博拉病毒
Three nurses in Kikwit of Ebola;
苏丹的六口之家  死于拉沙热
family of six in Sudan, Lassa fever;
十名住在海德堡大学宿舍的学生  死于军团病
10 students in a Heidelberg dorm, Legionnaires' disease;
我们都有过病人在我们眼前死去  艾伦
We've all had people die on our watch, Alan.
工作中难以避免  我们只能尽力而为
It's part of the job. We save who we can.
至今为止  这两百七十四人
I could live with 274
都是死于疾病  而不是因为我
because it was the disease that killed them,
所以我问心无愧
not me, until now.
可今天  我不但亲手杀死了一个人
I not only killed someone with my own hands today...
而且很有可能...  茱莉亚
but it's very likely... Julia
-很有可能...  -在我看来  你别无选择
- is very likely... - Way I hear it, you didn't have much choice.
我们如今面对的  是前所未有的挑战
What we're dealing with here... none of us has ever seen.
你是疾控中心最优秀的人才  你能创造奇迹
You're still the best CDC has. I've seen you pull off miracles.
你会想出办法救他们两个的
You'll figure out a way to save 'em both.
你的猴子研究得怎么样了
What happened with the monkey?
现在还得不出准确的结论
It's inconclusive for now.
这真不幸
That's too bad.
我...我还在做一些测试
I'm, uh... I'm still doing tests.
不  不
No. No.
受感染测试样本
生物危险品
不  它们该是绿色的
No, they should be green,
它们都该是绿色的  这不管用
they should all be green! It doesn't work.
这不管用
It doesn't work!
-观察室  -朵琳  亚伦在吗
- Observation. - Doreen, where's Alan?
茱尔斯
Jules?
听得到吗
Hello?
亚伦
Alan?
茱尔斯  你在吗  茱尔斯
Jules? You there? Jules?
有人在吗
Hello?!
能听到我说话吗
Can anybody hear me?!
那测试不管用
The test doesn't work!
那不管用
It doesn't work!
《双螺旋》前情提要
Previously on Helix...
那是他前妻吗  他从未说起过她或者他弟弟
That's his ex-wife? He never talks about her or his brother.
他没说的原因很可能是因为
That's probably because
他曾将前妻和弟弟捉奸在床
he caught her and his brother in bed together.
我刚研究出了测试方法
I just cracked the test.
我从三名安保人员身上取了对照样本
I swabbed three security techs for control samples -
结果都没变色
all clear -
然后我在已知感染者身上重做了那个测试
then I ran the test on known infectees.
结果全部呈现绿色  证明受到了感染
All green, positive for infection.
杜尚在研发一种解药  叫索迪拉
Duchamp was working on a cure, something called SODRA.
-共有多少试验样本死亡  -超过百分之七十五
- How many subjects were killed? - Over 75%.
我得留在下面
I have to stay down here.
这里太危险了  我们得尽快离开
It's too dangerous. We have to go.
艾伦  我不行
Alan, I can't.
她被传染了  她感染了病毒
She's infected. She has the virus.
我们得封锁R层
We need to seal off Level R.
这是唯一能阻止继续传染的方式
It's the only way to stop the contagion.
就这么丢下他们吗
Leave them down there?
他说得对  我们必须将那一层完全封锁
He's right. We need to seal it off.
测试不管用  这不管用
The test doesn't work. It doesn't work!
亚伦
Alan.
茱尔斯  你在吗  茱尔斯
Jules? You there? Jules?
第四天
他们关闭了跟我们的通讯
They shut off communications with us.
他们要饿死我们
They want to starve us out of here.
x宏和疾控中心的人已经放弃了我们
Hatake and the CDC have abandoned us.
没有治疗  没有解药
There is no treatment, no cure.
我们只得靠自己解决这事了
We are forced to take matters into our own hands.
疾控中心的人没有放弃我们
The CDC hasn't abandoned us.
等他们搞清楚这是怎么回事  该如何帮我们
They'll be back as soon as they figure out what's going on
就会回来的
and how to help us.
他们不会回来了
They are not coming back.
他们任我们在这儿自生自灭
They left us down here to die.
但我们绝不会坐以待毙
Only we will not go down without a fight.
这层有个二氧化碳排放系统的控制节点
On this level, there is a control node for the CO2 removal system.
我们可以手动操控
We can override it.
他们不能直接从外界过滤空气进来吗
Can't they just filter in air from outside?
外面现在零下60多度
It's 60 below out there,
主入口以内的区域都已经封锁
and everything past the main entrance is sealed up
像宇宙飞船一样  以防止传染
like a spaceship to prevent contamination.
如果我们把空气净化器关了
But if we shut off the oxygen scrubbers,
楼上的空气不超过六小时就会用尽
they run out of air upstairs in six hours max.
-我们也是  -R层比上面大
- So do we. - Level R is much larger.
我们人数更少  空气储量更多
Fewer people, bigger air pocket.
足够撑得比他们久  如果他们想
Enough to outlast them if they want to -
这话怎么说  比胆量的话
how do you say it? - play chicken.
这主意太糟了
This is a terrible idea.
我们得集中精力重建通讯
We need to focus on re-establishing communication.
这就是通讯
This is communication.
这个基地里满是危险物品
The base is full of hazardous materials
还有个更危险的传染病
and an even more hazardous infection.
你会危及每一个人...
You're endangering every single person--
谢谢你的意见  沃克博士
Thank you for your input, Dr. Walker,
但你是时候找个新地方待了
but it's time, I think, you found a new place to bunk.
你知道这是意外还是人为的吗
Do you even know if this was an accident, or was it intentional?
保持冷静  继续前进
我们说话这会儿  我的手下已经在调查了
I have my people investigating as we speak.
真是好极了  无法跟外界联系
Well, that's just great. And how do we control
我们要如何控制这场
this outbreak without communication
-疾病的爆发  -这里有着
- with the outside world? - You have access
世上最顶尖的头脑和设备
to the top minds and equipment in the world here.
这么说你是不打算修理卫星天线了
That sounds like you don't plan to repair the satellite dish.
顶级的军事承包商
It took a top-tier military contractor
搭脚手架弄了两个月才完成安装
two months in scaffolds to put up that equipment.
不是说修就能修的
It doesn't just get fixed.
那要多久才会有人发现我们这里出问题了
So how long before somebody notices we've gone dark?
我们定期会有物资补给
We have periodic resupply drops.
难道这里只有我觉得事态严重吗
Am I the only one here alarmed by this?
R层里关着那么多人  包括我的队员之一
We have people down on Level R, including one of my own,
他们却只有一周的供给
locked up with a week's worth of supplies.
是你要封锁那一层的
You're the one who wanted to seal that floor.
暂时性的  当时我以为可以向外界请求增援
Temporarily! When I thought we could call for reinforcements.
如果是长期情况
If this is a long-term situation,
我们就得照顾那些人
we have to provide those people with some standard of care!
我手头的人阻止一个带菌者
I barely had the manpower to stop
传染给半个基地的人就已经够呛了
one of those vectors from infecting half the base.
我们不能冒险开启那一层
We can't risk re-opening that floor.
我们现在面对的情况根本前所未见
We are dealing with something we've never seen before.
所以我们就这么放弃那些患病和快死的人吗
So, we just abandon the sick and the dying?
是的
Yes.
《双螺旋》第一季第四集
该死
Shit!
乔丹博士
Dr. Jordan.
怎么了
Yes.
范・艾根医生
Um, Dr. Van Eigem.
你昨天给我做过测试的  我能进去吗
You tested me yesterday. Can I come in?
当然  有什么事吗
Um, sure. How can I help you?
我不想去R层
I don't want to go to Level R.
不会的  你测试结果呈阴性
You won't. You tested negative.
测试结果一定准确吗  不会出差错吗
And you haven't gotten any false results? Any variances?
-不会的  测试是我亲自设计的  -你确定吗
- No. I designed the test myself. - Are you sure?
-当然了  -可是...
- Yes, of course. - I mean...
这样你还确定吗
are you really sure?
x宏坚持不让步  他想把感染的人
Hatake's not budging. He intends to leave the infected
留在下面  让他们自生自灭
downstairs with whatever food and supplies they can
-直到找到治疗方法为止  -可怜的茱莉亚
- scrounge until there's a treatment. - Poor Julia.
为什么我们不请求增援了
What happened to calling in reinforcements?
通讯系统瘫痪
With the com-link down,
我们跟外界失去了所有联系
we're blacked out and dead to the world.
他提到过什么定期补给
He did mention something about periodic resupply drops.
他说过定期是多久吗
He say how periodic they are?
没有  那家伙现在藏着掖着什么都不跟我们说
No, The man's playing his own game and he isn't sharing
你知道的  我们只能靠自己了
the playbook. You know that. We're on our own.
目前我们唯一的成果就是快速反应测试
All we have going for us is our rapid response test to the virus.
不好意思
Sorry.
我刚才忙聚合酶链式反应测试了
I had to babysit a PCR assay.
这借口真不错
And the dog ate my homework.
我知道大家现在都很有压力
Hey. We're all feeling the pressure, all right?
但是我们得集中注意力
But we need to stay on point here.
如果我们不采取行动
There are a lot of people in
会有很多人痛苦不堪备受煎熬
for a lot of suffering if we don't step it up.
朵琳  病毒传染源你查得怎么样了
Doreen, what's your progress on the source?
极有可能是动物传播
Strong possibility of zoonotic transfer.
唯一的问题是  是猴子传给了人
Only question is: was it a monkey to human,
-还是人传给的猴子  -我需要更详细的结果
- or the other way around? - I need more than that.
-莎拉你呢  -我正在继续沃克
- Sarah? - I'm picking up Walker's
对纳尔维克A和B样本的分析
analysis of the NARVIK-A and B samples.
DNA测序仪在一天24小时不停运作
I have the DNA sequencers going 24/7,
同时我在用多重连接依赖式探针扩增法
and I'm running multiplex ligation-dependent probe
对所有已知毒性致病因子进行检测
amplifications for all known virulence factors.
很好  我们只有尽快找到可行治疗方法
Good. The sooner we have a viable treatment option,
才能尽快让茱莉亚回来  记住这点
the sooner we get Julia back. Just remember that.
我先去看看我哥哥
I'm gonna check on my brother.
隔离室
门已关闭
请输入密码
情况危急
吗啡好像不起作用
I'm afraid the morphine isn't helping.
我知道这种症状  杜尚博士  他快不行了
I know the symptoms, Dr. Duchamp. He's dying.
我们需要马上使用索迪拉进行治疗
We need to start the SODRA immediately.
索迪拉疗法
The SODRA treatment has
从未在人体上进行过测试  一次也没有
never been tested on humans beings. Not once.
说不定会有效呢
That doesn't mean it won't work.
它不是万能抗病毒治疗剂吗
It's a universal antiviral.
我也希望我们有时间测试  可是情况紧急
I wish we had time for testing, but we don't.
如果这是你的弟弟
If it were your brother,
难道你不会想尽一切办法救他吗
wouldn't you try everything you could?
用未经临床测试的疗法杀人
Killing a human being with an untested treatment,
这是不道德的
it's unconscionable.
如果病人无法做出明确指示
It's up to next of kin to give informed consent
那么病人的亲属有知情同意权
when the patient has left no clear directives,
即使病人需要接受高度实验性治疗
even in the case of a highly- experimental treatment.
我同意了
I consent.
拜耶塞罗少校
Major Balleseros.
我听说你的卫星天线坏了
Heard about your satellite dish.
真糟糕啊
Hell of a thing.
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
我倒觉得
I like to think
我这么做是十分理智的决定
I'm bringing a little sanity to the proceedings.
我在这的使命之一
Keeping the word from getting
就是不让世人知道这里发生的破事
out on this shit-show is one of my imperatives.
我也有自己的使命
I also have imperatives.
自从来到这里
I've been waiting to hear
我就一直很好奇你的使命究竟是什么
what yours might be since I got here,
但我可不想疾控中心或者你的疯子科学家
you know, before the CDC or one of your wingnut scientists
将这一切公诸于世
shares it with the rest of the world.
我在这里的工作十分机密
My work here is protected,
-你无权知情  -不再如此了
- even from you. - Not anymore.
你制造出了一种病毒
You made a virus that does
跟你鼓吹的作用毫不相干
everything other than what you advertised.
以你的智商  你根本没资格
You don't have the intellectual capacity
评价我的工作
to evaluate my work.
你想让事情变得容易些吗
You want things to get easier?
那就把你许诺给上头的成果弄出来
Produce the results you promised our employers.
-环境警报  -发生什么了
- Environmental alert. - What's going on?
-空气感应器警报被触发  -环境警报
- Atmosphere sensor alert. - Environmental alert.
氧气水平
二氧化碳水平
再生系统关闭
二氧化碳含量在上升
CO2 levels are rising.
有人把氧气净化器关掉了
Someone's shut off the oxygen scrubbers.
很糟糕吗
Is that bad?
环境警报
Environmental alert.
只要你想呼吸  就糟得很
Only if you like breathing.
环境警报
Environmental alert.
控制节点离旧生热学实验室30米远
Control node is 30 meters from the old thermogenics lab.
装有模拟控制开关
It was engineered with analog override switches
以控制氧气净化器
for the oxygen scrubbers.
-是软件故障吗  -开关都基于硬件编码
- System malfunction? - They used a hardwired code.
我推测是那些人想逼我们下到R层
My guess is they want to force us down to Level R.
这是以断氧要挟我们去谈判
It's a blackmail play to get us to negotiate.
还能维持多长时间
How much time?
六小时后二氧化碳水平将达到临界值
Six hours before CO2 levels hit the redline.
再过两小时  我们就会感到不适
In two hours we can expect to start suffering
头痛  反胃  呕吐
headaches, nausea, vomiting--
那好  我们抄家伙下去谈判吧
All right. Let's get some weapons, and go negotiate.
他们肯定设了埋伏  我们都会被扣作人质
They'll have an ambush ready. We'd be taken hostage.
也只有你担心这个
Speak for yourself.
-我们到底怎么做  -不需要你插手
- What do we do? - We do nothing.
我会亲自解决这件事
I will handle this personally.
就像你亲自"解决"其他事那样吗
Like you've handled everything else?
我这就带一队安保人员下去
I'll take a security team downstairs.
不用带人  你和我就行
No security team; just you and me.
你也去吗
You're going?
这座基地努力多年才得以建成
It took many years to build this base.
如果有人想毁掉它
I won't sit by while someone tries
我绝不会坐视不理
to destroy it.
张嘴
Open up.
你就直说了吧  我被感染了吗
Just get it over with. Am I infected?
头痛是非常常见的病状
Headache is a very general symptom.
你不会有事的  除非你产生幻觉
It's not as if you're hallucinating
或者开始情绪不稳  暴躁易怒
or experiencing labile emotions and uncontrollable anger.
迟早的事
Not yet.
检测结果证明你没被感染
Test says you're clear.
那这是怎么回事
What about this?
这可能只是压力过大导致的心身性反应
It's possible that it's a psychosomatic response to stress.
这不是我幻想出来的  你还不明白吗
This is not in my head! Don't you get that?
你需要平复一下情绪
You need to calm down.
你说得倒轻巧
That's easy for you to say.
染上致命病毒的人又不是你
You're not the one with a deadly disease.
别让他们把我送下去
Don't let them send me down there.
求你了  一旦被送下去  我再也回不来了
Please? If I go down there, I'll never come back up.
别激动  我们可不是
Hey. We're not just
把感染者送下去等死的
sending people down there to die.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
那只是你个人的想法而已
That's what you think.
你不了解x宏这个人
You don't know Hatake.
那你也不了解法拉格特博士
And you don't know Dr. Farragut.
他绝不会让我们出任何事的
He's not gonna let anything happen to us.
希望你是对的  莎拉
I hope I can trust you, Sarah.
呼吸  要呼吸  彼得
Breathe. Breathe, Peter.
没事的
It's OK.
彼得  没事的  会没事的
Peter, it'll be OK. It'll be OK.
剂量调节器有问题了吗
Something wrong with the dose regulator?
不管我说什么也拦不住你了是吗
Is there anything I can tell you to make you stop?
没错
No.
呼吸  呼吸
Breathe. Breathe.
-氧气要耗尽了吗  -反正我还能呼吸
- We out of air yet? - I'm still breathing.
上次我给你的样本你检测出结果了吗
Did you get any results from that sample I gave you?
你想从我这要答案  你也得给我答案
You want answers, I want answers.
明白现在的局面了吧
See how that works?
我完全应该把这些情况报告给艾伦
There's no reason I shouldn't be telling Alan what's what.
你想让我接着忙活你这个小实验
You want me to keep working on your little pet project?
先给我个理由
Give me a reason.
也许你没注意  但这有人处心积虑
Maybe you haven't noticed, but there are people that
不想让基地里的秘密泄露出去
don't want what's inside this base getting out.
我是既缺觉  又缺咖啡  还过不了烟瘾
I haven't had nearly enough sleep, coffee, or cigarettes
再多点这种破事我可要受不了了
to deal with any more of this Fox Mulder crap from you.
朵琳
Doreen.
我接下来要告诉你的事  你如果泄露出去
If you tell another living soul what I'm about to say,
我会惹上大麻烦
I end up in a hurt locker.
我们现在的状况好得到哪去吗
You mean as opposed to this paradise?
我是国防部特别调查小组的人
I'm with a special investigative section in the Pentagon.
我来是为了对这里的秘密非法研究
I was sent as part of an internal inquiry
进行内部调查
for a black-bag research operation.
那你干嘛一开始不说
Well, why didn't you say so in the first place?
别让我后悔告诉你这事
Don't make me regret this.
好吧
Ok.
那么说  你的上级...认为病毒是武器吗
So, your superiors... think the virus is a weapon?
武器是用来消灭敌人的
Weapons get rid of the enemy;
但这病毒似乎会让敌人变得更危险
this thing seems to make them even more dangerous.
我们只知道这是一个不受政府掌控
What we have is a hidden base
秘密进行非法研究的隐密基地
conducting secret research outside of the reach of any government.
没人了解真实情况
No one knows the bigger picture.
你觉得你就了解吗
And you think you do?
我听德特里克堡的病菌专家们谈到
I heard these germ docs over at Fort Detrick
美国生物防御计划中心
用病毒运输DNA
talking about using viruses to move DNA around.
-基因运载工具吗  -对  就是这个
- Gene delivery vehicles? - Yeah, that was it.
或许病毒就像货车一样
What if this virus is acting like a freight train
将这些奇怪的DNA送进了宿主体内呢
pulling some weird-ass DNA behind it?
也有可能  你也不像表面看上去那么蠢嘛
Maybe... you're not as dumb as you look.
我会对病毒进行基因测序
I'll run the virus through the gene sequencer.
记着点  空气就快耗完  时间不多了
Try to remember that we are running out of air.
你可以把防毒面罩拿下来  病毒不是空气传播的
You can take the gas mask off. The virus isn't airborne.
你有什么症状吗
Are you experiencing any symptoms?
恶心  发热  排出黑色粘液
Nausea, fever, black mucus discharge?
我保证  我跟他不一样
I promise... I'm not like him.
如果我真的发疯了
If I start going crazy,
我允许你用刚才闩在门上的
you have my permission to beat me to death with that stick
那根棍子把我打死
that you suck in the door, just right now.
我只是想谢谢你救了我
I'd like to thank my rescuer.
求你了
Please.
手套我就不脱了
I'm keeping my gloves on.
我理解
Fair enough.
你叫什么
What's your name?
-杰伊  -没有什么头衔吗
- Jaye. - Just Jaye?
我有硕士博士学位各种乱七八糟的
I'm an MD, PhD, blah, blah, blah.
后面有整个字母表的头衔  如果有差别的话
Got an alphabet soup after my name if that makes any difference.
没差别
It doesn't.
-我是茱莉亚  茱莉亚・沃克  -我知道你是谁
- I'm Julia. Julia Walker-- - I know who you are.
你是疾控中心的那妞
You're that CDC chick.
我挺喜欢这样的叫法
I kinda like the sound of that.
我不想表现得像个粗鲁的客人
I hate to be a crappy houseguest,
但你有吃的或者喝的吗
but you got anything to eat or drink around here?
随意看看吧
Look around.
这就是我的家了  喜欢吗
You just got the grand tour. You like it?
这样的话  我更宁愿待在蒙大拿
All in all, I'd rather be in Montana.
x宏在各种藏身之处都放了食物贮存柜
Hatake stashed MRE lockers in strategic locations -
以防有朝一日事态失去控制
You know, in case the shit ever hit the fan.
-要我说这绝对是时候了  -对
- Oh, I'd say this qualifies. - Yeah.
2小时36分钟内  依据杜尚疗法
Two hours, 36 minutes, the first two infusions
修改版程序  病人注射了头两次
of the SODRA antiviral have been administered
索迪拉抗病毒药剂
under the modified Duchamp protocols.
病人情况显著稳定
Patient marginally stabilizing.
你就想着这么解脱吗
Is this how you want to go out?
还记得那时候你是个有种
The kid who had the balls to go through
在父亲昏倒之后掏他口袋的小孩吗
Dad's pockets when he was passed out?
本来我俩五五分钱  你说服我七三开
The kid who talked me down from a 50/50 to a 70/30 split
而且说得像是给了我面子一样
and made it seem like he was doing me a favor?
如果当时不是你
I would not have survived
我可能早死了
if you hadn't been there.
那男人...
What that man...
那男人对我们做的...
what that man did to us...
这是我欠你的
I owe you this.
而你欠我的
And you owe me...
是那个晚上
for that night.
环境警报
Environmental alert.
警告  氧气浓度已低至临界值
环境警报
Environmental alert.
我的头好痛
My head hurts.
你有强效一点的药吗
Do you have anything stronger?
我给你的非甾体类消炎药[镇痛药物]
I've given you the highest dosage of NSAID...
已经是最高剂量了
NSAIDs I can.
没关系  我不在乎肝脏损伤的副作用
I'm not worried about hurting my liver.
你重新确认了快速反应测试的结果吗
Did you recheck your rapid response tests?
是的
I did.
没有任何问题
There's nothing wrong with it.
你说过你会试着更关心我一些
You said you'd step up the care packages.
但一周就那几次语音通信远远不够
It's not enough to Skype with me a couple times a week.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你总是沉默不语
The silences...
缜默无言
the pauses.
你就不能痛快点做个了断
Why don't you just tell me her name
告诉我她的名字吗
and get it over with?
这冰洞里多得是人愿意和我在一起
There's tons of guys on this ice hole who'd love to be with me.
你在和谁说话
Who are you talking to?
一个如果仍不知悔改  就即将成为我前男友的人
My ex-boyfriend if he doesn't step up his game.
你听见我说的了吗
Did you hear me?
我才不会守在你身边等你想清楚
'Cause I'm not gonna wait around for you to figure it out.
不要走
Don't go.
你出现幻觉了
You're hallucinating,
说明我们的测试并不管用
which means that our test doesn't work.
-我得告诉艾伦  -求你了
- I need to tell Alan. - Please.
你不能告诉别人
You can't tell anyone.
我不能让你留在这里  你病了
I can't keep you here. You're sick.
我不是唯一有病的人
I'm not the only one.
你什么时候知道自己长了肿瘤的
How long have you known about your tumor?
-我没有肿瘤  -别骗我了
- I don't have a tumor. - Please.
我可是个肿瘤学家
I'm an oncologist.
言语不清  不受控制的颤抖
Slurring speech, tremors,
还有处方药加巴喷丁
prescription vial of Gabapentin.
我谁也没告诉
I haven't told anyone.
医患特权可以是双向的
Doctor-patient privilege goes both ways.
不如我们彼此为对方保密
It'll be our secret.
这一般要用多久
How long does this usually take?
谁也说不准
As long as it takes.
这些事情急不得
You can't rush these things.
这玩意非常重要
This is the real deal --
构造生命的基础什么的
building blocks of life and all that.
你放的这破音乐很难让人保持耐心
It's hard to be patient listening to your crappy music.
告诉我你终于发现了什么
Please tell me that means something.
是的
Oh, yes.
和我的小伙伴打个招呼吧
Say hello to my little friend.
病毒的核糖核酸图可以显示一些隐藏信息
An RNA map of the virus should show us what's under the hood.
好奇怪
Weird.
未知蛋白结构
我从没见过这种组合结构
I've never seen this combination before.
这说明什么
Meaning?
说明有人特意设计出这种病毒
Meaning someone designed this virus,
这绝对不是大自然的产物
and it sure as shit wasn't Mother Nature.
这是人类制造出来的
We're looking at the hand of man here.
这种特殊的蛋白质结构设计能把病毒
Proteins specifically designed to bind the virus to specific
绑在特定的细胞上以传递它的遗传信息
cells so it can deliver its genetic message.
什么信息
What's the message?
你知道他们设计这种病毒有什么用吗
Can you tell what they designed it to do?
我不知道
No.
但是我能弄明白
But I can find out.
莎拉
Hey, Sarah.
他怎么样了
How is he?
至少他有氧气瓶用
At least he has bottled oxygen,
不像我们
unlike the rest of us.
你还好吗  开始感到缺氧了吗
You Ok? You feeling the CO2 yet?
还没有
No.
我...
I, um...
我刚才...
I was...
找出了之前快速反应测试的结果
going over the rapid response test.
重新检查了一遍
I was... I was rechecking them.
结果...
And, um...
艾伦
Alan.
彼得
Peter?
彼得  你能看见我吗
Peter, can you see me?
我当然能看见你
Of course I can see you.
那个美女是谁
Who's the pretty one?
莎拉...  莎拉  这是...
Sarah... Sarah, this...
这是我弟弟  彼得
this is my brother Peter.
莎拉  你刚才想说什么
Sarah, you had something you wanted to tell me
快速反应测试怎么了
about the rapid response test?
测试不管用
It doesn't work.
什么叫不管用
What do you mean it doesn't work?
我当时在把结果整理归档
I was archiving the results,
结果发现了细胞循环程序里的一个缺陷
and I found a flaw in the cell line cycling protocol.
我们不能相信那些结果
We can't trust any of the results.
这层有感染者吗
Are there any infected on this floor?
没  至少还没有人上报
No. No one's reported in,
但我们不能肯定楼下的人是否都被感染了
but we can't trust that everyone downstairs is a positive.
很抱歉我让你失望了
I'm really sorry I let you down.
-还有沃克  -别这么说
- And Walker. - No, no
是我的失误  我责无旁贷
I made a mistake. There's no excuse.
现在你要做的就是弥补它
Right now you get to fix it.
-你找出漏洞了吗  -我还在努力
- Have you isolated the flaw? - I'm working on it.
好的  抓紧时间
All right, work faster.
然后去找x博士  告诉他我们需要进行
Then find Hatake and tell him we need to implement
全基地范围的重新检测
a base-wide retesting protocol,
然后解除R层的封锁  好吗
then open Level R, all right?
这事越快办妥
The sooner this gets done,
我们就能越早将那些人放出来
the sooner we can get those people out of there.
好
Right.
刚从安保人员那反馈来的消息
Security's checking in.
人们已经开始出现头痛和虚弱现象
People are reporting headaches, fatigue,
这些都是早期二氧化碳中毒的症状
which are early signs of CO2 poisoning.
我们必须尽快去R层解决这个问题
We need to get down to Level R and handle this.
这是什么
What am I looking at?
准许进入
Access granted.
我不知道要怎么说才好  但是
I don't know quite how to say this, but...
自从你感染后  这里的情况便急转直下
things have gone downhill since you were infected.
真的吗
No shit?
彼得
Peter.
我知道你很虚弱
I know you're weak,
但是我有好多疑问
but I have so many questions
关于你这里的工作  关于这个地方
about your work here, about this... this place.
七三分  你一点风险都不需要承担
Seventy-thirty? You're not taking any of the risk.
-什么  -好吧  六四分  最终价
- What? - OK, all right, 60-40, final offer.
谁知道那老头口袋里到底装着什么呢
You never know what's gonna come out of the old man's pockets.
-行  那就六四分  哥们  -那好
- Sixty-forty is just fine with me, buddy. - Ok.
你去藏起来  我到手了就去找你
You go hide. I'll find you when it's done.
如果你愿意  我更想在这陪着你
I will stay right here with you if that's ok.
-很危险的  -我知道  没关系
- It's dangerous. - I know. It's ok.
没关系的
It's ok.
弗莱明指挥官牙买加朗姆酒
Fleming's Commander Jamaica rum.
什么
What?
老头子常喝的酒
That was the old man's poison.
感觉波旁威士忌更适合他这种卑鄙小人
You'd think a mean scumbag like him would be a bourbon drunk.
-你试过那玩意吗  -他死了
- You ever try that stuff? - He's dead.
很久以前就死了  他不会
Been gone a long time. He can't...
再伤害我们了
hurt us anymore.
估计是因为被困在这种地方
Something about being trapped in this place...
我总会时不时看到那混蛋
I see that bastard around every corner.
什么都没有
Snake eyes.
让我们进去
Hey! Let us in!
别那么大声  杰伊
Not so loud, Jaye.
给我闭嘴  你会引来带菌者的
Shut the hell up! You're gonna attract the vectors!
-那就开门  -我们没地方了
- Then open the door. - We don't have any room.
胡扯  让我们进去
Bullshit. Let us in.
求你了
Please!
你听到了吗
Do you hear that?
-让我们进去  -闭嘴  过来
- Let us in! - Shut up. Come on.
他怎么样
How is he?
他一直在不停地回忆我们的童年
Well, he won't talk about much of anything but our childhood.
精神错乱吗
Delirium?
应该不是  他的情况时好时坏
Uh, no. I mean, he's in and out of it, but, uh,
我不知道  很难说  他好像
I don't know, it's hard to say. He just...
好像陷在了过去当中
He's stuck back there.
这是病毒数量对比吗
Are these the viral load comparisons?
病毒数量在注射索迪拉后有所下降  但是现在
They were declining after the SODRA infusions took hold, but now...
看起来病毒正在回侵
This looks like the virus is coming back -
而且来势更加凶猛
with a vengeance.
你知道我们是孤注一掷
You knew we were taking a chance.
-我很遗憾  -但是它起了作用
- I'm sorry. - But it was working.
或许我们可以再增加剂量
I mean, maybe we could... we could be more aggressive.
我们给他的剂量已经远远超出了我的试验用量
We've already given him a larger dose than any of my studies.
再多就很有可能会引起免疫性中毒
Any more could trigger a cascade of antiviral toxicity.
我们无能为力了
There's nothing we can do.
他还有多久时间
How long does he have?
如果你还有什么要对他说的
If you've got anything to say to him...
好好把握这最后的机会吧
...take this time and make the most of it.
彼得  我们得谈谈
Peter, we need to talk about...
-我们尝试的疗法  -你这语气听着不妙
- The treatment we're trying is... - Aw, hell, I know that tone.
...仍停留在试验阶段
...highly experimental.
每当妈妈病情加重的时候
Every time mom took a turn,
你脸上就会出现这副悲惨的表情
you've have that sad-sack look on your face.
有多糟
How bad?
天呐  你就直说吧
Aw, Jesus, don't sugar-coat it.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
但我必须要问你一些问题
I have to ask some questions.
目前这里发生的事情我们没办法解释
There are things going on here that we can't explain.
你认为我可以吗
And you think I can?
发生的这一切或许与你的研究有关
Some of it may have to do with your research.
你向来是家里最聪明的那个
Well, you were the genius in the family,
难道你没发现
and you couldn't figure out
我在这里做的都是不起眼的杂活吗
that I've been doing shit work up here?
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
我本以为x宏招募我
I thought Hatake recruited me
是让我来做高端前沿的科研
to do next-gen stuff.
我以为自己大显身手的机会到了
This was gonna be my ticket to the show.
告诉我关于病毒的事
Just tell me about the virus.
x宏让我为其他医生做动物尸检
Hatake had me doing animal necropsies for the other docs.
我一直都得不到重用
I was never the alpha.
他对我唯一感兴趣的一点就是
The only part of my life Hatake seemed interested in was...
茱莉亚
...Julia.
他是怎么知道她的
How did he know about her?
他到处都有耳目
He's got ears everywhere.
我是说  在这里大家都喜欢向他倾诉
I mean, he was the one around here who ever wanted to talk.
是我逼你出走  我欠你更多
I drove you away. I owed you better.
别反驳  你知道事实如此
No, you know I'm right.
我本来应该在那里的  可是我
I could have been there, but I didn't...
我不想再继续亏欠你
...I didn't want to owe you anymore -
不管是因为爸爸  还是其他任何人
not for dad, not for anyone.
-别说了  -是你一直在照看着我
- Don't do that. - You were the one who stuck up for me.
你为了保护我
You were the one
-毅然与父亲对抗  -不是这样的
- running interference with the old man. - It was never like that.
我一直都嫉妒你
I envied you.
-所以我才没去  -从她出现的那一刻起
- That's why I wasn't there. - From the moment she showed up...
所以你们两个那天晚上
That's why the two of you ended up together.
-才会在一起  -不只是那一晚
- That night. - It wasn't just that night.
我们在之前就开始了
It was before.
每隔一段时间  我们都会一起出差参加会议
Every once in a while, when we'd travel to some conference.
即使当你阻止了我们后  我们也很清楚
Even after you ended things, we knew we...
我们不会停止见面的
we couldn't stop seeing each other.
所以我才会来这里
That's why I came up here.
我无法控制自己
I couldn't stay away.
所以只能有多远走多远
I went as far as I could.
真的很对不起
I'm so sorry.
他要不行了
He's crashing!
x博士
Dr. Hatake?
加巴喷丁
Gabapentin.
加巴喷丁  在哪里  到底在哪里
Gabapentin, come on, come on!
硫酸吗啡
索迪拉疗程过后三小时
Three hours after completion of SODRA protocol,
病人心脏停搏
patient experienced cardiac arrest
并伴有严重的病毒性败血症
congruent with overwhelming viremic sepsis.
此次恶化
This time,
导致脑电波活动急剧下降
with concomitant catastrophic decrease in brainwave activity.
病人经过除颤器抢救后
Patient has been fitted with a defib vest,
目前处于植物人状态
is now intubated and on artificial respiration
只能靠插管维持人工呼吸
in a vegetative state.
病人几乎不可能重新恢复知觉
It's unlikely that the patient will regain consciousness
或脱离呼吸机自主生存
or be able to maintain his own life without the ventilator.
我能感觉到他们抓住了我  想拖我走
I can feel their hands on me, dragging me away.
求求你快阻止他们
Please make them stop.
没事的  闭上眼睛
Shh, close your eyes,
听医生的话  把眼睛闭上
close your eyes. Doctor's orders.
一切会没事的
Everything's gonna be fine.
我不会让他们把你带走的  我发誓
I'm not gonna let them take you, I promise.
我就知道你能保护我免受他们侵害
I knew I could trust you to protect me from them.
是不是  我说了吧
Did I tell you, or did I tell you?
这里的食物够吃几星期了
There's enough food here for weeks.
你知道这意味着什么吗
Do you know what this means?
一日三餐都吃奶酪面包吗
Cheese bread three meals a day?
还好你对这里的地形了如指掌
Good thing you know your way around this base.
看来对这里了解的不止我一个人
Looks like I'm not the only one.
那是什么
What is it?
是我名字的缩写
It's my initials.
茱莉亚・琳恩・沃克
Julia Lynn Walker.
这也太巧合了吧
Hell of a coincidence.
不  不是巧合
No, it isn't.
不可能的
It can't be.
不可能什么
Can't be what?
这是我的字迹
It's my writing.
我就是这么写自己名字的  还有
The way I wrote my name and...
画这些夜来香花朵
the flower evening primrose.
我小时候最喜欢它了
It was my favorite when I was a girl.
它们在蒙大拿州随处可见
It grows in Montana.
我的笔记本里画满了这个
I have notebooks full of them.
这是我的笔迹
I did this.
我以前来过这
I've been here before.
警告  氧气浓度已低至临界值
环境警告
Environmental alert.
先生们
Gentlemen.
我们需要谈谈
We need to have a talk.
放下武器  不会用上它们的
Put down the weapons. They won't be necessary.
抱歉  不能如你所愿
Forgive us if we don't agree.
断绝这个基地的氧气无异于谋杀
Depriving this base of oxygen is murder.
难道把我们关起来
What about locking us up
不给补给  放弃治疗就不是谋杀吗
with barely any supplies and no treatment?
这只是暂时的隔离
It is only a temporary quarantine.
或许你该跟我们一起待在下面
Maybe you should stay down here with us.
让我们看看什么叫"暂时"
Then we'll see your definition of "Temporary."
你说得没错
You are right.
我没有设身处地为你们着想
I'm not standing in your shoes.
我不得不做一个艰难的选择
I had to make a hard choice.
-你在玩弄我们的生命  -我没有
- You're playing with our lives. - I'm not.
-我们的生命同等重要  -你说谎
- Your lives are worth no less than mine. - You're lying.
要不我怎么会只带一个人来呢
Why else would I come down here with only one man?
你们完全可以干掉我俩
You could kill us both.
如果我们相互斗争  必然死路一条
If we fight... we die.
只有齐心协力
Together...
才能死里逃生
we survive.
我们能相信你吗
We have your word?
我以声誉担保
My word of honor.
谢谢
Thank you.
他们就要停手了
They were about to give up.
你为什么还...
Why did you...
为什么
Why?
他们是停手了  可他们没投降
They gave up... but they did not surrender.
他们会杀了我们
They were willing to kill us.
-也许不是今天  -但
- Maybe not today. - But--
他们不会善罢甘休的
They would not have stopped.
我们可以把他们关起来
We could have just locked them up.
不到36小时前
You shot an unarmed woman
你杀了一个手无寸铁的女人
less than 36 hours ago.
那是为了保护你
To protect you.
刚才就算还了你的人情
I just returned the favor.
把尸体处理了  上楼去吧
Dispose of the bodies and go back upstairs.
你不上去吗
You're not coming?
我还有事要处理
I have something to take care of.
沃克博士吗
Dr. Walker?
为何冒这个险
Why take the risk?
我需要你去上面看着
I need you upstairs.
就我所知  病毒中携带的遗传信息
As far as I can see, the genetic message inside the virus
是大量拼接而成  真正的前沿技术
is a massive splice job - real cutting edge -
源于动物和人类
from animal and human species.
有趣的地方在这里
And here's where it gets interesting.
未知
这有什么有趣的
How is that interesting?
因为它全然未知
Because it's completely unknown.
它不同于人类已知的任何基因序列
Ran it against every genetic sequence known to man.
这是完全未知的单链
This is a completely unidentified single strand.
为什么有人想把它植入人体内
Why would anyone want to put that inside of us?
我不知道  但这么做后果极其严重
I don't have a clue, but it scares the crap out of me.
这种病毒能强制将这些信息输入人体内
There's some trait that they want us to manifest,
AMH蛋白匹配
从而让我们显现出某些特性
and this disease is a way to force it in.
病毒的创造者想从内到外
The people who designed this virus want to change us
彻底地改变我们
from the inside out.
我也许并不完美
I mean, I may not be perfect,
但我喜欢我原本的样子
but... I like what I am.
我也喜欢这样的你  朵琳
I like you too, Doreen.
至少我们还没被感染
Well, we're not infected yet.
我们把这个报告给艾伦
We'll take this to Alan,
查清真相
get to the bottom of it,
在幕后黑手造成实质伤害前
stop whoever's doing this
及时阻止他们
before they cause any real damage.
你怎么了
Hey, what's wrong?
能发现这一切多亏了你
This was your idea to begin with.
你是对的
You were right.
是啊
I know.
抱歉  朵琳  非常抱歉
Sorry, Doreen. I'm so sorry.
《双螺旋》前情提要
Previously on Helix...
他要不行了
He's crashing!
那是他前妻吗  他从未说起过她或者他弟弟
That's his ex-wife? He never talks about her or his brother.
他没说的原因很可能是因为
That's probably because
他曾将前妻和弟弟捉奸在床
he caught her and his brother in bed together.
这是我的笔迹
I did this.
我以前来过这
I've been here before.
-你测试结果呈阴性  -你确定吗
- You tested negative. - Are you really sure?
我不能让你留在这里  你病了
I can't keep you here. You're sick.
我不是唯一有病的人
I'm not the only one.
你什么时候知道自己长了肿瘤的
How long have you known about your tumor?
病毒的创造者想从内到外
The people who designed this virus want to change us,
彻底地改变我们
from the inside out.
第五日
情报收集任务完成
请求撤离
信息已发送
等待回复
撤离搁置
视位置及威特博士获救情况而定
信息结束
请详细说明
信息已发送
等待回复
带回威特博士
信息结束
威特博士是谁
Who the hell is Dr. Hvit?
法拉格特博士  你要见我是吗
Dr. Farragut, you wanted to see me?
是的  想让你看点东西
Yeah, I want to show you something.
-是彼得病情反复了吗  -不  他情况还那样
- Is it Peter? - No. His status is unchanged.
还是没有大脑活动
Still no brain activity.
来看这个
Have a look at this.
我用你的治疗方案
I used your protocols and
以及我正在试验的改良化合物
a modified compound I've been experimenting with.
在这两处结合位点
I substituted multiple residues
用多样残留物代替
at these two binding sites,
在这里加了四氢呋喃氨基甲酸酯
added a tetrahydrofuran carbamate here,
在这里加了三嗪环  以减少硬脂交互作用
a triazine ring here, all to reduce stearic interaction.
这样就可以延缓病毒攻破索迪拉
And that's taking the virus longer to break the SODRAs down.
但终究还是抵御不了
But it still does in the end.
我在培养菌中能做到的只有这样了
I've taken this as far as I can in culture.
我得看看它在活组织中的反应
I need to see how it reacts in living tissue.
我可以马上开始动物实验
I can start animal studies to test efficacy
以验证其疗效和安全性
and safety right away.
-24小时内就能出结果  -我希望这个试验
- We could have results in 24 hours-- - I'd like to bring
能让我队伍里的兽医病理学家朵琳・博伊尔参与
my veterinary pathologist, Doreen Boyle, up to speed on this.
她应该能帮不少忙
I think she could be a big help.
艾伦  这是一大突破
Alan, this is progress.
还得先在老鼠身上看看是否有效
It has to work in the rats first.
-如果有效呢  -如果有效
- And if it does? - If it does,
x宏就没有借口了
Hatake won't have any more excuses.
我们就能解除R层的封锁
We'll reopen Level R,
开始在茱莉亚和其他受感染的病患身上试验
start testing Julia and the rest of the infected patients.
法拉格特博士  我让你准点报备的
Dr. Farragut. I asked you to check in on the hour.
不受干扰的研究才能尽快取得成果
Uninterrupted research is how we get results.
x宏有意见的话
If Hatake has a problem with that,
你让他自己来跟我说
he can talk to me himself - for whatever that's worth.
他让我全权负责这里  他正在...
He's left me in charge while he takes care--
他在处理"基地事宜"  谁信啊
While he conducts "base business". Right.
别人会听到的
Someone might hear you.
-好痛  -我知道  但你得小声点
- It hurts. - I know, but you have to stay quiet.
要是被他们发现  你就得去R层了
If they find you, they'll take you back to Level R.
我得回实验室工作了
I have to get back to my lab work.
我会尽快拿些吗啡回来
I'll try and get back as soon as I can with more morphine.
热乎乎的巧克力布朗尼蛋糕
Warm, gooey chocolate brownies.
威斯康星大学一项研究表明
A study at the University of Wisconsin showed that
想象可口的食物有助减轻疼痛
fantasizing about delicious food can help minimize pain.
布朗尼蛋糕是我的最爱
Brownies are my go-to.
纸杯蛋糕
Cupcakes.
很好
That's good.
什么样的  越详细越好
What kind? The more specific, the better.
红丝绒奶油干酪糖霜蛋糕
Red velvet, cream cheese icing.
而且不是松松垮垮的那种
And none of that flaky cake.
我喜欢紧实的
I like it dense.
好受些了吗
Did it help?
好点了
A little...
但把我馋虫勾起来了
But now I'm hungry.
等待是最折磨人的部分
The worst part is the waiting.
死亡不知何时就会突然降临
Death should come out of nowhere.
而你却能够坦然面对
You shouldn't have to stare it in the face.
你怎么做到的
How do you do it,
明知难逃一死却还能坚持生活
knowing you're just waiting to die?
人人都难逃一死
We're all waiting to die,
只不过我的时间更少一点而已
I just have a little less time.
员工数据库检索模块
搜索姓名  威特
无结果
你在这干什么
What the hell are you doing?
坐这挺惬意啊
It's comfy.
不许坐他的座位
Get out of his chair.
好  威特博士在哪
Sure. Where's Dr. Hvit?
-谁  -威特博士
- Who? - Dr. Hvit.
我想和他或者她谈谈  现在就谈
I need to speak to him, or her, right away.
基地里没有这号人物
There's no one on this base by the name of Dr. Hvit.
马上离开他的座位
Now get out of his chair.
你还真是尽忠职守啊
He's got you well trained.
你说什么
Excuse me?
他给了你多少好处让你这般忠心耿耿
How much is he paying you to inspire such loyalty?
-我不听命于他  -是啊
- I don't work for him. - That's right.
他收养了你  你就像他的儿子
He adopted you. You're like a son to him.
我就是他的儿子
I am his son.
你知不知道  在里约热内卢的贫民窟
You know, in the favelas in Rio,
那里的帮派都自称为家族
the gangs, they call themselves a familia.
也就是家庭的意思  而且他们有个说法
Family. And they have a saying:
"忠以血  叛以血"
"Blood in, blood out."
他们找来这些九岁十岁的小男孩
They'd find these little boys, nine, 10 years old,
让他们行凶杀人  以此将他们收入帮派
and they'd make them murder people to bond them to the gang,
以血献忠
blood in.
而这些男孩陷得如此之深  全然不知
And these boys, they'd go so deep, they'd have no idea
他们只是马前卒子  随时会被牺牲掉
that they were grunts, that they were expendable.
而如果他们胆敢抗命
And if they disobeyed,
或者试图脱离帮派
or tried to leave the gang...
以血惩叛
...blood out.
鬼知道x宏正在R层干什么勾当
Hatake's down on Level R, doing God knows what.
你真以为他让你负责是信任你
You think he left you in charge because he trusts you,
还是他想转移你的注意力
or because he's trying to distract you?
我需要你立马滚出这间办公室
You need to get out of this office.
现在就滚
Now.
双螺旋
求你开门吧  我们有吃的
Please. We have food.
数量很多  足够大家分了
There's plenty here. We can all share.
你被感染了吧
Are you sick?
-快滚远点  -你这是浪费时间
- Get the hell away from here! - This is a waste of time.
我们不能就这么站在走廊上
We should get out of the hallway.
我们得把这层的人组织起来
We have to organize the people down here.
这样活下去的机会才更大些
It's a better chance of survival.
能说说你不想回那间房的真正原因吗
Can we talk about the reason you don't want to go back?
-是什么  -因为墙上的姓名缩写
- What's that? - The initials on the wall.
-你的姓名缩写  -那不是我的姓名缩写
- Your initials. - They weren't my initials.
我从未来过这
I've never been here before.
可你的笔迹又怎么解释
So how do you explain that it was your handwriting?
被感染的征状之一就是出现幻觉
Hallucinations are one of the symptoms of the infection.
得了吧  我也看见那些字了
Nice try, but I saw them too.
会不会是你小时候来过这
Is it possible you were here when you were younger?
是啊  肯定是我忘记了
Yeah, I must have forgotten
我全家来这冰天雪地的北极圈度假过好几次
all those family vacations to the Arctic Circle.
我在蒙大拿州长大
I grew up in Montana.
小时候去过最远的地方就是波兹曼市
The most exotic place I ever went as a kid was Bozeman.
蒙大拿州地广人稀
波兹曼市为该州第四大城市  人口约四万人
茱尔斯
Jules.
你刚才叫我什么
What did you just call me?
如果你不喜欢的话  我就不那么叫
If you don't like it, I won't call you that.
也不是  只是...
No, it's just, uh...
只有我妈和艾伦这么叫我
Alan and my mother were the only ones who ever called me that.
求你...救救我
Help... please.
朵琳
Doreen!
天哪  撑住
Jesus. Hold on.
我的天哪
Oh, my god.
发生了什么
What happened?
-她被带菌者袭击了吗  -是老鼠
- Was... was she attacked by a vector? - It was the rats.
老鼠吗  老鼠这么会跑出来
The rats? How did they get out?
笼子被掀翻到她的身上
The cages were turned over on her.
可能她突发心脏病什么的
Maybe she had some kind of heart attack,
抓住了架子  倒下的时候掀翻了
grabbed the rack, and it went down when she did.
或者是有人推翻的
Or someone pushed it.
你认为有人故意为之吗
You think someone did this on purpose?
外勤人员每年都有体检
We have annual physicals for field duty.
如果朵琳真有心脏不适的征兆
If Doreen had any hint of cardiac distress,
她不会获准参与这次调查的
she'd never have been permitted to join this investigation.
海拔对体能影响有个体差异
Altitude changes effect individuals differently.
而且昨天二氧化碳净化器关闭了四个小时
And the CO2 scrubbers were turned off for four hours yesterday.
在我看来她身体状况很好
Seems like she was in pretty good health to me.
法拉格特博士  你知道
Do you know how many murders
这座基地发生过几起谋杀吗
have occurred at this base, Dr. Farragut?
从未有过
Zero.
但意外情况却经常发生
Accidents, however, happen all the time-
这他妈根本不是意外
This wasn't a goddamn accident!
-除非有证据证明是人为  -证据
- Until the evidence suggests otherwise-- - Evidence?
我们身处荒芜  与世隔绝
We're in the ass-end of nowhere, cut off from the world.
我的得力助手困在R层  生命堪忧
My best doctor is trapped and dying somewhere below us,
而我在疾控中心的最好朋友
and my closest friend from the CDC
很有可能刚被人谋杀
has very likely just been murdered.
这地方...简直就是个随时引爆的定时炸弹
This place is a... it's a time bomb waiting to go off,
而我们还在假装
and we're pretending this
企盼着这些垃圾会救我们一命
these goddamn things are gonna save us!
我想目前我们最大的麻烦不是病毒
Right now, I'm thinking the virus is not our biggest problem.
-我马上去查看监控录像  -不行
- I'll review the surveillance footage immediately. - No.
你不能一个人去  莎拉  去找杜尚博士
Not alone you won't. Sarah, find Dr. Duchamp.
让他马上用索迪拉进行动物试验
Tell him to start the animal trials with the SODRA immediately.
一旦出现并发症马上通知我
You find me if there are complications.
我告诉他们只要把氧气净化器打开
I said we would bring food and water
我就给他们送食物和水
if they turned the oxygen scrubbers back on,
但他们却袭击我
but they attacked me.
出血减缓了  但伤口还是需要缝合
The bleeding is slowing, but you're gonna need stitches.
我们得送你去用作分诊室的那间实验室
We need to get you to that lab we set up for triage.
那可是在基地的另一侧啊
That's on the other side of the facility.
我们没办法一路把他拖去那儿
We can't drag him all the way over there.
-为什么不能  -你在跟谁讲话
- Why not? - What was that?
x博士  这是杰伊  杰伊  这是x博士
Dr. Hatake, this is Jaye. Jaye, Hatake.
-杰伊  -别装做不认识我
- Jaye? - Don't pretend like you don't know who I am.
我也不想假装帮你
And I won't pretend I'm gonna help you
当初可是你把我们锁在这儿自生自灭的
after you locked us down here to fend for ourselves.
-确实是你封锁了这儿  -我别无他法
- You did seal us up down here. - I had no choice.
我们不能让传染病扩散
We could not allow the infection to spread.
我们得送你去那间实验室  把伤口缝起来
We need to get you to that lab, close up this wound.
太危险了  我们根本到不了那
It's too dangerous. We'd never make it.
有别的方法穿越这一楼层吗
Is there any other way across this level?
有个维修隧道
An access tunnel.
一直通向基地的另一边
It goes all the way to the other side of the base.
但我不会求你...用你的生命冒险救我的
But I would not ask you to... risk your life for mine.
你不需要求我
You don't have to ask.
你需要帮助  我就会帮你
You need my help, I'm gonna help you.
我们来尝试确定事件发生的时间
Let's narrow the window of incident.
你最后一次见到博伊尔博士是什么时候
When was the last time you saw Dr. Boyle?
大概是昨天早上9点
About 9am yesterday morning.
她已经有十小时没和你汇报了吗
In 10 hours, you didn't check in with her?
当时我在弟弟身上进行索迪拉的实验
I was running SODRA trials on my brother.
并且她能力足以自理  不需要时时向我汇报
And she was capable; she didn't need to check in.
是啊  "不受干扰的研究"
Right. "Uninterrupted research."
怎么回事
What happened there?
文件损坏了
The file's been corrupted.
我查查备份
I'll check the backup.
不可能啊  备份也被删除了
That's impossible. The backups have been deleted too.
唯一有权限这么做的只有我和
The only ones with access are me and--
x宏  恰巧消失了的那位
Hatake, who's conveniently disappeared.
我们俩都和这事无关
Neither of us have anything to do with this.
我会查出博伊尔博士身上到底发生了什么
I will find out what happened to Dr. Boyle.
我会通过验尸来自己找出答案
I'll find out myself through an autopsy.
杜尚博士
Dr. Duchamp?
我是拜耶塞罗少校
I'm Major Balleseros.
又要新一轮的检查吗
Is this another check-in?
我没有受感染的迹象
I'm showing no signs of infection.
不是
No.
我是来找威特博士的
I'm looking for a Dr. Hvit.
这名字我有段时间没听过了
That's a name I haven't heard in a while.
我查看研究资料的时候
I was going through the research files,
发现你们曾合作过一篇论文
and I saw that you two did a paper together.
那是很多年前的事了
That was many years ago.
-你是说他现在离开基地了吗  -不  他在
- So he's no longer on the base? - Oh, no, he is.
只是没人再见过他了
It's just, no one ever sees him anymore.
我听说他得了一种少见的免疫缺陷症
I hear he developed a rare immune deficiency.
不能再轻易和别人接触
He can no longer interact with people.
他的存在几乎成了这里的一个传说
He's become somewhat of an urban legend.
据说他现在住在白色房间里
I heard rumors he's in the white room.
白色房间在哪里呢
Where can I find that?
我们都在白色房间里
We are all in the white room.
不好意思  我想和少校谈谈
Excuse me. I need to speak with the major.
是不是你杀了疾控中心的兽医
Did you kill the CDC vet?
我好像不记得了
You'd think I'd remember that.
是你干的吗
Did you do it?
监控录像怎么说的
What did the surveillance video show?
x宏知道吗
Did Hatake know?
问他去  他不是什么都和你说吗
Ask him. He tells you everything, right?
法拉格特博士正在进行尸检
Dr. Farragut is running an autopsy as we speak.
你最好祈祷自己没留下什么蛛丝马迹
You better hope you covered your tracks.
行动代码852  D层  血液科
Code 852, level D, Hematology.
请注意  行动代码852  D层  血液科
Attention: Code 852, level D, Hematology.
范・艾根医生
Dr. Van Eigem?
糟了
Shit.
范・艾根医生  你在干什么
Dr. Van Eigem, what are you doing?
我在为托尼跳舞
I'm dancing for Tony.
可托尼不在这里
Tony isn't here.
他当然在这
Of course he is.
怎么了
What's wrong?
发生了什么
What happened?
我无法控制自己
I couldn't stop myself.
我要变成那些怪物了  对吗
I'm gonna turn into one of those things, aren't I?
我们先回屋里去吧
We need to get you back to the room.
来吧
Come on.
还有多远
How long is it?
四十米
Forty meters.
我建议咱们绕路走
I vote we go around.
谁知道里边等着我们的是什么
Who knows what's waiting for us in there?
我们没时间了
We don't have time.
好吧  我们走
All right, let's go.
我们踩的这些是什么
What are we stepping on?
看起来像是玻璃
Looks like glass.
有人把灯打破了  估计是想躲起来
Someone busted the lights out. Probably trying to hide.
或是  制造陷阱
Or... Setting a trap.
找到什么了吗
Found anything?
她死于一种栓塞
She died of an embolism.
扫描显示她的左脑有一处瘀伤
A scan revealed bruising in the left hemisphere of her brain,
与气泡一致
Consistent with an air bubble.
这么说是自然死亡
So it was natural causes.
可为什么有人要故意删除监视录像
Why would anyone have erased the security footage?
-你昨天见过朵琳吗  -碰到了一面
- Did you see Doreen yesterday? - Just in passing.
关于研究她有提起过什么吗
Did she say anything? About her research?
有什么突破吗
Any breakthrough she might've had?
没  她什么都没说
No, she didn't.
我对朵琳了解的不多
I didn't know Doreen too well,
不过她看上去是一个很好的队友
but she seemed like a good person to have on your team.
我认识她15年了  她不应该遭受这些的
I knew her 15 years. She didn't deserve this.
她有家人吗
Did she have any family?
第三段婚姻里有一个儿子
A son from her third marriage.
把那瓶酒精递给我
Hand me that bottle of alcohol.
-那是什么  -针孔
- What is that? - Puncture mark
注射器针孔
from a needle.
吗啡
我不想变得像那些怪物一样
I don't want to become one of those things.
我明白
I know.
阻止我
Don't let me.
你知道我是什么意思
You know what I'm asking.
你生病了
You're sick.
你只是吃了药在胡言乱语
It's the drugs talking.
在我看见托尼的幻觉之前
I was on my way to the drug stockroom
我已经准备
before...
去药库自行了断
I saw Tony.
可我自己下不了手
I can't do it myself.
求求你了
Please.
求求你
莎拉
Sarah?
莎拉  我是艾伦
Sarah, it's Alan.
-你在里面没事吧  -马上来
- You all right in there? - One minute.
抱歉  我刚才在换衣服
Hey. Sorry, I was just getting changed.
有什么事吗
What's going on?
尸检证明  朵琳是被谋杀的
Doreen was murdered. The autopsy proves it.
-用什么方法  -有人给她打了空气针
- How? - Somebody used a syringe
使她看起来像得了栓塞
to make it look like she had an embolism.
他们手法很娴熟
They knew what they were doing.
我们一定要多加小心
We need to be careful.
-你还好吗  -是的  我
- Are you ok? - Yeah. I'm...
我
I, uh...
我  我真不知道这里到底怎么了
I... I just don't know what's going on here.
沃克被感染了  朵琳死了
I mean... Walker's sick. Doreen's dead.
现在你又告诉我她是被谋杀的
You're telling me that somebody murdered her. I...
我们真的能活着走出这里吗
Are we even gonna make it out of this place alive?
会没事的
It's ok.
我不会让你有事的
I won't let anything happen to you.
好吗
All right?
-莎拉  我...  -对不起
- Sarah, I... - I'm sorry.
我  我不该吻你
I... I shouldn't have done that.
你嗑药了吗
Are you high?
你说什么
What?
我几乎看不到你的瞳孔了  你吃了什么药
I can barely see your pupils. What are you on?
我有点偏头痛  所以吃了点止疼药
I had a migraine, so I took something.
-什么止疼药  -加巴喷丁
- What? - Gabapentin.
别骗我  除非你把整瓶都吃了
You're lying, unless you took the whole bottle.
-艾伦  等等  你听我解释  -不
- Alan, wait. I... I can expl-- - No,
这种事情没有借口  从来都没有
there's no excuse for this, ever!
这里的人们命悬一线
People's lives are at stake;
他们都指望着我们呢
they're depending on us!
你这样的状态根本没法工作
You're of no use to me like this!
但是  我
But I--
别说了  你去睡一觉清醒一下
No, you go sleep this off.
我们回头再处理这件事
We'll deal with it later.
对不起  我们能歇一会吗
I'm sorry... Can we take a moment?
不  我们不能停
No, not really.
让我检查一下你的伤口
Let me take a look at your wound.
伤口需要压力止血  得把它绑起来
We need to tie something around you for more pressure.
给  用这个
Here, use this.
快一点
And hurry up.
把你的身体往前倾
Ok, I'm gonna need you to lean forward for me.
什么声音
What was that?
天啊  是老鼠
Oh, my god. Rats!
-它们从哪来的  -更重要的是
- Where are they coming from? - The more important question is:
它们在躲避什么
What are they running from?
快跑
Run!
这里有门
The door!
到门这里来
Get to the door!
杰伊呢  她刚刚还在我身后
Where's Jaye? She was right behind me.
-我没看到她  -我们得回去
- I didn't see her. - We have to go back!
太迟了
It's too late.
我们到底在找什么
What exactly are we looking for?
朵琳遗留下来的任何研究成果
Anything salvageable of Doreen's research.
还有她死前发现的线索
Any clue as to what she might have discovered before she...
你是说有人想掩盖真相
You think there's some kind of cover-up?
除了这个原因还有什么
Why else would anyone kill her?
转基因实验室
The transgenics lab.
那里怎么了
What about it?
就是发现猴子的实验室
That lab where they found the monkey.
她还没来得及采集样本
It was totally cleaned out before she had a chance
那里就被彻底清理了
to gather any samples.
-她没告诉你吗  -没有
- She didn't tell you? - No, she didn't.
从上到下消毒了个遍
Sanitized from top to bottom.
我想肯定是x宏下的命令
Figured Hatake must have ordered it.
如果那里被清理了
If it was cleaned out,
她又是从哪里拿到猴子标本做分析的呢
where'd she get the monkey sample she was analyzing?
也许这里的某位科学家在帮助她
Maybe some of the scientists from here were helping her.
这么说起来  她确实提到过一个名字
Come to think of it, she did mention a name:
威特博士
Dr... Hvit?
她从没跟我提过这个名字
She never mentioned him to me.
那就怪了  朵琳说她曾找过他
That's strange. She said she spoke to him.
还说他似乎知道所有问题的答案
Said he seemed to have all the answers.
我去找找这个威特博士
Well, I will find this Dr. Hvit and...
看看他能否对现在的情况作出解释
see if he can shed any light on the situation.
我不认识什么威特博士
I don't know a Dr. Hvit.
朵琳和他谈过
Doreen talked to him.
她和他谈过  朵琳亲口告诉你的
She... talked to him? Doreen told you that?
不是  拜耶塞罗少校说的
No, Major Balleseros did.
拜耶塞罗少校还告诉我
Major Balleseros also told me
他们发现转基因实验室被清理了
how they found the transgenics lab cleaned out.
但我想你对此也一定毫不知情吧
But I guess you know nothing about that either.
那只是常规的卫生消毒程序
That was a routine sanitization procedure.
胡说  那是为了掩盖真相
Bullshit, that was a cover-up.
我们既然请你们来研究病毒
Why would we want to cover up a virus
为什么还要隐瞒它的真相
that we need you to cure?
你如此固执地认为我们是坏人
You're so focused on seeing us as the bad guys,
却忽略了自己身边的人
you don't see what's right in front of you.
你对拜耶塞罗少校又有多少了解
How well do you know Major Balleseros?
我五天前才认识他
I met him five days ago.
我也是你五天前认识的  你就只信任他
Same day You met me. And you trust him?
凭什么  就因为他穿军装吗
Why? Because he's wearing a uniform?
你背上的伤疤是怎么回事
How did you get those scars on your back?
多年前发生了一场大火
There was a fire, years ago,
在我京都的家
at my home in Kyoto.
我回去时整个房子都已经陷入火海
The entire house was in flames when I arrived.
可我的女儿...
My daughter...
还在里面
was still inside.
我试图去救她
I tried to save her.
她是个什么样的人
What was she like?
你的女儿
Your daughter.
她很聪明
She was smart.
对世界充满好奇
Curious about the world.
你...
You...
你很像她
... you remind me of her.
外面有一阵子没有动静了
I haven't heard anything outside for a while.
我们得赶紧去分诊实验室
We should try and get to the triage lab.
你为什么改变心意了
What made you change your mind?
我知道深陷痛苦的滋味
I know what it's like to be in pain.
那种痛苦...
The kind of pain that you...
你会不计一切代价让它消失
you would do anything to make it stop.
虽然我从没考虑过自杀
And I've never considered ending it, but...
但我们都想自己选择什么时候
... don't we all wish that we could control when we go
什么方式死去
and how we go?
你真的想好了吗
Are you sure?
真的要这么做
Are you really sure?
是的
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
找到了
Got something.
这是塞姆汀
This is Semtex.
塑胶炸药
Plastic explosive.
是拜耶塞罗破坏了卫星信号
Balleseros sabotaged the satellite.
因为他不需要用卫星联系
Because he didn't need it to call out.
从到这以来他一直在向谁报告
He's been sending messages to someone since we got here.
朵琳的研究也在里面
Doreen's research is on here too.
他杀了朵琳
He killed her.
最后一条消息  "找到白色房间的
Here's the last transmission: "Found Dr. Hvit
威特博士  15时撤离"
in the white room. Evac 1500..."
白色房间  那到底是什么意思
White room? What is the damn white room?
杜尚  白色房间在哪
Duchamp. Where is the white room?
我们都在白色房间里
We are all in the white room.
这是基地科学家之间的玩笑
It's an inside joke among the base scientists.
我们在北极圈里  白色房间就是北极圈
We're in the arctic; it's all the white room.
他们在基地外面
They're outside.
埃马・威特
看来你收到我的消息了
I see you got my message.
多谢了  要不是你我还真找不到威特
Thanks. I would have never found Hvit without you.
x博士  保持清醒  就快到了
Dr. Hatake, stay with me now. We're almost there.
请你
Please...
叫我宏就行
call me Hiroshi.
快起来
Come on.
你俩真慢啊
Took you guys long enough.
这种暴风雪天气没人会出去
Nobody goes outside in a whiteout,
两英尺外就是白雪茫茫
you won't even be able to see more than two feet in any direction.
不是有导绳吗
There are guide ropes to follow, right?
不是那么容易的
It's not that simple.
零下60度的天气超乎你想象
You've never experienced anything like this. Minus 60,
而风雪更会使寒意加倍
and the wind chill doubles that.
如果你一定要去  你必须跟着大楼周围的导绳
Fine, if you're doing this, you stay on the guidelines
直到你找到出去的那条
around the building until you get to the line going out.
到那之前千万别解开绳子
Do not unclip until you get there,
要不然你就会...彻底消失
or else you'll just... disappear.
我推开了特蕾西然后一路狂奔
I managed to get Tracey off me, and then I ran.
可能太黑了  她看不见我
It was too dark for her to see me, I guess.
我一头钻进最近的一个实验室
I ducked into the first lab I could find,
-然后就来这了  -我当时真以为你必死无疑
- and then I came here. - I thought for sure you were dead.
我也是这么想的
That makes two of us.
杰伊  我
Jaye, I --
别再为没等我而自责了
Don't beat yourself up for closing that door.
你以为我就在你身后
You thought I was right behind you.
看起来我们搭档不错
Looks like we make a pretty good team.
那可不是吗
We do, don't we?
刚好  他快醒了
Good. He's waking up.
看他还有什么关于他女儿的谎言要告诉我们的
Maybe he can tell us more lies about his daughter.
你怎么知道...
How did you...
你当时不在那
You weren't there.
你很像她
You remind me of her.
我不在哪
I wasn't where?
x宏说起女儿时你并不在场
You weren't there when Hatake told that story.
那不是我的姓名缩写  我从未来过这
They weren't my initials. I've never been here before.
可你的笔迹又怎么解释
So how do you explain that it was your handwriting?
幻觉是感染症状的一种
Hallucinations are one of the symptoms of the infection.
不会的
No.
不可能的  我看见你做了许多事情
That's not possible. I watched you do things.
-你需要把伤口绑起来  -给
- ... Tie something around you for more pressure. - Here.
-用这个  -快点
- Use this. - Hurry up.
是你自己  茱尔斯
It was you, Jules.
全是你自己想象出来的
It was all you.
可你救了我这么多次
All those times you saved me.
是你救了自己
You saved yourself.
我要往回走  把绳扣换一下位置
Hey! Coming through! Switch clamps!
你这个混帐  是你杀了她
You killed her, you bastard!
你根本不清楚发生了什么
You have no idea what's going on here!
朵琳的死只是附带伤害
Doreen was collateral damage-- ugh!
很高兴认识你  博士
Nice knowing you, doc.
拜耶塞罗从这进来了吗
Did Balleseros come back through here?
我没见到他
I haven't seen him.
他在雪地里袭击了我
He attacked me on the ice.
我们得召集一队安保人员去追捕他
We need to get a security team together and go after him.
这不是你该做的事情
You don't need to do anything.
你一开始就不该去雪地里的
You should have never been on that ice in the first place.
是他杀死了朵琳
He killed... Doreen.
看起来他差点把你也杀了
Well, it looks like he almost killed you too.
这是我对你那条消息的回复
I've got a reply for that message!
别动
Hold still.
清洁小队请到C层食品储存室
Cleanup requested. Pantry, level c.
莎拉  知道我为什么选你参加这次行动吗
You know why I picked you for my team, Sarah?
因为我是最合适的人选
Because I was the best candidate.
因为你充满斗志
Because you were driven.
我还记得你第一天走进我办公室
I remember the first day you walked into my office, and...
当时我就心想
I thought to myself,
"这个女孩  她一定在睡梦中
"That girl, even when she sleeps,
都想着要做得比别人好"
She tries to do it better than anyone else."
工作时  我们心无旁骛
Nothing distracts us from the work.
但过于专注一件事情就会这样
But that's the problem with laser focus,
我们看事情的角度会与别人不同
with our particular way of looking at the world.
我们只能看见眼前发生的事  那些
We only see the thing in front of us, the thing...
我们所关注的
under the microscope,
而忽略了身边周围的一切
And we miss what's happening all around.
这就是为什么我的婚姻会悲剧收场
That's why my marriage fell apart.
这就是为什么我弟弟
That's why my brother...
会选择来到这个地方
was up here in this... place.
我不能一直犯同样的错误
I can't keep making the same mistakes.
很抱歉之前我没有听你解释
I'm sorry I didn't listen to you before, but...
现在我想听听
I'm listening now.
我经常会偏头痛
I get these migraines.
自大学起就这样  一旦发作起来
I've had them since college, and when they come on,
我无法思考
I... I can't think,
也无法工作  什么都干不了
I can't... work, I can't do anything.
所以我从药品储藏室拿了些吗啡
I took some morphine from the drug stockroom.
想着少量注射一点缓解症状
I thought if I just had a little bit to even me out,
这样我就可以回去工作了
I'd be able to go back to work.
真的很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我之前绝没有干过这样的事  我保证
I've never done anything like this, I swear.
没关系
It's ok.
在这里  我们都迷失了一部分的自己
We've all lost ourselves... a little bit here.
再一次  我的队伍离析分崩
My team... has fallen apart. Again.
上一次  我失去了你和茱尔斯
I lost you and Jules last time.
这一次  我失去了朵琳
Now I've lost Doreen.
我不知道该怎么做了
I don't know what to do.
这向来是你最拿手的
You were always good at that part.
就算在母亲最糟糕的那段日子
Even with mom, on her worst days,
你仍心存希望
you had hope.
我需要你给我一点希望
I need a little of your hope...
就是现在  彼得
right now, Peter.
神经活动
《双螺旋》前情提要
Previously on Helix...
你什么时候知道自己长了肿瘤的
How long have you known about your tumor?
你嗑药了吗
Are you high?
我有点偏头痛  所以吃了...
I had a migraine, so I took--
别骗我  除非你把整瓶都吃了
You're lying, unless you took the whole bottle.
我不想变得像那些怪物一样
I don't want to become one of those things.
你知道我是什么意思
You know what I'm asking.
谢谢
Thank you.
-他还有多久时间  -好好把握这最后的机会吧
- How long does he have? - Take this time and make the most of it.
被感染的征状之一就是出现幻觉
Hallucinations are one of the symptoms of the infection.
这他妈根本不是意外
This wasn't a goddamn accident!
这是我对你那条消息的回复
I've got a reply for that message!
第六日
姓名  朵琳・博伊尔博士
对不起  朵琳
I'm sorry, Doreen.
我们并肩对抗了
We fought through...
七次疾病爆发
seven outbreaks together,
我一直以为是我在引领着你
and I always thought I was the one leading you.
而事实上是你一直在鞭策着我进步
It turns out you were the one pushing me.
找到拜耶塞罗了吗
Have you located Balleseros?
还没有
No, not yet.
朵琳遇害不是巧合
Doreen's murder was no coincidence.
-我不懂你什么意思  -你懂得很
- I'm not sure I follow. - Oh, you follow just fine.
不过我还是把话说明白吧
But let me spell it out for you anyway:
无论拜耶塞罗是什么阴谋
whatever Balleseros is up to,
都绝对跟这个病毒有关
it has everything to do with this virus.
你要装作毫不知情的样子  你随意
If you want to pretend you don't know that, that's fine.
但我要找到他
But I want him found.
这是谁
Who's this?
瑞伊・范・艾根医生
Dr. Rae Van Eigem.
R层封锁后  我在B层找到了她
I found her on Level B after Level R was sealed off.
她在昏迷之前就已经死亡了
She died before the coma could set in.
你在B层找到的她
You found her on Level B?
怎么不通知我
Why wasn't I notified?
时间紧迫
There wasn't time.
我将她隔离  并尽我所能地帮助了她
I isolated her and tended to her needs as best I could.
这是纳尔维克B
This is NARVIK-B.
她应该是带菌者  而不是尸体
She should be a vector, not a corpse.
她怎么死的  莎拉
How did she die, Sarah?
吗啡过量
Morphine - overdose.
谁给的药
Who administered the dose?
我做了我认为正确的事
I did what I thought was right.
你那套不杀感染者理论也不过如此嘛  博士
So much for not killing the infected, right, Doc?
我要去R层
I am going down to Level R
带沃克博士回来
and I am bringing back Dr. Walker.
你最好跟你上司知会一声
You might want to inform your boss.
他在处理紧急事件
He's dealing with an emergency situation.
还有什么事能比这场病毒爆发
What emergency situation could possibly be more pressing
更紧急
than this outbreak?
他办完事就会回来
He'll be back when he's finished,
谁都不许去R层
and no one is going down to Level R
出入都不行  包括沃克博士
no one in, no one out. That includes Dr. Walker.
你要向我开枪吗  丹尼尔
You're gonna shoot me, Daniel?
是想这么做吗
Is that really your play here?
你得回实验室
You need to get back to your lab.
我不为你做事
I don't work for you!
你到底知不知道现在什么情况
Do you have any idea what this thing is?
这病毒对人有什么影响
What it's doing to people?
我很清楚  他们病了
I'm aware, yes. People are sick.
不是病了  是快死了
Not sick; they're dying!
你弟有好转的迹象
Your brother is showing signs of improvement.
我弟几乎没有脑部活动
My brother barely has brain activity,
全拜x宏所赐
no thanks to Hatake!
x博士和我跟你们目的一致
Dr. Hatake and I both want the same thing you do.
你手里的枪可不是这么说的  孩子
That gun in your hand is telling a different story, son!
你俩能消停会儿吗
Will you two cut it out?
回去干你的活
Get... back to work.
现在就去
Now.
我来处理她
I'll take care of her.
彼得
Peter.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我是来帮你的
I came to help you.
帮我什么  你...
Help me with what? You...
你不是真实存在的
You're not real.
感觉很真实啊
Feels pretty real.
快走开
Go away.
我还在呢
Still here.
你让我留下肯定是有原因的
You must want me to stay for a reason.
什么原因
Like what?
她是谁
Who is she?
你好
Hello?
《双螺旋》第一季第六集
-那现在怎么办  -我要下去找茱莉亚
- So, what now? - I'm going down to get Julia.
-等等  那...  -她写过一本书
- Wait, what about-- - She wrote the book
是关于病毒拼接和RNA结合蛋白的
on viral splicing and RNA binding proteins.
我需要...我们需要她
I need her - we need her -
来一起攻克这个难题
to fight this thing.
艾伦  我们不清楚她现在的病情
Alan, we don't know how sick she is.
我们甚至都不清楚她能否正常工作
We don't even know if she can work.
我们是不知道  但是朵琳死了
No, we don't. But Doreen is dead,
拜耶塞罗失踪了
Balleseros has gone missing,
所以我们又回到原点了
and we are back to square one.
茱尔斯是我们最大的希望
Jules is our best hope.
-也是唯一的希望  -那我们怎么去R层
- She's our only hope. - How do we get down to Level R?
楼梯井被封了  电梯又被丹尼尔控制着
The stairwells are sealed shut and Daniel controls the elevator.
我得再想办法
I'll have to improvise.
对了  给你这个  治你的偏头痛的
By the way, these are for you, for your migraines.
加巴喷丁  你在哪里...
Gabapentin. Where did you--
是苏勒玛尼博士用来治疗强迫症的  应该管用
Dr. Sulemani used them for OCD. They should work.
不要再用吗啡了
No more morphine.
知道了吗  我需要你保持敏锐机警
All right? I need you sharp.
现在就剩下我们俩了  如果我们不同心协力
You and I are all we have left. If we don't have each other,
如果我们不互相帮助  我们就一无所有了
if we don't back each other up, we have nothing.
当然了  还有...
Absolutely. And...
谢谢你
thank you.
自助餐厅开放
Cafeteria is now open.
自助餐厅...
Cafeteria is now--
天哪
Oh, my God.
怎么了
What is it?
-你的伤口  -感染了吗
- Your wound. - Infection?
不是  伤口愈合快得不可思议
No, it's... it's healing remarkably fast.
肯定是因为我基因好
Must have good genes.
肯定是的
Must have.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
你为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
告诉你什么
Tell you what?
我出现幻觉了  杰伊不是真的
That I was hallucinating! That Jaye wasn't real.
你为什么要让我继续相信她的存在
Why did you let me go on believing she was here?
你很喜欢看别人受罪煎熬吗
Do you enjoy watching people suffer?
我跟你一样  也是名医生
I am a doctor first, like you.
我的责任是救死扶伤
My job is to save people.
用撒谎救死扶伤吗
By lying to them?
我没告诉你是因为没这个必要
I didn't tell you, because I didn't need to.
你当时神志不清
You were disoriented,
跟杰伊说话好像对你有所帮助
and speaking to Jaye seemed to be helping.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你说得对
You're right.
救命啊
Help!
救命
不要
No!
我们救不了所有人
Not everyone can be saved.
沃克博士
Dr. Walker?
茱莉亚
Julia!
Julia.
我很久没做过铝热剂了
It's been a long time since I've made thermite.
上次还是高中毕业恶作剧的时候
It was in high school - senior prank.
那次不太成功
It didn't go very well.
这根本不是隔离
This was no quarantine;
更像是"彻底封锁自生自灭"
it was a "seal and forget."
里面很暗  我看不太清楚
Dark in there. I can't see much.
他们可能都躲在实验室里
They're probably all huddled in the labs.
这样肯定找不着她
We'll never find her like this.
我们得进去看看
We have to go inside.
我好像在走廊尽头看到了什么
I think I see something at the end of the hall.
快跑
Go!
-让我看看  -艾伦  不用  我没事
- Come here. - Alan, stop. I'm fine.
如果有任何擦伤或者创口之类的
If there's an abrasion or a cut or anything of the kind--
-真没事  -我们得确保无虞  你明白的
- I'm fine. - We have to make sure. You know that.
我真没想到会有这么多带菌者
I had no idea there'd be so many of them.
让你身处这么大的危险  我真是昏头了
I ought to have my head examined for putting you at risk.
是我自愿跟着你下来的
I chose to go down there with you.
听着  先是朵琳  现在又是茱尔斯
Listen, first Doreen, then Jules.
我可不能再失去你了  莎拉
I can't lose you too, Sarah.
那茱莉亚怎么办
What are we gonna do about Julia?
为了找到她  我们得先对付那些...
To get to her, we have to go through those...
-那些怪物  -我是想说"那些患者"
- Those monsters? - I was going to say "those patients."
绝望的患者  我们要想帮助茱尔斯
desperately sick patients. If we want to get to Jules,
我们得先治好他们
we'll have to treat them first.
要是治不好呢
What if we can't?
那上头就会连同我们一起
Then they'll bury this base...
将这基地彻底摧毁
with us in it.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
你昏过去了
You passed out.
别担心  茱莉亚
Don't worry, Julia.
很快你就会没事了
We'll have you back on your feet in no time.
你照我眼睛干什么  我看不清了
What are you doing to my eyes? I can't see.
那是什么
What is that?
我要给你打镇静剂
I'm giving you a sedative.
你需要休息
You should sleep.
我不想睡过去
I don't want to sleep.
别说话
Shh.
你会好起来的
You're going to be OK.
准许进入
Access granted.
怎么回事
Aw! What the hell?
-你是谁  -我还想问你呢
- Who are you? - I could ask you the same thing.
我是阿娜娜
I'm Anana.
阿娜娜
Anana?
我这是在哪
Where am I?
你在我家里
You're in my home.
这手铐有必要吗
Are these really necessary?
鬼知道你是谁啊
Don't know you from Adam.
这么说  我也该把你铐起来
In that case, maybe I should cuff you too.
我叫塞尔西奥
I'm Sergio.
看来我脸上这一拳是拜你所赐了
I assume I have you to thank for punching me in the face?
谁叫你一个劲地反抗我
You kept trying to fight me.
除此以外感觉怎么样  赛尔西奥
How are you feeling otherwise,Sergio?
糟糕透顶
Like hell.
那也比被扔在雪地里
That's better than expected for a guy
等着被冻死要强得多
who was left for dead on the ice.
-这绿乎乎的是什么玩意  -这是海藻药膏
- What is this green shit? - It's a seaweed pack.
这附近又找不着什么神医  所以将就着吧
We're not exactly near the Mayo Clinic, so relax.
你是个警察
You're the law?
汤拉尔定居点周围四百英里以内唯一的治安官
Only peace officer within 400 miles of Tonrar settlement.
-汤拉尔是什么  -意思是"幽灵"
- Tonrar? - Means "Ghost."
其实没有名字说的这么吓人
Sounds scarier than what it is.
我们不会在一个地点停留太久
We don't stay in one place very long.
给  喝了这个  能让你暖和点
Here, drink this. It'll warm you up.
你手指头没冻掉真是运气好...
You're lucky to have all your fingers and--
你这是想干什么
What'd you have to do that for,huh?
我可是尽了地主之谊呢
I was trying to be hospitable.
-疼  -疼就对了  正好让你明白状况
- It hurts. - Good! Let that be our introduction.
你见鬼去吧
Bullshit!
-怎么着  你想拿我当人质吗  -看情况
- What am I, a hostage? - Depends.
局面会有多难看  全在你
This can be as dirty as you want it to be.
-你想要什么  -要你脑袋里的
- What do you want? - I want what's in here.
告诉我所有关于北极生物公司的事
Tell me what you know about Arctic Biosystems.
我什么都不知道
I don't know anything.
你想这么玩吗
That's how you want to play it?
那好  或许你就该是人质
All right, then maybe you are a hostage.
-真是荒唐  -如果你配合  那是最好
- This is ridiculous! - If you want to talk, great.
如果不  我可以把你带回基地
If not, I can always bring you back to the base
让想杀你的人完成他的使命
and let whoever tried to kill you finish off what they started.
莎拉  来看这个
Sarah...come have a look at this.
告诉你看到了什么
Tell me what you see.
病毒在侵害细胞  迅速繁殖
The virus is attacking the cell, multiplying rapidly.
再看看  仔细一点
Look again. Look more closely.
天哪
Oh, my god.
之前我居然没发现
I can't believe I didn't see it before.
你怎么能发现呢  我们根本没注意这方面
How could you have? We weren't looking for it.
他把病毒用作运载体
He's using the virus as a delivery mechanism.
问题是  病毒要运送的是什么
The question is: what's the virus bringing to the party?
原因又是什么
And why?
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
-法拉格特博士  -病毒里有什么
- Dr. Farragut. - What's in the virus?
-什么也没有  -我亲眼看到了
- Nothing. - I saw it with my own eyes.
你在基因序列中加入了什么
What did you splice into its genetic code?
我听不懂你在说什么
I don't know what you mean.
我知道你把病毒用作运载体
I know you're using the virus as a delivery mechanism.
告诉我  你是不是在折腾什么基因疗法
Now, what kind of gene therapy are you messing with?
你把我弟弟当成了小白鼠
You used my brother as a lab rat!
你搞砸了他的生活  茱莉亚的生活
You played with his life, with Julia's life,
还搞砸了R层那些可怜人的生活
with the rest of those poor people on Level R.
你把基地建在这儿就没人能监管你
You put this place here so you wouldn't be regulated,
然后你就可以扮演上帝来操控别人的生活
so you could play God with people's lives!
看看你带来的后果吧
Look where's it's gotten you!
告诉我真相
Tell me the truth.
是的  纳尔维克的确是个运载体
Yes...NARVIK is a... delivery system.
但法拉格特博士  这并不是阴谋
But there is no conspiracy, Dr. Farragut.
阴谋论只是你幻想出来的
That, I'm afraid, is in your head.
至于你弟弟...他也不是小白鼠
As far as your brother... he was no lab rat.
那这到底是怎么回事
What then? What is all this?
这是治疗绝症的一种方式
A way to treat what was once untreatable.
癌症
Cancer.
世卫组织定义五大绝症包括艾滋病  恶性肿瘤
白血病  类风湿  肌萎缩侧髓硬化症
化解全部"五大绝症"  试想一下
All five classifications. Think of it:
一种能够治愈当代最致命疾病的疗法
a cure for one of the deadliest diseases of our time.
病毒不用来害人而是是用来救人
Instead of causing harm, the virus delivers a cure.
真是妙点子
It's brilliant.
不幸的是  我们还没有完善它
Unfortunately, we haven't perfected it yet.
不是因为病毒
It wasn't the virus.
不是什么
What's not?
病毒让彼得生病  但并不会改变他
The virus made Peter sick but it didn't change him.
是病毒内的基因疗法改变了他
It was the gene therapy inside the virus.
你在纳尔维克-B菌株里加了什么才改变了他
What did you put into the NARVIK-B strain that changed him?
什么都没有
Nothing.
我们还没有在病毒中加入基因疗法
We hadn't introduced the gene therapy.
病毒里有其它东西
There is something inside this virus.
我会找出来的
And I will find it.
你得告诉我这到底怎么回事
I need you to tell me what's really going on here.
不关你的事
It doesn't concern you.
我唯一关心的就是你和基地的安全
Your safety and the safety of this base is my only concern.
如果我被蒙在鼓里就没法保护你了
I can't protect you if I'm in the dark.
你不在的时候发生了很多事情
A lot has happened while you were away.
拜耶塞罗找到了威特博士
Balleseros found Dr. Hvit. -
-什么  他是怎么...  -没事了
- What? How did he-- - it's not a problem.
我已经把他解决了
I took care of him. -
解决了他  你干了什么
Took care of him? How?
让他见识了一下冰镐的厉害
Introduced him to the business end of an ice axe.
并留他在雪地里自生自灭
Left him out on the ice.
你到底做了什么
What have you done?
是你说过他的存在对我们是一个威胁
You said yourself he was a threat.
所以我解决了他
I eliminated him.
你个蠢货  难道你不明白吗
You fool! Don't you see?!
一旦他没及时向上级报告
When he fails to check in,
那些人就会来了
they will come.
你需要吃点东西
You need to eat.
你的身体需要能量才能恢复
Your body is trying to heal.
说得好像你在乎似的
Like you care.
你死了对我没什么好处
You're no good to me dead.
好吧  那告诉我为什么我会在这里
Fine. I just want to know why I'm here.
所以我们又要开始兜圈子了吗
So, we're doing this dance again?
我说过  我想知道北极生物公司的事情
I told you why you're here. Arctic Biosystems.
我也说过了  我什么都不知道
I already told you, I don't know anything.
你知道的多到足以让别人对你下手
You knew enough that someone tried to shank your ass
杀人灭口了
and leave you for dead.
那是私人恩怨
That was a personal thing.
与基地无关
Had nothing to do with the base.
他们在做什么研究
What about the research they do?
还有那些孩子们
Tell me about the children.
什么孩子  你到底在胡说些什么
What children? What are you talking about?!
你不说拉倒  反正我们有的是时间
We can try this again later.
无论你怎么问  我的答案都是一样
Gonna be the same whenever you try it.
那就要看你能挨饿到什么程度了
That depends on how hungry you get!
这个年龄的孩子多可爱啊
They are so cute at that age.
这是哪  你为什么带我来这儿
What is this place? Why did you bring me here?
我只是来凑凑热闹而已
Hey, this is your dance party.
这可是你的舞会
I'm just along for the ride.
也许你应该问问她
Maybe you should ask her.
问什么
About what?
或许她正试图让你回想起一些事情
Maybe she's trying to get you to remember something.
一些你已经忘记的事情
Something you've forgotten.
已经忘记的事情我怎么还想得起来
How am I supposed to remember something I've forgotten?
有些事情只要你不想忘记
Nothing's ever really forgotten -
就永远不会忘
not if you don't want it to be.
去吧  去问问她
Go ahead, ask her.
你好
Hi.
我是茱莉亚
I'm Julia.
我也叫茱莉亚
That's my name too.
茱莉亚  这里是什么地方
What is this place, Julia?
这里是我家
This is my house.
你是说你住在这里吗
You mean you live here?
只有夏天才住这里
Only in the summer.
我和妈妈一起来的
I come here with my mommy.
我小时候也是和我母亲一起过夏天的
I used to spend the summer with my mommy too.
真的吗
You did?
嗯  在一个叫蒙大拿的地方
Mm-hmm. In a place called Montana.
你听说过这个地方吗
Have you ever heard of it?
我当然听过啦  傻瓜
Of course I have, silly.
我们现在不就在这儿吗
Where do you think we are right now?
没错  这是我长大的地方
Yes. This is where I grew up.
这里是蒙大拿
This is Montana,
我和母亲一起住过的地方
where I lived with my mother.
我回家了
I'm home.
接下来就是等吗
Now we wait.
只能如此了
Something like that.
怎么回事
What the hell?
你见过...
Have you ever...
它在做什么
What's it doing?
对低温产生了反应
Reacting to the cold.
极度低温
Extreme low temperatures.
会减慢病毒的效果
Slowing down the effects of the virus.
这说不定在人体上也行得通
Which means this might work on humans.
我们要给彼得降温
We need to get Peter on ice.
把他头抬一下
Lift his head. All right.
艾伦  那到底是什么东西
Alan, what was that thing?
不管是什么  低温能延缓它的效果
Whatever it was, the cold slowed it down.
我从没见过像这样的东西
I've never seen anything like that in my life.
莎拉  没人见过这样的东西
Sarah, no one has seen anything like that.
起作用了
It's working.
起作用了  但是还要继续给他降温
It's working, but we have to get him colder.
有个实验室  在G层  是研究冷沉淀的
There was a lab. Down on Level G, doing some kind of cryo work.
-谁的  -威克多・艾德里安博士
- Who? - Um... Dr. Victor Adrian.
你呆在这里  持续给他降温并准备转移
You stay here. Get him colder and get him prepped to move.
好
OK.
钥匙
Key.
休想
Don't.
明白了吗
Understand?
休想
Don't!
你明白了吗
Do you understand?!
-轻点  -想知道你为什么在这吗  看看
- Easy! - You want to know why you're here? Take a look.
-看什么  一群小孩吗  -失踪儿童
- What am I looking at? A bunch of kids? - Missing kids.
过去二十年来  北极生物公司周围
Thirty-one over the past two decades, all within
二百英里的范围内发生了31起失踪儿童事件
200 miles of Arctic Biosystems and your precious Dr. Hatake.
我不明白
I don't understand.
有人在偷我们的孩子
Someone's been stealing our children.
你根本不知道你保护的是什么人
You have no idea who you're protecting.
或者你知道
Or maybe you do.
你说呢
You tell me.
你再轻举妄动  我就崩了你
You try anything again, I will shoot you.
真有趣
That's funny.
我们慢慢地从身后接近她
We'll sneak up on her slow.
我就在你后边  别害怕
I'll be right behind you. Don't be afraid.
威克多・艾德里安吗
Victor Adrian?
我是疾控中心的艾伦・法拉格特
I'm Alan Farragut of the CDC.
滚蛋
Piss off.
-我正看着呢  -我需要你的帮助
- I was watching that. - I need your help.
我被关在这里都一个星期了
I've been stuck here for a week
如同困兽一般
like a caged animal.
你还指望我热情欢迎你吗
What do you expect me to do? Put out a welcome mat?
我知道这情况不怎么理想
I know the situation has been less than ideal.
这可真是年度最佳轻描淡写
Now that is the understatement of the year.
我这么做有什么好处
What do I get out of it?
-你说什么  -等价交换
- Excuse me? - Quid pro quo.
我帮了你这个忙  你也得回报我
I scratch your back, you scratch mine.
-你同意吗  -你想要什么
- Do we understand each other? - What is it you want?
首先  把守卫撤走
First, you're gonna call off the guards.
这六天来我连拉屎
I haven't taken a shit without
都得有人监视着
a chaperone for the last six days.
其次  我要在救援到来后
Second, I want to be first in line
第一个离开这鬼地方
out of this hell-hole when the cavalry arrive.
行  只要你帮我解决这事
All right, all right. You help me solve this,
我保证你排在第一个
and you will be first in line.
我向你保证
I guarantee it.
艾伦・法拉格特博士
Dr. Alan Farragut,
有何能为你效劳的
how may I be of assistance?
你是研究冷却系统的
You work with cooling systems?
冷沉淀疗法
Cryo-therapy?
变频浸没降温  我的最新成果
VFC Immersion. Latest and greatest.
真的有效吗
Does it work?
不如你亲自来跟我的小朋友们打个招呼如何
Why don't you say hello to some of my friends?
-给我住手  -你俩都为x宏效力
- Stop right there! - You both work for Hatake.
-是吗  -放开他
- Is that it?! - Let him go.
-就是他在基地要杀了我  -你说什么
- He tried to kill me back at the base! - What? When?
你想要x宏的信息  找他就行了
You want information about Hatake? Here's your man!
来啊  问他
Go ahead! Ask him!
你疯了吗  这是我弟弟
Are you out of your mind?! That's my brother!
-丹尼尔是你弟弟  -丹尼尔是谁
- Daniel is your brother? - Who's Daniel?
这是我弟弟图克
That's my brother Tulok!
能告诉我你为什么要袭击我弟弟吗
You want to tell me why you attacked my brother?
我只是...想逃跑
I was just... trying to escape.
这是我和弟弟们的照片
This is a picture of me and my brothers.
他们是双胞胎
Twins.
你刚见到的是图克
You met Tulok outside.
这个是米嘉
This is Miksa.
在我们还小时他就失踪了
He disappeared when we were kids.
当时他只有四岁
He was only four years old.
米嘉现在在哪
Where's Miksa now?
明知故问  你这个混蛋
You tell me, you son of a bitch.
-你见过他吧  -我得回基地
- Have you seen him? - I need to go back to the base.
我要和你一起去
We need to go back to the base.
我从没在人体身上试验这项技术
Look, I didn't know we'd be trying this out on an actual person,
还是一个状况如此糟糕的人
let alone someone as bad off as he is.
-我保证不了什么  -明白
- I can't promise anything. - Understood.
变频浸没降温
VFC immersion hypothermia.
第一次人体临床试验
Human trials, take one.
你要如何抑制
How do you stop the body's
人体自身的御寒机能呢
natural defense mechanisms against the cold?
这就要靠我这套特殊的冷却流程了
It is all in how we cool the body down.
冷却液进入肺部的同时
The solution is taken into his lungs
也将从皮肤渗入
while it simultaneously soaks into the skin
从里到外完全包裹身体
and envelops the entire body, inside and on the out.
那他怎么维持呼吸
So how does he breathe?
他不需要呼吸
He doesn't breathe.
人体在九个月的胚胎阶段就不呼吸
Humans don't breathe for the first nine months.
只要维持他的血氧即可
It's a matter of keeping him oxygenated.
成功与否你都会遵守我们的约定吧
Either way, we still have a deal right?
不论他是生是死
No matter how this goes.
再给我一点时间就好  彼得
Just give me a little more time, Peter.
开始吧
Let's do this.
茱莉亚  快来吃晚餐
Julia, come on. Time to eat.
你怎么也在这
Why are you here?
是你害她生病的  都是你的错
You're the one that made her sick. This is all your fault.
我的错  这怎么能怪我呢
My fault? Don't blame me.
我们都是因为她才被困在这的
We're all trapped here because of her.
-你这么说不公平  -谁说要公平了
- That's not fair. - Who said anything about fair?
这是你的潜意识
This is all in your head.
问题是你让我们来这干什么
Why are we even here?
我不知道
I don't know.
能请你递一下蔓越莓酱吗
Pass the cranberry sauce.
-谢谢  -所有都因你而起  茱莉亚
- Thank you - It's all about you, Julia.
一直都是
It's always been about you.
他说的没错
He's right, y'know. He's right.
是你让我们陷入了这场麻烦
You got us into this mess.
我没有  我不是  我只是
I'm not -- I mean, I didn't -- I just,
我不是故意的  拜托
I didn't mean to get -- Oh, come on.
我也想知道为什么
I just want answers.
你连真正的问题是什么都不清楚
You don't even know the right questions to ask.
为什么找你  茱莉亚
Why you, Julia?
为什么会有这种病毒  为什么现在爆发
Why this virus? Why now?
饿死了
I'm starved.
我们能边吃边说吗
Can we do this while we eat?
其实你知道所有答案  只是你没意识到罢了
You have all the answers. You just don't know it.
我在努力  可还是想不起来
I'm trying to remember, but I can't.
那就快想
Just figure it out already.
快想出来我们好吃饭
Figure it out so we can eat.
有人要红薯吗
Would anyone like sweet potatoes?
也许问题的重点不在于我们
Maybe the question isn't why we're here
而在于我们为什么会在这
as much as why are we're HERE -
在这  这个你长大的小木屋
this place, the cabin where you grew up.
也许吃点东西问题就能迎刃而解了
Maybe this would be easier if we all ate something.
你能来切火鸡吗  茱尔斯
Will you carve, Jules?
等等  不该是这样的
Wait, this isn't supposed to be happening.
这不是真的
This is not happening!
这样真的没问题吗
Are y... are you sure about this?
他会适应的
He'll adapt.
他会稳定下来的  这是正常反应
He'll settle. It's normal.
你怎么知道
Normal for what?
没事的  那些猴子和他的反应一样
It's OK. The monkeys did the exact same thing.
还有老鼠也是
The rats too.
无反应
这会害死他的  艾伦
This is killing him. Alan.
艾伦
Alan!
-他要被淹死了  -不  不要
- He's drowning. - No. No.
这是唯一能救回他的方式了
If there's any chance we could save him...
他的体温在下降
His core temperature's dropping.
35摄氏度
It's 95.
29度
Eighty-five.
冷却液输送中
24度
Seventy-five.
18度
Sixty-five.
13度
Fifty-five degrees.
艾伦
Alan.
他能看见我们吗
Can he see us?
我想不能
No. I don't think so.
但这确实起作用了
But it's something.
有进展了
Progress.
疾控中心似乎有了突破性进展
The CDC seems to have had a breakthrough.
抱歉让你失望了
I'm sorry for disappointing you.
-请原谅我  父亲  -是我的错
- Please forgive me, father-- - It's my fault.
是我还没有将你准备好
I didn't prepare you well enough.
这是我的失误
I made a mistake.
没什么失误可言  只有被浪费了的机会
There are no mistakes, only opportunities wasted.
这种事不会再发生了
It won't happen again.
那就好  因为我们的时间已经不多了
Good. We don't have much time to prepare.
你想让我做什么
What do you want me to do?
首先...
First...
带我去看看拜耶塞罗少校的尸体
show me Major Balleseros' body.
太神奇了
It's amazing.
虽然他的大脑活动还没完全恢复
Brain activity isn't 100%,
但毕竟有所好转了
but it's a start.
艾伦  你还好吗
Alan, are you OK?
我就把他留在这里了
This is where I left him.
就是这里
Right here.
我脱下了他的外套和靴子
I took his jacket and boots.
他走不了多远的
He couldn't have got far.
他是被人带走了
He's been taken.
我去找他
I'll go find him.
不用
No.
我们回头再处理这件事
We'll deal with this later.
他们来了
They're here.
你还好吗
Are you OK?
是的
Yeah.
警告  有飞机驶入
Warning: incoming flight.
感谢上帝  救援终于到了
Thank God. The cavalry's here.
怎么可能
How?
我一直没能和外界联系上
I never got the call out.
诶拉瑞亚集团
《双螺旋》前情提要
Previously on Helix...
这是我弟弟  彼得
This is my brother Peter.
这是我对你那条消息的回复
I've got a reply for that message!
无论拜耶塞罗有什么阴谋
Whatever Balleseros is up to
都绝对跟这个病毒有关
has everything to do with this virus.
我要找到他
But I want him found.
-你是谁  -我是阿娜娜
- Who are you? - I'm Anana.
过去二十年来  北极生物公司周围
Thirty-one missing kids over the past two decades,
二百英里的范围内
all within 200 miles of
发生了31起失踪儿童事件
Arctic Biosystems and your precious Dr. Hatake.
-我就把他留在这里了  -他是被人带走了
- This is where I left him. - He's been taken.
这是我和双胞胎弟弟们
This is me and my brothers twins.
这个是米嘉  在我们还小时
This is Miksa. He disappeared
-他就失踪了  -米嘉现在在哪
- when we were kids. - Where's Miksa now?
明知故问  你这个混蛋
You tell me, you son of a bitch.
别担心  茱莉亚
Don't worry, Julia.
很快你就会没事了
We'll have you back on your feet in no time.
第七日
诶拉瑞亚集团
有飞机驶入
Incoming flight.
-我不要紧  没事儿  -有飞机驶入
- I'm fine. I'm fine. - Incoming flight.
我们的行为...
You know, what we did was--
-在这种状况下...  -我们的研究
- Under the circumstances- - The work is really
-才是最重要的  没关系  -完全是...
- what's important. Fine. It's fine. - It was perfectly-
我们的行为只是生理需要  我真没关系
What we did was biology. I'm OK. Really.
-好吧  -有飞机驶入
- Ok. - Incoming flight.
-有飞机驶入  -我也没关系
- Incoming flight. - Fine. I am too.
有飞机驶入
Incoming flight.
你怎么看  是好是坏
What do you think? Good or bad?
鉴于我们一直没能和外界联系上  可能不妙
Considering we never got the call out, probably bad.
肯定不妙
Definitely bad.
-是军方吗  -不是
- Military? - No.
-是公司的投资人  -不要开枪
- My corporate patrons. - Hold your weapons.
是  长官
Sir.
是法拉格特博士吧
Dr. Farragut, isn't it?
很高兴终于见到你  我是康斯坦丝・萨顿
It's so nice to finally meet you. I'm Constance Sutton.
我是北极生物公司的母公司
I'm the Chief Operating Officer of the Ilaria Corporation,
诶拉瑞亚集团的首席运营官
parent company of Arctic Biosystems.
我来这儿只有一个原因  帮助你
I'm here for one reason only: to help you.
诶拉瑞亚集团
首先我需要能和疾控中心联系的通话线路
The first thing I need is a working line to the CDC.
据我所知
Am I to understand
通讯卫星已经无法使用了吧
that the communication satellite went down?
不幸的是  我也没有魔力电话
Unfortunately, I don't have a magic telephone.
我跟这基地里的所有人一样条件受限
I'm under the same constraints as everyone at this base.
你的直升机呢
What about your helicopters?
早已离开了  两天后才回来
They're out of range already. They'll be back
恐怕在那之前你只能跟我和我手下
in two days' time. I'm afraid you're stuck with me
待在这儿了  博士
and my boys until then, Doctor.
坐两个小时的直升机可真不好受
Two hours in a helicopter ouch.
很遗憾你得一路长途跋涉来这儿
I'm sorry you had a rough journey.
艾伦  解药的研究进行得如何
So, Alan, how goes the search for a cure?
-进展缓慢  -所以我才穿了军靴来
- Slowly. - Hence the fact that I am here wearing combat boots.
但是时候在我们公司和疾控中心之间
But it's time for us to create a new paradigm
建立一套新的合作方式了
between our corporation and the CDC,
你们需要诶拉瑞亚集团如何协助
so what do you need from Ilaria
来控制这场可怕的传染病
to contain this terrible disease?
我队伍里不可或缺的成员  沃克博士
An integral member of my team, uh, Dr. Walker,
正被困于R层
is trapped down on Level R.
-我需要她回来  -不可能
- I need her back. - Impossible.
x博士  别这样  我们得化解现在的困局
Dr. Hatake, please. Let's square the circle here.
沃克博士为什么被关起来了
Dr. Walker, why is she locked up?
她受到了感染
She's infected.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
她是研究RNA结构方面的专家
She's an expert in RNA structure.
她很重要  因为...
And that's important because...?
RNA的用途是携带信息
RNA carries the message.
我们将疗法指导储存在DNA中
We store the instructions for the cure in the DNA,
然后由RNA携带传递
and then the RNA passes it on,
因此  她是我团队中最重要的人
and that makes her the most important member of my team.
诶拉瑞亚就是来给你们提供额外帮助的
Well, Ilaria is about value-add.
既然你需要沃克博士  那就给你
If Dr. Walker is what you need, Dr. Walker is what you will get.
克莱恩中尉  制定个计划
Lieutenant Klein, let's prepare a plan
-把沃克博士带回来  -是  长官
- to retrieve Dr. Walker. - Yes, ma'am.
艾伦  我只要一样东西  解药
Alan, one thing; one thing only: a cure.
拜托你了
Please.
现在
Now,
x博士  我们能谈谈吗
Dr. Hatake, may we have a word?
单独谈谈  如果你不介意的话
In private, if you don't mind.
康斯坦丝
Constance.
宏
Hiroshi.
我们只要两样东西  宏
Two things, Hiroshi!
两样很简单的东西 仅此而已
Two simple things. That's all we needed.
我制造出了你要的病毒
I created your virus--
但解药在哪儿呢
Where is the cure?!
病毒和解药
Virus and cure.
两者缺少任何一个都没有任何意义
One without the other is meaningless.
我们可不想杀光所有人  只是减少点数量而已
We don't want to kill everybody; just thin the herd a bit.
然后统治他们
And rule them.
是时候了  我们已经等得够久了
It's time. We've waited long enough.
你明白的
You know that.
我们遇到了一点困难
There have been a few setbacks.
你失败了
You failed.
谢天谢地疾控中心的人来了
Thank God the CDC arrived
-替你做了你的工作  -是替你
- to do your job for you. - For you.
我所听说的另一棵菌株  是干什么的
What is this other strain that I'm hearing about?
纳尔维克-B  那种能把人变成...
NARVIK-B, the one that turns people into...
只是对病毒的另一种尝试罢了
An alternate attempt at the virus.
为什么
Why?
从A菌株上很难研制出解药
The cure has been elusive in the A strain.
也许B菌株能...
Perhaps the B strain--
你简直是满嘴胡言  宏
Perhaps you are full of shit, Hiroshi.
这是威利斯假说
It's the Willis hypothesis.
又称"老种广布学说"  提出若某物种年代越久远  其地理分布越广泛  因此物种极少自然灭绝  需借助外力
我们当时不同意  现在也一样
We said no then. Nothing has changed.
病毒和解药
Virus and cure.
多简单
Simple.
你真的打算去R层吗
Do you really plan to go down to Level R?
去把这个叫沃克的带回来吗  没错
To get this Walker? Yes.
既然法拉格特博士需要她  那就给他
If Dr. Farragut needs her, he gets her.
-解药现在就靠他了  -然后呢
- The cure is in his hands now. - And then?
然后我们依照标准无人协议  不留活口
And then we follow normal null protocol. No witnesses.
这些人是我的手下
These people are my employees,
我对他们负有责任
my responsibility.
没人能活着离开这  宏
No one gets out alive, Hiroshi.
在开始前你就知道的
You knew that before we started.
那疾控中心的人呢
What about the CDC?
如果他们没能活着回去会怎么样
If they fail to return?
我们有专人负责这类事情
We have people in place to control such things.
如果我...
And if I...
发现你背叛了我们...
find out that you betrayed us...
你和这个基地最终
...the only thing left of you or this facility
都只会成为这雪地里一道黑色的伤疤
will be a blackened scar on the ice.
说吧
Now say it.
说出来
Say it.
没人能活着离开这
No one gets out alive.
《双螺旋》第一季第七集
给我松绑吧  拜托
Agh! Come on! Please?
求我吗  还以为你们军人都是硬骨头呢
Begging? Thought you military guys were tough.
至少解开一只手让我能抓牢
Just one hand even, so I can hold on.
-没门  -还有多远
- No. - How much farther?
-很远  -"很远"
- Far. - "Far!"
你在学我说话吗
Are you mocking me?
还是你想听我唱《一百瓶啤酒》
Would you prefer I sang "One Hundred Bottles of Beer?"
我更希望你闭嘴
I'd rather you shut your mouth!
那你给我松绑  我保证再不说话
- Well, then untie me, and I promise you won't hear a word.
或者我也可以加速  让你掉下去
Or I could just speed up, you fall off,
我就不用再听你废话了
and then I won't have to hear you yapping.
我还是觉得我的方案好点
I like my plan better.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
关于  关于萨顿
About... about Sutton.
她怎么了
What about her?
外界通话系统
关闭
我认为她对我们有所保留
I don't think she's telling us everything;
从x宏让我们经历的这些事就能看出来
not with what Hatake's been putting us through.
-什么意思  -我是说
- What do you mean? - What I mean
她和我们的目的并不相同
is I don't think our agenda is her agenda.
也对  这个时候派萨顿和她的私人军队
Right. Where's the profit in sending Sutton
进驻基地能有什么好处呢
and her private army up here?
尤其是我们已经在
Especially when we're already
-义务为他们解决麻烦了  -这些大医药公司
- cleaning up their mess for free. - Big pharma.
你知道他们关心的只有利润
You know they're only interested in the bottom line.
并非真心造福大众
They don't really want to help people.
谁又知道他们为了保护投资能做出什么事情
And who knows how far they'll go to protect their investment?
但我们不能停止研发解药
We can't stop working on a cure.
是不能  还有好多人命悬一线
No, too many lives at stake.
但我们不能为萨顿干活
But we do not work for Sutton.
不让她知道我们的解药
We keep the cure from her.
也许得留这一手
We may need it.
餐厅开放中
Cafeteria is now open.
丹尼尔
Daniel.
x宏的养子
Hatake's adopted son.
但你应该知道给你发薪水的是我们吧
Though on some level you do realize that we pay your salary, yes?
就是说我卖身给你们了是吧
So you've already bought me.
"购买了你出色的服务"更为贴切
Paid for excellent service, rather.
你之前见过这位沃克博士吗
Did you have a chance to meet this Dr. Walker?
见过
Yeah.
我觉得事态发展遇到些阻碍  丹尼尔
I'm feeling some pushback, Daniel,
而我又忙得很  所以我要的是
and I'm extremely busy, so I need a quick win
-速战速决  行吗  -你说了算
- on this one, OK? - OK.
在把沃克交给法拉格特博士之前
I need full intel on Walker
我需要知道她的全部信息
before I return her to Dr. Farragut, and...
说实话  我觉得x宏什么都不会跟我说
well, let's be honest, Hiroshi is not gonna tell me anything.
本来也没什么可说的
There's not much to tell.
我喜欢你  丹尼尔  所以我不希望
I like you, Daniel, and I don't want
咱们的关系一开始  就充斥着你对我的谎言
to start our relationship with you lying to me.
我还没意识到你我之间还有关系可言
I wasn't aware that we had a relationship.
你的忠诚我理解  我甚至十分赞赏
Loyalty I understand. Hell, I even admire it.
所以威胁什么的就不说了
So let's skip the negatives
直接说说好处  如何
and get straight to the positives, shall we?
你的工作做得非常好
You are very good at your job.
而x宏不可能永远做这个基地的负责人
And Hatake is not gonna be in charge of this place forever.
好好想想吧  丹尼尔  行吗
Just think on it, Daniel. Please.
x宏毁掉了他身边所有与他亲近的人
Hiroshi has destroyed everyone who's ever been close to him.
别让他也毁了你
Don't let him do the same to you.
真方便啊
Handy.
美军在北极圈废弃了67个
The U.S. Military abandoned 67 of these early-warning stations
这样的预警站  总得有人用用这些设施吧
across the Arctic. Someone should put them to use.
给我松绑不行吗
How about untying my hands?
你睡觉还得用手吗
You need your hands to sleep?
你反正有枪
You've got the gun.
没错  你说的有道理
Yeah, you make a good point.
我只是想说
I'm just saying.
咱做事儿讲点道理呗
Let's be reasonable.
那好吧
Ok.
好
ok.
讲理的话就得把你的脚也捆上
It's reasonable to hogtie you.
彻底断了你逃跑的念头
Make sure you don't get any ideas about running off.
别这样
Aw, come on!
我得回到上面去
I need to get back upstairs.
我得去找艾伦
I need to get to Alan.
我的血液里没准有能对抗病毒的抗体
My blood could have antibodies that fight the virus.
澳大利亚有个人
There's a guy in Australia,
他的血浆拯救了两百万婴儿的生命
his blood plasma has saved 2 million babies.
我们要救的只有四五十人
We only have to save 40 or 50 people.
你要是真的话  整件事就容易多了
This would be so much easier if you were real.
-有我总聊胜于无  -才怪
- I'm better than nothing. - Barely.
你和我的银色瞳孔有关联吗
Are you connected to my silver eyes?
-所以我才总会看见你  -这就是你的理论吗
- Is that why I'm seeing you? - Is that your hypothesis?
你知道我讨厌苏格拉底反诘法
You know I've always hated the Socratic method.
好吧
Fine.
也许你只是暂时性的畏光
Maybe it's temporary light sensitivity.
或者是间歇丛集性头痛
Or non-episodic cluster headaches.
或者你可能快瞎了
Or maybe you're just going blind.
总比死了强
Better than dead, I guess.
又或者
Or maybe...
你是头号幸存者
...maybe you're survivor zero -
第一个被治愈的人
the first one cured.
如果我康复了  怎么还会出现幻觉呢
But if I'm cured, why am I still hallucinating?
更关键的问题是
I have an even better question.
为什么你幻想的是我
Why are you hallucinating me
而不是艾伦呢
instead of Alan?
萨顿想让我背叛你
Sutton is trying to turn me against you.
她当然想这么做
Of course she is.
我就是跟你汇报一声
I just wanted to let you know.
萨顿是个危险的敌人
Sutton can be a dangerous enemy.
我明白
I understand.
不  你不明白
No. You don't.
她不会放过任何妨碍她的人
She destroys anything that gets in her way.
她也是这样形容你的
She said something similar about you.
你想从我身上得到什么
What is it you want from me?
你的信任
Your trust.
我在努力保护你
I'm trying to protect you.
不过有件事你可以帮我
But there is one thing you can do.
无论如何
Under no circumstances
绝不能让萨顿接近沃克博士
can Sutton be allowed to gain access to Dr. Walker.
她为什么如此重要
Why is Walker so important?
跟解药有关吗
Is it about the cure?
我根本不关心解药的事
I never cared about the cure.
我以为因为解药才...
But I thought that's why--
我请求你的帮助  难道还不足以说明我的信任吗
Is it not enough that I asked for your help?
我认为  萨顿想杀沃克
I think... Sutton will kill Walker.
我不想看到这一幕发生
I do not wish... that outcome.
你得离暖炉近点
You should get closer to the heater.
-你真要睡觉吗  -累了当然要睡
- Are you really gonna sleep? - That's what tired people do.
真受不了你[葡萄牙语]
Deus caramba.
老天  你连西班牙语都说不对
Jeez, you can't even speak Spanish correctly.
因为我说的是葡萄牙语
That's 'cause it's Portuguese.
那不就是蹩脚的西班牙语吗
See? Horrible Spanish.
你的家乡在哪
Where's your home?
圣埃斯皮里图州  就在里约热内卢以北
Espirito Santo. Just north of Rio.
失踪儿童的事  我真的很抱歉
I really am sorry... you know, about the missing kids.
我们从小就被教导不要远离狩猎营地
As a child, we were warned to stay near the hunting camps.
不然就会被凯里帕利抓走
Otherwise, the Qalupalik would take us.
因纽特神话中长相似人的蓝色生物
什么帕利
Qalu-who?
一种专偷孩子的妖怪
Boogeyman. Child-stealer.
但长大后我发现原来我的儿时妖怪真的存在
But I grew up and discovered my Boogeyman was real.
我也是
Mine too.
圣埃斯皮里图州也有很多失踪儿童吗
A lot of kids go missing in Espirito Santo?
是啊
Yeah.
好吧
Fine.
虽然我不喜欢你
I don't like you.
但我对你所经历的那些感到抱歉
But I'm sorry about whatever you went through.
法拉格特博士
Dr. Farragut.
萨顿女士
Ms. Sutton.
叫我康斯坦丝就行
Please, call me Constance.
解药的研究有进展吗
So, how is the search for the cure progressing?
停滞不前  因为沃克博士不在
It isn't, without Dr. Walker.
我以为我们已经达成了共识
I thought we had an understanding.
你负责研究解药
You take care of the lab work,
我负责其余的事
and I will take care of everything else.
恐怕你没有尽职尽责  康斯坦丝
I'm afraid you didn't square the circle on that one, Constance.
计划正在执行中
Plans are in motion.
我的手下很快就会把沃克博士接上来
My security team will be going down to retrieve Dr. Walker very soon.
我要和他们一起去
And I'll be going with them.
这恐怕不行  艾伦
I'm afraid that's a non-starter, Alan.
我们不能让你再遭到任何不测
We can't allow anything to happen to you.
沃克博士是我的队员
Dr. Walker is a member of my team.
我需要确保她的安全
I need to guarantee her safety.
你好像不太信任我
I'm sensing you have some trust issues.
要是我去不成  那谁也别想去
If I don't go, no one goes.
随便你吧
Suit yourself.
但你必须全程在武装人员保护下行动
But you will have an armed escort at all times.
那再好不过了
I wouldn't have it any other way.
周边警报
Perimeter alert.
米嘉
Miksa.
你为什么会在这
What the hell are you doing here?
你想说我怎么还没死吗
You mean alive?
米嘉
Miksa!
抱着你的感觉都跟以前一样
You even feel like him.
你又是谁
Who the hell are you?
他说过你以为自己叫丹尼尔
He says you think your name is Daniel.
你的名字是米嘉
Your name is Miksa.
你在很小的时候就被他们带走了
You were taken from us as a child.
听着  我不管你以为我是谁
Listen, I don't know who you think I am--
这么多年来我一直在搜寻你的下落
I've been searching for you my entire life.
我的弟弟
My brother.
这算什么  你又在搞什么鬼
What is this? What are you trying to pull?
这跟我可没关系
Don't look at me.
她家里有个长得跟你一模一样的
She's got another one exactly like you back home.
你有一个孪生兄弟
Your brother, your twin!
他叫图克
Tulok.
真不赖
Impressive.
但这种照片处理技术我也会
But I can use Photoshop too.
把他带到禁闭室  我来处理这女的
Take him to Isolation. I'll deal with her.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
到桌子的距离是四步
Four steps to the table.
一  二  三步到柜子
One, two, three steps to the cabinet.
一步到推车  这个可得记住
Ah! One step to the cart. Gotta remember that.
x博士  是你吗
Dr. Hatake? Is that you?
彼得
Peter?
很高兴看到你一点儿都没见外
Nice to see you've made yourself at home.
茱莉亚・沃克是谁  宏
Hiroshi, who is Julia Walker?
你怎么从未提起过她
Why haven't you mentioned her?
为什么我要这么做
Why would I?
你汇报过那个惨死的兽医朵琳
You briefed us that poor dead veterinarian, Doreen--
沃克无足轻重
Walker seemed unimportant.
可恰恰相反的是
Dr. Farragut seems to think
法拉格特博士认为她至关重要
she's the exact opposite of unimportant.
她是他的前妻
She's his ex-wife.
原来是私人关系  这是他的理由吗
Ah, nepotism. Is that his reasoning?
也许吧
Perhaps.
那你又怎么解释呢
And what is yours?
雇佣考量
Recruiting.
我这里有疾控中心所有科学家的资料
I have files on all CDC scientists.
这么说她的确很重要
So she is important.
最后我并没有雇佣她  所以不
I chose not to recruit her, so no,
我不认为她很重要.
I don't believe so.
看来我们的看法不尽相同
A difference of opinion then. Good.
是人力资源的问题  我了解了
Human Resources problems I can understand.
听好了  x宏
I'll tell you what, Hiroshi,
我会亲自去R层把沃克博士带回来
I will personally arbitrate Dr. Walker's importance
到时再由我来决定她是否重要
or lack thereof when I go down to Level R and pull her out.
她在哪里
Where is she?
她在一间被当做分诊部的实验室
She's in a lab we set up for triage.
R层17号
R-17.
宏
Hiroshi.
别忘了你是站在哪边的
Let's not forget which side you're on.
准许进入
Access granted.
之前用过枪吗
Ever use one of these?
最近才用过
Recently.
法拉格特博士
Dr. Farragut.
要和我们一起去  就得拿上枪
You want to come with us? Take the gun.
楼层B  预定清扫
Scheduled cleaning, Level B.
Scheduled cleaning, Level B
你真的认为这些人信得过吗
Do you really think you can trust them?
不  但之前我们单独行动时
No, but you saw what happened
你也见识到下面有多危险了
when we went down there alone.
如今正好有这么多武力
All these guns around -
何不好好利用一下呢
might as well use them to get what we want.
去把茱莉亚带回来
Go get Julia,
拜托了  这样我们才能尽快回家
please, so that we can all go home.
拜耶塞罗
Balleseros.
法拉格特博士
Doctor Farragut!
快住手  住手
Please! Stop! Stop it!
就是他杀了博伊尔博士
That man killed Dr. Boyle!
军队...
The army en--
你居然杀了一名
You killed a member of the CDC
帮我们寻找解药的疾控中心成员吗
who's trying to find a cure for this virus?
我向你保证  他会付出代价的
I promise you, I will make this man pay.
你现在没有时间精力
You have neither the time
浪费在这种事上面  但我有
nor the wherewithal to handle this right now. I do.
-这事与你无关  -没错  但如果我的协助
- This is not your concern. - No, but if my men handle this,
能让你更快地回到实验当中
that puts you back in the lab faster,
那我义不容辞
and that is very much my concern.
让我和囚犯单独待会
Give me a minute with the prisoner,
做好R层攻入与拯救行动的准备
and get ready for Level R insertion and retrieval.
-长官  -解散
- Ma'am. - Dismissed.
我操
Shit.
这是为了什么
What was that for?
你杀掉了研发解药
You murdered 25%
所需人力的四分之一
of the workflow we need for the cure.
那我杀了四分之一的你怎么样
How about I kill 25% of you?
别这样  康斯坦丝
Come on, Constance.
是萨顿女士
Ms. Sutton.
我雇你来是干什么的
What am I paying you for?
病毒  解药
Virus. Cure.
错  那是诶拉瑞亚集团雇你的原因
Wrong. That is what Ilaria pays you for.
而我呢
I, on the other hand,
是让你给我找出
tasked you with finding me proof
x宏叛变的证据
that Hatake has gone off the rails.
你上次报告的时候  说发现了什么是吗
The last time you checked in, you said you were on to something.
抱歉让你失望了
Sorry to disappoint you.
最近我都在忙着保住自己的小命
I've been a little busy trying not to get killed.
所以除了这烂借口你什么都没有了吗
So you have nothing except excuses?
还有个被捅了一刀的脾脏
And a perforated spleen.
x宏的问题是你一手造成的
You created the Hatake situation.
别把责任都赖给我
Don't you blame me for your mess.
我就喜欢你这点  塞尔吉
That's why I like you, Serge.
你要么是非常勇敢
You're either very brave
要么就是非常非常的愚蠢
or very... very foolish.
显然  我两者皆有
Apparently, both.
白痴再勇敢  依旧还是白痴
A brave fool is still a fool.
你是准备帮我把衣服脱了呢
So, are you gonna take these off,
还是说我仍在受处罚中
or am I still in a time-out?
我需要艾伦做我的盟友
I need Alan as an ally.
而放了你是毁掉这个同盟
Releasing you will be the quickest way
-的最快方式  -你在开玩笑吧
- to screw that up. - You're kidding, right?
我是会开玩笑的人吗
Do I ever kid?
-那我就这么待着  -先待着吧
- So I stay? - So you stay.
再说我也怀疑你是否能在
Plus, I'm not sure you would survive
碰到丹尼尔那家伙后还能活下来
an encounter with that Daniel character.
我该感谢你对我的肯定吗
Thanks for the vote of confidence.
如果我是你
Oh, now, if I were you,
我会把这
I would think that my...
销魂的一吻
soft kisses...
当成对你最大的肯定
...are all the vote I needed.
克莱恩中尉
Lieutenant Klein!
把他关进禁闭室
Throw him in isolation.
准许进入
Access granted.
沃克博士
Dr. Walker.
你去哪里了
Where were you?
发生了什么
What happened here?
-是其他的科学家吗  -不  是个带菌者
- Was it the other scientists? - No, a vector.
你受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
它就在这  就在我眼前
It was here, right in front of me,
蓄势待发  可然后  它...
ready to attack, and then it just... and then... it just...
突然就停手了
stopped.
沃克博士  你看起来  好多了
Dr. Walker, you look... better.
我还活着  身体健康  就是可能有点精神失常
Alive. Healthy. Possibly going crazy. All of the above.
这真是太好了
This is wonderful.
除了精神失常  这最好不是真的
Yeah, except for the crazy part. Could do without that.
我需要抽检血样  做个诊断性测试
I'll need to draw blood. Run diagnostic tests.
我已经做了所有的测试
I've already done all the tests.
没有病毒的迹象  只是
There's no sign of the virus. The only thing-Ah!
我的眼睛好疼
Ah, my eyes hurt!
我的眼睛不知道怎么了  看什么都模糊
There's something happening to my eyes. Everything's blurry.
坐在这
Sit here.
我给你用绷带绑起来
Let me get you some bandages.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
E层
Level E.
据报告  这些带菌者非常敏捷强壮
My sit-reps indicate these vectors are fast and strong?
-F层  -绝对超乎你想象
- Level F. - Like nothing you've ever seen.
其他人呢
And the others?
普通人而已  他们感染了纳尔维克-A病毒
Human. Suffering prolonged and fatal cellular breakdown
只能在底下痛苦地等死
due to the NARVIK-A strain.
-E层  -或者还没病变就被咬死了
- Level E. - Or not suffering at all.
你说过下面还有未感染的人是吗
You said there were healthy people down there as well?
当时未感染  现在就不好说了
There were. Now I don't know.
R层
Level R.
佩雷斯  你打头
Perez, take point.
遵命
Sir.
安全
Clear.
R-17号实验室在哪里
Lab R-17?
应该是这边
This way, I think.
-都听到他说的了  行动  -收到
- You heard the man. Let's go. - Roger that.
你现在能走吗
Can you walk?
能  怎么了
Yes. Why?
-我们得离开这  -为什么
- We need to leave this place. - Why?
有个女人要来杀你
There is a woman coming down here to kill you.
-你到底在说什么  -以后我会解释清楚的
- What are you talking about? - I'll explain everything,
但我们得先离开这
but right now, we need to leave.
-艾伦知道吗  -他正跟随她一起下来
- Does Alan know about this? - He's coming down with her.
艾伦绝不会
Alan would never --
他不知道她做得出什么  但我知道
He doesn't know what she's capable of. I do.
你得跟我走
You have to come with me.
-不要  我要等艾伦  -你这么做
- No. I want to wait for Alan. - If you do...
就是送死
you'll die.
你要相信我
You have to trust me.
茱莉亚
Julia...
求你了
please.
好的
Ok.
准许进入
Access granted.
艾伦  等等
Alan, wait a moment.
攻进去  单发射击  不要连击
Make entry. Single shots, no bursts.
-沃克博士很重要  -听我口令
- Dr. Walker's precious cargo. - On my mark.
准备  进攻
Ready... breach!
小心
Look out!
小心后面
Behind us!
全员撤退  快
Full retreat! Let's go! Go!
撤退
Fall back!
-菲利普被抓住了  -别管他了
- Philip's down! - Leave him.
我要去找茱莉亚
I have to find Julia.
她不再是原来的她了  她已经和他们一样了
She's not in there. She's one of them now.
那我也不会把她丢在这
I'm not leaving her down here.
难道你感染或者死掉就能救她了吗
How is getting yourself infected or killed gonna help her?
我也不知道  但我不能丢下她不管
I don't know, but I can't leave her behind.
我们得先回到楼上
We have to get back upstairs.
带上足够的人手和武器再回来
Then we come back down with more security, bigger numbers.
否则我们就是来送死
Otherwise we're sitting ducks.
我自己去找茱莉亚
I'm going to find Julia.
你还没弄清形势是吗
You still don't understand how this works, do you?
-回电梯那去  -我刚刚才救了你一命
- Get to the elevator. - I just saved your life.
我也很感激
And I am extremely appreciative,
但我得保护我的投资
but right now I have to protect my investment.
靠对着它开一枪吗  尽管动手吧
By putting a bullet through it? Go ahead.
如果你非要去送死  最后变成
If it's the difference between shooting you now
他们其中一员  那朝你开枪只是迟早的事
and shooting you later when you're one of them, then fine,
不过到时候  我就得朝咱们的莎拉
although I will need to put a bullet
也来上一枪  免得走漏风声
through young Sarah as well. Loose ends.
保护法拉格特博士回B层
Let's escort Dr. Farragut back up to Level B,
-克莱恩中尉  -遵命  长官
- please, Lt. Klein? - Yes, ma'am.
-为什么来这  -这里没有监控
- Why here? - No cameras.
这是父亲照的
Father took that.
父亲
Father?
他去世了  母亲也是
He's dead; mother too.
-你叫我什么来着  -米嘉
- And what did you call me? - Miksa.
那是我们祖父的名字
It was our grandfather's name.
我为什么要相信你
And why should I believe you?
你说的这一切
Any of this?
我为什么要骗你呢
Why would I lie?
-x博士有很多敌人  -x宏
- Dr. Hatake has many enemies. - Hatake?
他是始作俑者  是他偷走了你
He's responsible. He's the one that stole you,
-你和其他小孩  -其他小孩
- along with the others. - The others?
这些年来一共有31个孩子失踪
Thirty-one children over the years.
你对他们有印象吗
Do you remember any of them?
过去这里总有孩子出现
There were always children here.
但我也没多想
I thought it was normal.
他们都去哪了
What happened to them?
我不知道
I don't know.
还是说你不想知道
Maybe you didn't want to know.
-我们在哪里  -楼上
- Where are we? - Upstairs.
你安全了
You are safe.
丹尼尔
Daniel?
-这是什么意思  -别装了
- What's the meaning of this? - Don't.
别再装了
Just don't.
你是哪位
And you are?
我是他姐姐
His sister.
那些当年你从我们身边偷走他的家人
The one you left behind when you stole him from his family.
沃克博士
Dr. Walker,
这些人会护送你回实验室
these men will escort you back to the lab.
拿上这个  你会需要的
Take these. You'll need them.
-去吧  你会没事的  -那你呢
- Go. You'll be fine. - What about you?
我还...
I'm...
不确定
not sure.
沃克博士
Dr. Walker.
茱莉亚
Julia!
-我是...  -把她带走
- I'm... - Get her out of here.
楼下的局面暂时还在掌控之中
Lower secure for now,
我们在上面应该很安全
We should be safe up here.
B层
Level B.
电梯已锁
Elevator locked.
我为你牺牲了我的手下  现在该你回报我了
I sacrificed my own men for you. Now it's your turn.
赶紧给我研发解药去
Run along and find me that cure.
-那沃克博士呢  -艾伦
- Well, what about Dr. Walker? - Oh, Alan.
她要么变成那些鬼东西了  要么就是死了
She's one of those things now, or dead.
我都不知道哪个结果更糟糕
I don't know which is worse.
上帝啊
Oh, my god.
茱尔斯  茱尔斯
Jules. Jules.
你怎么在这里  我还以为你...
What are you doing here? I thought you were...
天啊  你的症状都消失了
Look at you. Your symptoms are gone.
我痊愈了  至少...
I'm cured. At least, I, uh,
我是这么认为的
I mean... I think I am.
-怎么治好的  -我不知道
- How? - I don't know.
看着我
Look at me.
茱尔斯
Jules.
电梯已锁
B层
*你从不知道我有多爱你*
*Never know how much I love you*
*从不知道我有多在意*
*Never know how much I care*
*当你双臂紧拥着我*
*When you put your arms around me*
*我只觉得热到难以忍受*
*I get a fever that's so hard to bear*
*当你吻我  你让我发热*
*You give me fever, when you kiss me*
*当你紧拥我  我会发热*
*Fever when you hold me tight*
*无时无刻  朝朝暮暮*
*Fever in the morning, fever all through the night*
*每个人都会发热*
*Everybody's got the fever*
*这是大家都知道的事*
*That is something you all know*
*发热不是什么新鲜事  自古至今如此*
*Fever isn't such a new scene, fever's started long ago*